<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Karobben</title>
  
  <subtitle>Engjoy~</subtitle>
  <link href="https://karobben.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://karobben.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-10-22T04:13:29.876Z</updated>
  <id>https://karobben.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Karobben</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Glycolysis &amp; the TCA (citric acid) cycle 11| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/21/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-11/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/21/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-11/</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T01:45:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:13:29.876Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="1623">1623</h2><p>21</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>10 Cell Signaling|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/21/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-10/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/21/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-10/</id>
    <published>2021-10-21T13:57:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:12:53.899Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Cell’s-social-network">Cell’s social network</h2><ul><li><p>Pharmacological agents</p></li><li><p>Chemicals</p></li><li><p>Heavy Metals</p></li><li><p>Growth factors</p></li><li><p>Hormones</p></li><li><p>Neurotransmitters</p></li><li><p>Morphogens</p></li><li><p>Odors</p></li><li><p>Pheromones</p></li><li><p>Ions</p></li><li><p>Light</p></li><li><p>Temperature</p></li><li><p>Pressure</p></li><li><p>Radiation</p></li><li><p>Viruses</p></li><li><p>Bacteria</p></li></ul><h2 id="Life-Depends-on-Correct-Cellular-Response">Life Depends on Correct Cellular Response</h2><p>differentiation; proliferation; migration; exocytosis; apoptosis; adhesion; senescence</p><p><em><strong>Stimulation</strong></em>:<br>Growth factors<br>Hormones<br>Neurotransmitters<br>Morphogens<br>Odors<br>Pheromones<br>Ions</p><p>Light<br>Temperature<br>Pressure<br>Radiation</p><p>Viruses Bacteria<br>Pharmacological agents<br>Chemicals<br>Heavy Metals</p><p><em><strong>Responding</strong></em>:<br>differentiation<br>proliferation<br>exocytosis<br>migration<br>apoptosis<br>adhesion<br>senescence</p><h3 id="Transmembrane-signaling-only-a-few-mechanisms">Transmembrane signaling: only a few mechanisms</h3><ol><li>Ligand-gated ion channel (iontropic receptros)</li><li>G-protein-coupled receptors (metabotropic)</li><li>Kinases-linked receptors</li><li>Nuclear receptors</li></ol><h3 id="Signal-Transduction">Signal Transduction</h3><ol><li>Synthesis of the signal</li><li>Release of the signaling molecule by the signaling cell: exocytosis, diffusion, cell-cell contact</li><li>Transport of the signal to the target cell</li><li>Detection of the signal by a specific receptor protein</li><li>Initiation of one or more intracellular signaltransduction pathways</li><li>A change in cellular metabolism, function or development triggered by the receptor-signal complex</li><li>Deactivation of receptor</li><li>Removal of the signal (downregulation) 12</li></ol><h2 id="Signaling-events-are-ordered-both-spatially-and-temporally">Signaling events are ordered both spatially and temporally</h2><p>Cellular Tools for information transmission<br>Signal Transduction</p><ul><li>Ligands<br>transmit signals</li><li>Receptors<br>receive information in form of a ligand transmits signal across membrane</li><li>Transducers<br>pass information enzymatically active may be signal integrators</li><li>Adapters<br>no catalytic activity modulate proximity of transducers</li><li>Scaffolds<br>provide architecture allow energetically unfavorable events</li><li>Effectors<br>perform an end function</li></ul><h3 id="Ligands-structure">Ligands (structure)</h3><p>Chamical structure, small molecules:<br>• Small molecules (e.g. amino acid or lipid derivatives, acetylcholine)<br>• Peptides (e.g. ACTH, vasopressin)<br>• <em><strong>Steroids</strong></em><br>• <em><strong>Retinoids</strong></em><br>• <em><strong>Thyroxine</strong></em><br>• Proteins (usually large &amp; hydrophilic, bind to cell-surface receptors)</p><p><em><strong>(hydrophobic, bind intracellular receptors)</strong></em></p><h3 id="Major-classes">Major classes</h3><p>• Hormones<br>• Growth factors, cytokines, chemokines<br>• Neurotransmitters<br>• Pheromones<br>• Can also be changes in metabolite concentration, e.g. oxygen or nutrients or physical stimuli such as light and heat</p><h2 id="Models-of-Cell-Signaling">Models of Cell Signaling</h2><ul><li><p>ENDOCRINE SIGNALING<br>Example: release of insulin by cells in the pancreas, travels in the blood stream and acts on distal liver, muscle and fat cells</p></li><li><p>PARACRINE SIGNALING<br>Examples: Growth factors and cytokines that signal to neighboring or surrounding cells</p></li><li><p>AUTOCRINE SIGNALING<br>Example: PDGF binds to PDGFproducing and secreting cells to stimulate cell growth</p></li><li><p>SIGNALING BY MEMBRANEATTACHED PROTEINS<br>Example: Delta-Notch signaling</p><h3 id="Not-every-ligand-that-binds-to-a-receptor-also-activates-the-receptor">Not every ligand that binds to a receptor also activates the receptor</h3></li><li><p><strong>Agonists</strong> are able to activate the receptor and result in a maximal biological response. The natural endogenous ligand with the greatest efficacy for a given receptor is by definition a full agonist (100% efficacy).</p></li><li><p><strong>Partial</strong> agonists do not activate receptors thoroughly, causing responses which are partial compared to those of full agonists.</p></li><li><p><strong>Antagonists</strong> bind to receptors but do not activate them. This results in receptor blockage, inhibiting the binding of agonists and inverse agonists.</p></li><li><p><strong>Inverse</strong> agonists reduce the activity of receptors by inhibiting their constitutive activity.</p></li></ul><h3 id="What-determines-the-cellular-specificity-of-responses-to-ligands">What determines the cellular specificity of responses to ligands?</h3><ol><li>The presence or absence of receptors</li><li>The internal signal transduction or response machinery of individual cell types</li></ol><h3 id="Ligands-induce-specific-cellular-response">Ligands induce specific cellular response</h3><h3 id="Signaling-events-are-ordered-both-spatially-and-temporally-v2">Signaling events are ordered both spatially and temporally</h3><ul><li>Transducers<br>They work as a gateway to the cell. As a result, they are crucial … to regulate almost every known physiological process.” (Robert Lefkowitz)</li></ul><h3 id="Receptors-can-be-classed-as-either">Receptors can be classed as either</h3><p>Cellular Tools for information transmission</p><p>Cell-surface receptors<br>OR<br>Intracellular receptors</p><h3 id="Intracellular-Nuclear-Receptors">Intracellular (Nuclear) Receptors</h3><p>• Can be located in the cytoplasm or the nucleus<br>• Bind to hydrophobic ligands that can diffuse across the plasma membrane<br>• Contain DNA-binding domains and act as ligand-regulated transcriptional activators or suppressors<br>• Characteristic lag period between ligand binding and cellular response of 30 minutes to several hours<br>• Effects of NR agonists can persist for hours or days after plasma concentration is zero</p><h3 id="Cell-surface-receptors">Cell-surface receptors</h3><p>Hydrophilic ligands bind to cell-surface receptors</p><h3 id="Properties-of-Cell-Surface-Receptors">Properties of Cell Surface Receptors</h3><p>• Integral membrane proteins<br>• Domain structure<br>- Extracellular<br>- Transmembrane<br>- Intracellular<br>• Exhibit ligand binding specificity<br>• Ligand binding induces conformational change that exerts an effect intracellularly<br>• Effector specificity</p><h3 id="Seven-Major-Classes-of-Cell-Surface-Receptors">Seven Major Classes of Cell-Surface Receptors</h3><p>Experimental Figure 15.3 Ligand Growth hormone binds to its receptor through molecular complementary. Binding Specificity</p><h3 id="Ligand-Binding-Specificity">Ligand Binding Specificity</h3><h3 id="Ligands-binding-to-different-types-of-receptors-lead-to-different-physiological-responses">Ligands binding to different types of receptors lead to different physiological responses</h3><p>(epinephrine)<br>(adrenergic receptors)</p><h3 id="Sensitivity-of-a-cell-to-an-external-signal-is-determined-by-the-number-of-surface-receptors">Sensitivity of a cell to an external signal is determined by the number of surface receptors</h3><h3 id="Maximal-cellular-response-does-not-require-binding-of-all-receptors">Maximal cellular response does not require binding of all receptors</h3><p>50% of maximal response when only 18% of receptors bound with ligand<br>80% of maximal response is induced when 50% of the receptors are occupied</p><h2 id="Signaling-events-are-ordered-both-spatially-and-temporally-v3">Signaling events are ordered both spatially and temporally</h2><ul><li>Transducers pass information enzymatically active may be signal integrators</li></ul><h3 id="Protein-kinases-and-phosphatases-are-employed-in-virtually-all-signaling-pathways">Protein kinases and phosphatases are employed in virtually all  signaling pathways</h3><p>Figure 15.4 Regulation of protein activity by a kinase/phosphatase switch.</p><p>Figure 15.5 A simple signal transduction pathway involving one kinase and one target protein.</p><p>• ~ 600 kinases and 100 different phosphatases in human genome<br>• Target residues are ‘phosphoacceptors’ - Ser, Thr or Tyr<br>• Assembled into the ‘KINOME’<br>• Diversity encompasses transmembrane, simple and complex structures</p><h3 id="Post-translational-modifications-PTM">Post-translational modifications (PTM)</h3><p>Ser/Thr directed Tyr directed<br>34<br>• Reversible addition of a small chemical group causes change in activity or location of a signaling protein<br>• PTMs require the action of both modifying and unmodifying enzymes (allowing the signal to be given and terminated)</p><p>MODIFICATION TARGET ADDITION REMOVAL ROLES<br>PHOSPHORYLATION<br>PO4-<br>Tyr<br>Ser<br>Thr<br>kinase phosphatase Activity switch<br>Targeting<br>S-NITROSYLATION<br>NO<br>Tyr<br>Cys<br>S-nitrosylase Nitrohydrolase<br>Reduction<br>Activity switch<br>Targeting?<br>GLYCOSYLATION N- or Oeg. Asn many many<br>Processing<br>Targeting<br>LIPID<br>eg. Farnesyl<br>Prenyl<br>Geranyl<br>Myristoyl<br>etc<br>various many many Processing<br>Targeting<br>Activity<br>ACETYLATION<br>lysine Acetylation<br>complexes<br>De-acetylation<br>complexes<br>Large scale<br>conformational<br>changes</p><p>Figure 15.6 GTPase switch proteins cycle between active and inactive forms.</p><p>Figure 15.7 Switching mechanism of G proteins.</p><h3 id="Second-messengers-amplify-the-signal">Second messengers amplify the signal</h3><h3 id="Second-messengers">Second messengers</h3><p>• Short lived, diffusible intracellular signaling molecules<br>• Elevated concentration leads to rapid alteration in the activity of one or more cellular enzymes<br>• Removal or degradation terminates the cellular response<br>MESSENGERS<br>metal ions<br>Lipids</p><ul><li>inositol lipids<br>Cyclic nucleotides<br>+sugar nucleosides<br>examples<br>dissolved gas<br>Calcium<br>Zinc, also Mn 2+<br>DAG<br>PIPs, IPs<br>cAMP, cGMP<br>ADR-ribose,<br>cADP-ribose<br>NO<br>39</li></ul><h2 id="Signaling-events-are-ordered-both-spatially-and-temporally-v4">Signaling events are ordered both spatially and temporally</h2><p>• Adapters<br>no catalytic activity modulate proximity of transducers<br>•Scaffolds<br>provide architecture allow energetically unfavorable events</p><h3 id="Signaling-induced-by-protein-protein-interactions">Signaling induced by protein-protein interactions</h3><p>Cellular Tools for information transmission</p><p>Adapter has no catalytic activity, modulate proximity of transducers<br>Many signal-transduction pathways contain large multiprotein signaling complexes which are held together by adapter proteins</p><p>Signaling proteins are modular, consisting of groupings of highly conserved domains each with a specific function.</p><p>When used in combination, these domains allow the construction of specialized molecules with multiple input and output points. Use of domains ensures function only in the correct conditions/context</p><h3 id="Adapter-Protein-clustering">Adapter - Protein clustering</h3><p>MyrSH3 SH2 Kinase domain<br>site 1: Yact site 2: Yinhib<br>action<br>interaction<br>These regulatory interactions are mediated by specific protein domains<br>42<br>Clustering of neurotransmitter receptors in the region<br>of the postsynaptic plasma membrane adjacent to the<br>presynaptic cell promotes rapid and efficient signal<br>transmission 43</p><ul><li><em><strong>PDZ domains</strong></em> are protein-protein interaction domains recognizing mainly the C-termini of their target proteins</li><li><em><strong>Src-homology 2 (SH2) domains</strong></em> bind to specific phospho-tyrosine containing peptide motifs.</li><li><em><strong>Src-homology 3 (SH3) domains</strong></em> bind to proline rich peptides</li><li><em><strong>Pleckstrin homology (PH) domain</strong></em> Bind to phosphoinositides, bg-subunits of G-proteins and PKC</li></ul><h3 id="Scaffolding-protein-provide-architecture-and-allow-energetically-unfavorable-events">Scaffolding protein provide architecture and allow energetically unfavorable events</h3><h3 id="Lipid-Rafts">Lipid Rafts</h3><p>Rafts, 10-50 nm, contain a max of 50 proteins along cholesterol, sphingolipids, and Glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored proteins</p><h3 id="Caveolae-are-a-special-type-of-lipid-raft">Caveolae are a special type of lipid raft</h3><p>Coalesce with active signaling and might concentrate signaling proteins</p><p>May provide a microenvironment for signaling and help GPI-linked proteins signal across membrane</p><p><em><strong>Caveolae</strong></em> are small (50 -100 nm) invaginations in plasma membrane containing<br><em><strong>Caveolin</strong></em> on the cytosolic leaflet of the plasma membrane<br>Caveolin helps form the flask-shaped pits involved in endocytosis<br>Caveolin interacts with cholesterol and may be play a role in transfer of cholesterol into lipid raft domains.<br><em><strong>Signal proteins</strong></em> that attach to the plasma membrane via lipid anchors tend to be concentrated in caveolae.</p><h2 id="Effectors">Effectors</h2><p>perform an end function<br>Cellular Tools for information transmission</p><h3 id="Many-ligands-bind-to-multiple-types-of-receptors-leading-to-different-physiological-responses">Many ligands bind to multiple types of receptors leading to different physiological responses</h3><p>(epinephrine)<br>(adrenergic receptors)<br>48<br>Different Receptor ligand complexes can activate<br>the SAME response:<br>49<br>Example: Epinephrine or glucagon can activate glycogen breakdown and<br>release of glucose into the blood<br>Turning off or dampening signaling<br>50<br>Signaling Pathways often cross-communicate<br>Signaling Networks<br>51<br>the same cellular response<br>may be induced by multiple<br>signaling pathways by<br>distinct mechanisms<br>Interaction of different<br>signaling pathways permits<br>fine-tuning of cellular<br>activities<br>Cell-Cell Adhesion and Communication- Integrating Cells into Tissues<br>Cell adhesion molecules (CAMs) classes:</p><ol><li>cadherins – cell-cell adhesion; calcium dependent e.g, E-cadherin, P-cadherin</li><li>Ig superfamily of CAMs – cell-cell adhesion; calcium-independent; some are found<br>enriched on specific cell types – e.g. N-CAM, V-CAM</li><li>Integrins – cell-matrix adhesion molecule e.g. a1 integrin, b1 integrin<br>Signal Transduction<br>• The effects of activation of cell surface receptors are<br>more complicated than a simple step-by-step<br>cascade<br>• By no means is signaling a linear event<br>• Extensive networking and cross talk<br>• Key is integration<br>• Why so complicated?<br>Amplification - Reliability - Redundance<br>53<br>When signaling goes wrong<br>• Dysregulated signaling results in inappropriate responses to stimuli<br>• Over- and under-reaction are equally devastating<br>• All disease is the result of<br>inappropriate,<br>inadequate or<br>over-enthusiastic signal transduction<br>54<br><a href="http://learn.genetics.utah.edu/content/begin/cells/badcom/">http://learn.genetics.utah.edu/content/begin/cells/badcom/</a><br>Losing the Signal:<br>Type I Diabetes<br>When the target ignores the Signal:<br>type II diabetes<br>Too much signal: Stroke<br>Multiple breakdowns: Cancer<br>When a signal doesn’t reach its target:<br>Multiple Sclerosis<br>55<br>When signaling goes wrong<br>Oncogenic transformation<br>•Uncontrolled Proliferation<br>•Suppressed Apoptotic<br>•Downregulation of antigenic surface proteins<br>Many signaling proteins are oncogenes: activating or inactivating<br>mutations are sufficient to cause transformation<br>90% human tumors<br>have activating Ras<br>Mutations<br>Activating mutations of Ras,<br>Rac, Rho or cdc42 are<br>Enough to induce cellular<br>transformation<br>In the lab<br>Some cancer-causing<br>viruses encode an<br>activated form of src<br>Suppression of pro-apoptotic<br>genes will lead to<br>transformation<br>Amplification or<br>overexpression of Her2/neu<br>is associated with<br>aggressive breast cancers<br>Mutations of receptors may<br>lead to constitutive activity<br>56<br>Studying Cell-Surface Receptors and<br>Signal Transduction Proteins<br>57<br>Kd = dissociation constant<br>measures the affinity of the receptor for the ligand<br>R + L RL<br>k<br>on<br>koff<br>Kd = [L]<br>[R] = [RL]<br>Low Kd = high affinity of ligand for receptor<br>High Kd = low affinity of ligand for receptor<br>koff - rate constant for dissociation of a ligand<br>from its receptor<br>kon - rate constant for formation of the<br>receptor-ligand complex<br>At equilibrium koff = kon<br>Kd = The concentration of ligand at which half its receptors are occupied<br>Kd = koff/kon The lower stable the RL complex, thus the lower the K koff is relative to kon, the more d<br>The lower the Kd, the lower the ligand<br>concentration required to bind 50% of receptors<br>Kd = [R][L]/[RL] Simple equilibrium-binding equation<br>58<br>For high-affinity ligands, binding assays can determine the Kd<br>and the number of receptors per cell</li><li>Suspension of cells incubated<br>for 1 h at 4oC with increasing<br>conc. of 125I-labeled insulin</li><li>Pellet cells and wash away<br>unbound insulin</li><li>Measure radioactivity = total<br>binding</li><li>Repeat binding assay in the<br>presence of 100-fold excess<br>unlabeled insulin =<br>nonspecific binding</li><li>Subtract nonspecific binding<br>from total binding = specific<br>binding</li><li>Determine total number of<br>receptors per cell</li><li>Determine Kd<br>59<br>Isolation of Membrane receptors<br>Affinity chromatography: ligand is<br>chemically linked to polystyrene<br>beads - pass homogenate over<br>column - receptor binds - release<br>receptor by passing excess ligand<br>through column<br>60<br>A typical mammalian cell has between 1,000 and 50,000 copies of receptor<br>Affinity labeling: crosslink radiolabeled ligand to receptor- follow radioactivity in<br>purification<br>Cloning of Receptors<br>• Allow identification of receptors that constitute small percentage of total<br>cellular protein, and identification of receptors from small tissue source<br>• Expression cloning<br>• Homology cloning<br>61<br>Expression Cloning of<br>Receptors<br>• Make cDNA library from appropriate tissue<br>• Express library in cell line that does not<br>express the receptor of interest<br>• Use ligand binding to identify clone that<br>encodes receptor<br>62<br>Functional Expression Assay<br>• Divide library into smaller pools<br>to find clone that encodes<br>receptor<br>• Provided cells express relevant<br>signal-transduction proteins,<br>transfected cells will now exhibit<br>normal cellular response to<br>ligand X if the cDNA encodes the<br>functional receptor<br>63<br>Homology Cloning</li></ol><ul><li>find additional variants of receptor</li><li>find novel receptors<br>Degenerative PCR (odorant receptors)<br>Or screen library at low stringency (glutamate receptors)<br>Or database search (Taste receptors)<br>64<br>65<br>• Design degenerate primers that match amino acid sequences in conserved<br>region of receptor family members<br>• Use these primers in all pairwise combinations to amplify related sequences in<br>cDNA prepared from tissue suspected of expressing the new receptor<br>• Clone and sequence DNAs from PCR<br>• Examine sequence for hallmarks of receptor family<br>• Use these DNAs as probes to screen cDNA library from tissue known to<br>express receptor<br>• Examine proteins encoded by positive cDNA clones<br>Degenerative PCR Cloning<br>The structures and actions of receptors may be studied by using biophysical<br>methods such as X-ray crystallography, NMR, circular dichroism, and dual<br>polarization interferometry.<br>Computer simulations of the dynamic behavior of receptors has been used<br>to gain understanding of their mechanism of action.<br>66<br><a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/mediaplayer/index.php?id=1875">http://www.nobelprize.org/mediaplayer/index.php?id=1875</a><br><a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/mediaplayer/index.php?id=1877&amp;view=2">http://www.nobelprize.org/mediaplayer/index.php?id=1877&amp;view=2</a><br>Research of Dr. Robert Lefkowitz led to the identification, purification, reconstitution and cloning<br>of the adrenergic receptors; the discovery of their homology with the seven transmembrane<br>spanning visual light receptor rhodopsin and the realization that there was a large gene family of<br>G protein coupled receptors.<br>Dr. Brian Kobilka was the first to crystallize one of the beta-adrenergic receptor subtypes — a key<br>first step toward determining its structure. He was then able to show in great detail the structure<br>of this GPCR when it is binding to a hormone, just as it is poised to activate its G-protein, and as<br>it is turning on its associated G-protein.<br>Nobel Prize in Chemistry 2012<br>67<br>68<br>Immuno-Assays and Affinity Techniques Can Be<br>Used to Study the Activity of Signal Transduction<br>Proteins<br>Example 1: Activation of three signal transduction proteins by phosphorylation.<br>69<br>Mouse erythrocytes progenitor cells were treated for 10 min with different concentration<br>of hormone erythropoietin<br>Example 2: A pull-down assay shows that the small GTP-binding protein Rac1 is activated by<br>platelet-derived growth factor (PDGF).<br>70<br>Lysate from cells<br>treated with vehicle<br>Lysate from cells<br>treated with PDGF<br>A. The structure of the EGFR biosensor construct consisting of the TagGFP green fluorescent<br>protein and two tandem SH2 domains from adapter protein Grb2.<br>B. EGFR activation and internalization in A549 cells. The EGFR biosensor plasmid was<br>transfected into the A549 cell line, the transfected cells treated with 100 ng/mL EGF to activate<br>EGFR and then the internalization process was observed in real time by fluorescence<br>microscopy. The increasing internalization of the biosensor-EGFR complex over time can be<br>quantitated using granularity analysis. 71<br>Figure 2. Specificity of A549 EGFR Biosensor Activity – EGF (100 ng/mL) stimulated<br>EGFR (ERBB1) internalization while Tyrphostin AG1478 (1 µM), a selective inhibitor of<br>EGFR, blocked receptor translocation to the plasma membrane and internalization.<br>Hepatocyte growth factor (HGF, 100 ng/mL), a ligand specific for HGFR has low affinity<br>for EGFR and showed much less activity than EGF. Bar = 10 µm.<br>72<br>73<br>74<br>75<br>Thank You!<br>-Please read Chapter 15 of the text book<br>-If you have a question feel free to contact at<br><a href="mailto:ssavkovi@tulane.edu">ssavkovi@tulane.edu</a><br>76</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Oxidative phosphorylation &amp; ATP synthesis 12| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/20/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-12/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/20/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-12/</id>
    <published>2021-10-20T13:29:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:07:38.457Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Oxidative-phosphorylation-ATP-synthesis-12">Oxidative phosphorylation &amp; ATP synthesis 12</h2><p>Invest 1st ATP</p><p>Aldose to ketose</p><p>Position carbonyl for aldolase (step 4) to split molecule into two 3-carbon fragments</p><p>Invest 2nd ATP</p><p>Allosteric regulation, e.g., feedback inhibition by ATP</p><p>Split 6-carbon into two 3-cabon compounds</p><p>Schiff base intermediate</p><p>Funnel DHAP through GAP into 2nd half of pathway</p><p>Catalytically “perfect” enzyme</p><p>Form high-energy intermediate</p><p>Thermodynamically unfavorable reaction</p><p>Generate NADH</p><p>1st energy payoff</p><p>Substrate level phosphorylation (phosphate transfer from carbohydrate to ADP)</p><p>Setup for next formation of high-energy intermediate</p><p>Slide 20:<br>Some 2,3-BPG falls off, binds Hb, favors O2 release</p><p>Slide 21:</p><p>Dehydration forms high-energy intermediate</p><p>Slide 22:</p><p>Substrate-level phosphorylation</p><p>Cori Cycle<br>In the Cori cycle,<br>Lactate from skeletal muscle is transferred to the liver<br>Converted to pyruvate then glucose<br>This glucose can be returned to the muscle</p><p>Glycogen<br>Regulate at PFK</p><p>Adenylate kinase<br>salvages high-energy bond of ADP<br>generates AMP, a sensitive metabolic indicator<br>Keq= 1</p><p>Low ATP or a small increase in AMP relieves PFK inhibition</p><p>xczx</p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PLAIN"><figure class="iseeu highlight /plain"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bashtmas">rm package*<br>rm  -r themes<br>rm  -rf t*<br>rm _config.*<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><pre>123      Untitled.ipynb     config    node_modules       profile.jsx  test.mdtmp.log25663File.md  _config.icarus.yml     link_list.md   package-lock.json  public    test.md.mdwebGLREADME.en.md  _config.landscape.yml  live2dDemo     package.json       scaffolds    themesREADME.md     _config.yml     live2d_models  paper.md       source    tmp</pre>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>8 Vesicular Traffic|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/18/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-8/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/18/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-8/</id>
    <published>2021-10-18T07:48:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T01:09:05.295Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Vesicular-Traffic">Vesicular Traffic</h2><ul><li>Lodish MCB, 8th ed., pages 631-659.<br>14.1 Techniques for Studying the Secretory Pathway<br>14.2 Molecular Mechanisms of Vesicle Budding and<br>Fusion<br>14.3 Early Stages of the Secretory Pathway<br>14.4 Later Stages of the Secretory Pathway</li></ul><h2 id="14-1-Studying-the-Secretory-Pathway">14.1 Studying the Secretory Pathway</h2><ul><li><strong>Various labels</strong> enable tracking protein movement through the secretory pathway to different destinations.</li><li><strong>Components required</strong> for intracellular protein trafficking have been identified by analysis of yeast temperature-sensitive secretory (sec) mutants.</li><li><strong>Cell-free assays</strong> for intercompartmental protein transport have defined individual steps of the secretory pathway.</li></ul><h3 id="Protein-Transport-through-the-Secretory-Pathway">Protein Transport through the Secretory Pathway</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Uli0H.png" alt="Protein Transport through the Secretory Pathway"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p635</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>GFP labeled viral membrane glycoproteins synthesized and transported to host cell membrane by the constitutive secretory pathway.</li><li>Looked at time points to determine cell location.</li><li>At 0 time point, VSV G-GFP retained in ER.</li><li>At 40 min, most concentrated in the Golgi.</li><li>At 180 min, most VSV G-GFP has integrated into and is diffusing within the plasma membrane.</li></ul><h3 id="Secretory-and-Endocytic-Pathways">Secretory and Endocytic Pathways</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UlY90.png" alt="Secretory and Endocytic Pathways"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p633</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Transport vesicles transport membrane and soluble proteins from one membrane-bound compartment to another.</li><li>Transport vesicles collect cargo proteins in membrane budding from a donor compartment and deliver cargo by fusing with a target membrane.</li><li>Secretory pathway distributes cargo proteins to final destinations (ER, Golgi, cell surface (including secretion) or lysosomes.</li><li>Cargo buds from the ER, fuse together to form a new cis-Golgi cisternae → move by nonvesicular cisteral maturation, and retrograde vesicle transport.</li><li>Regulated (aggregates) and constitutive secretion.</li><li>Lysosomal proteins bud and fuse with late endosome.</li><li>Endocytic vesicles bud from plasma membrane, delivered to lysosomes via late endosomes.</li></ul><h3 id="Sec-Mutants-Identify-5-Stages-of-Secretory-Pathway">Sec Mutants Identify 5 Stages of Secretory Pathway</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U1aGt.png" alt="5 Stages of Secretory Pathway"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p637</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Yeast temperature-sensitive mutants define 5 major stages and individual components involved in targeting and vesicular transport: Cytosol, Rough ER, Vesicles transporting proteins from the ER to the Golgi complex, Golgi cisternae, and constitutive secretory vesicles</li><li>Mutations simultaneously in both class B and class D functions: proteins accumulate in rough ER, not in Golgi → defines order of steps</li></ul><h3 id="ER-to-Golgi-Transport-and-Processing">ER to Golgi Transport and Processing</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U3lYn.png" alt="ER to Golgi Transport and Processing"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p636</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Yeast temperature-sensitive mutant: At 40°C is retained in ER, not processed in Golgi. At 32°C, transported to Golgi and processed.</li><li>Shows that processing of glycosylation occurs in Golgi.</li></ul><p>EXPERIMENTAL FIGURE 14-3 <strong>Transport of a membrane glycoprotein from the ER to the Golgi can be assayed based on sensitivity to cleavage by endoglycosidase D.</strong></p><ul><li>Detecting secretory protein carbohydrate modifications by compartment-specific enzymes elucidates trafficking through different compartments.</li></ul><p>Experiment:</p><ul><li>Temperature-sensitive VSV G protein – labeled with a pulse of radioactive amino acid during synthesis in cells</li><li>Split cells into two groups –<ul><li>Group 1 – Control cells maintained at 40°C – misfolded protein retained in ER</li><li>Group 2 – Experimental cells shifted to 32°C – protein moves through secretory pathway</li><li>Time points – VSV G protein extracted and treated with endoglycosidase D</li></ul></li><li>(a) Protein movement to cis-Golgi and modification:<ul><li>Protein retained in the ER – not modified</li><li>Protein moved from the ER to the cis-Golgi – core oligosaccharide Man8(GlcNAc)2 is trimmed to Man5(GlcNAc)2 by cis-Golgi resident enzymes</li><li>Endoglycosidase D – cleaves the oligosaccharide chains from proteins processed in the cis-Golgi, but not from proteins retained in the ER</li></ul></li><li>(b) SDS-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of the digestion mixtures (Autoradiography only shows labeled VSV G protein in gel.):<ul><li>(ER) resistant – uncleaved (larger-slower-migrating)</li><li>(cis-Golgi) sensitive  – cleaved (smaller-faster-migrating)</li><li>5 min – most protein resistant to EndoD cleavage – not yet moved from ER to cis-Golgi ER</li><li>60 min – most protein cleaved by EndoD cleavage – moved to and modified in the cis-Golgi</li></ul></li><li>© Percentage of EndoD-sensitive VSV G protein over time:<ul><li>Derived from electrophoretic data</li><li>40°C – little increase n sensitive protein – misfolded proteins retained in ER</li><li>32°C – most protein moved from ER to cis-Golgi and modified by 30–40 min</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Protein-Transport-from-One-Golgi-Cisternae-to-Another">Protein Transport from One Golgi Cisternae to Another</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U3jts.png" alt="Golgi Cisternae to Another"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p637</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Mutant in cis-Golgi. Cannot process from High mannose glycosylation.</li><li>Wild type processes glycosylation in each of the Golgi cisternae.</li><li>Mixing of Golgi shows cis-Golgi enzyme (N-acetylglucosamine transferase) moved from wild type medial Golgi to mutant cis-Golgi by retrograde vesicle transport during cisteral maturation process.</li></ul><p>EXPERIMENTAL FIGURE 14-5 A cell-free assay demonstrates protein transport from one Golgi cisterna to another.</p><ul><li>Cell-free transport assays – biochemical dissection of secretory pathway individual steps<br>Experiment:</li><li>VSV virus infection of cultured mutant cells lacking one of the Golgi enzymes that modify N-linked oligosaccharide chains –fate of the VSV G protein.</li><li>(a) VSV G protein modification in Golgi of intact wild-type and mutant fibroblast cells<ul><li>Wild-type cells:<ul><li>medial-Golgi – N-acetylglucosamine transferase I adds one N-acetylglucosamine to N-linked oligosaccharides</li><li>trans-Golgi – N-linked oligosaccharides further modified to more complex carbohydrate</li></ul></li><li>Mutant cells – lack medial-Golgi N-acetylglucosamine transferase I:<ul><li>medial-Golgi – no addition of N-acetylglucosamine</li><li>trans-Golgi – no further modification to complex carbohydrate</li><li>G protein reaches the cell surface with a simpler high-mannose oligosaccharide containing only two N-acetylglucosamine and five mannose residues.</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>(b) Golgi isolated from VSV-infected mutant cells and noninfected wild-type cells:<ul><li>Mutant cell Golgi – contains VSV G protein</li><li>Wild-type cell Golgi – no VSV G protein</li><li>Golgi mixed together</li></ul></li><li>Result: Some VSV G protein modified by wild-type medial-Golgi N-acetylglucosamine transferase I</li><li>Conclusion: N-acetylglucosamine transferase I – moved by transport vesicles from the wild-type medial-Golgi cisternae to the mutant cis-Golgi during cisternal maturation process.</li></ul><h2 id="14-2-Molecular-Mechanisms-of-Vesicle-Budding-and-Fusion">14.2 Molecular Mechanisms of Vesicle Budding and Fusion</h2><ul><li>Three types of coated vesicles mediate protein transport through different pathways.</li><li>Small GTPase proteins direct coat protein polymerization on donor membranes to pinch off vesicles carrying different cargoes.</li><li>Coat shedding exposes Rab and SNARE proteins that target vesicles for fusion with specific target membranes.</li></ul><h3 id="Vesicle-Budding-and-Fusion-with-a-Target-Membrane">Vesicle Budding and Fusion with a Target Membrane</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UG6de.png" alt="Vesicle Budding and Fusion"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p640</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Coat proteins bind membrane cargo cytosolic domain.</li><li>Soluble cargo bind receptors, receptor also binds coat protein.</li><li>Vesicle SNARES (v-SNARES) captured in budding vesicle.</li><li>Coat evaginates donor membrane, pinches off coated vesicle.</li><li>Monomeric GTP-binding protein also binds coat protein in GTPbound form. GTP hydrolysis → decoating. G protein also leaves.</li><li>Decoating uncovers v-SNARES, interaction with target membrane t-SNARES for membrane fusion.</li></ul><h3 id="Coated-Vesicles-Involved-in-Protein-Trafficking">Coated Vesicles Involved in Protein Trafficking</h3><ul><li>Three major types of transport vesicles: each with a different type of protein coat and monomeric GTPase protein.</li></ul><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Vesicle Type</th><th style="text-align:left">Transport Step Mediated</th><th style="text-align:left">Coat Proteins</th><th style="text-align:left">Associated GTPase</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">COPII</td><td style="text-align:left">ER to cis-Golgi</td><td style="text-align:left">Sec23/Sec24 and Sec13/Sec31, Sec16</td><td style="text-align:left">Sar1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">COPI</td><td style="text-align:left">cis-Golgi to ER Later to earlier Golgi cisternae</td><td style="text-align:left">Coatomers containing seven different COP subunits</td><td style="text-align:left">ARF</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin and adapter proteins*</td><td style="text-align:left">trans-Golgi to endosome</td><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin + AP1 complexes</td><td style="text-align:left">ARF</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left">trans-Golgi to endosome</td><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin + GGA</td><td style="text-align:left">ARF</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left">Plasma membrane to endosome</td><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin + AP2 complexes</td><td style="text-align:left">ARF</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left">Golgi to lysosome, melanosome, or platelet vesicles</td><td style="text-align:left">AP3 complexes</td><td style="text-align:left">ARF</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Sar1-Role-Assembly-Disassembly-of-COPII-Coat">Sar1 Role Assembly/Disassembly of COPII Coat</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UJz9A.png" alt="Sar1 Role Assembly/Disassembly of COPII Coat"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p641</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li><ol><li>GEF function: Sar1-GDP → Sar1-GTP, membrane bound.</li></ol></li><li><ol start="2"><li>Sar1-GTP recruits coat proteins, curvature forms bud w/ cargo.</li></ol></li><li><ol start="3"><li>GTP hydrolysis, Sar1-GDP loses affinity for vesicle membrane.</li></ol></li><li><ol start="4"><li>Sar1-GDP not membrane bound, promotes coat disassembly.</li></ol></li><li>Image: Coated vesicles accumulate during in vitro budding in presence of nonhydrolyzable GTP analog.</li></ul><h3 id="Docking-Fusion-of-Vesicle-w-Target-Membrane">Docking/Fusion of Vesicle w/Target Membrane</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UY6Cd.png" alt="Docking/Fusion"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p643</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ol><li>Vesicle Rab binds Rab effector on target membrane.</li><li>v-SNARE forms stable coiled-coil interaction with t-SNAREs (syntaxin and SNAP-25); hold vesicle close to target membrane.</li><li>Fusion of two membrane → drives dissociation of the SNARE complexes (4), freeing SNARE proteins (recycled by NSF – an AAA-family member).</li></ol><ul><li>Not shown: Rab-GTP hydrolyzed to RabGDP – dissociates Rab from the Rab effector.</li></ul><h3 id="Targeting-Sequences-on-Cytosolic-Regions-of-Cargo-Proteins-Bind-to-Specific-Coat-Proteins">Targeting Sequences on Cytosolic Regions of Cargo Proteins Bind to Specific Coat Proteins</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Signal Sequence*</th><th style="text-align:left">Signal-Bearing Protein</th><th style="text-align:left">Proteins with Signal</th><th style="text-align:left">Vesicles That Incorporate Signal Receptor</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">LUMINAL SORTING SIGNALS</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Lys-Asp-Glu-Leu (KDEL)</td><td style="text-align:left">ER-resident soluble proteins</td><td style="text-align:left">KDEL receptor in cis-Golgi membrane</td><td style="text-align:left">COPI</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Mannose 6-phosphate (M6P)</td><td style="text-align:left">Soluble lysosomal enzymes after processing in cis-Golgi</td><td style="text-align:left">M6P receptor in trans-Golgi membrane</td><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin/AP1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">CYTOPLASMIC SORTING SIGNALS</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Lys-Lys-X-X (KKXX)</td><td style="text-align:left">ER-resident membrane proteins</td><td style="text-align:left">COPI α and β subunits</td><td style="text-align:left">COPI</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Asn-Pro-X-Tyr (NPXY)</td><td style="text-align:left">LDL receptor in plasma membrane</td><td style="text-align:left">AP2 complex</td><td style="text-align:left">Clathrin/AP2</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="14-3-Early-Stages-of-the-Secretory-Pathway">14.3 Early Stages of the Secretory Pathway</h2><ul><li>COPII-coated vesicles transport newly synthesized proteins containing Golgi-targeting sequences in their cytosolic domain or bound to such proteins from the rough ER to the cis-Golgi (anterograde direction).</li><li>COPI-coated vesicles transport vesicles carrying ER/Golgi-resident proteins in the retrograde direction, which supports Golgi cisternal maturation.</li></ul><h3 id="Vesicle-Mediated-ER-and-cis-Golgi-Trafficking">Vesicle-Mediated ER and cis-Golgi Trafficking</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UN8p9.png" alt="Vesicle-Mediated ER and cis-Golgi Trafficking"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p644</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Forward (anterograde) transport: COPII vesicles ER → cis-Golgi transport.</p><ul><li>Step 1: COPII coat assembles.</li><li>Step 2: COPII coat disassembly.</li><li>Step 3: Membrane fusion<br>Reverse (retrograde) transport: COPI<br>vesicle cis-Golgi to ER transport.</li><li>Cargo: recycles membrane bilayer, v-SNAREs, and missorted ERresident proteins.</li><li>Step 4: COPI coat assembles.</li><li>Step 5: COPI coat disassembly.</li><li>Step 6: Membrane fusion.</li></ul><h3 id="KDEL-Receptor-Retrieval-of-ER-Resident-Luminal-Proteins-from-the-Golgi">KDEL Receptor Retrieval of ER-Resident Luminal Proteins from the Golgi</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UUFHK.png" alt="KDEL Receptor Retrieval"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p647</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Soluble ER proteins contain KDEL (LysAsp-Glu-Leu) ER-targeting sequence. May become missorted to cis-Golgi: Nonspecifically incorporated into COPII vesicle fluid phase.</li><li>cis-Golgi to ER retrieval mechanism: cis-Golgi acidic pH promotes receptorKDEL interactions.</li><li>Higher pH of ER → dissociates ER resident KDEL protein from the KDEL receptor. Retrieval system prevents depletion of ER luminal proteins.</li></ul><h3 id="Processing-of-N-linked-Oligosaccharide-within-cis-medial-and-trans-Golgi-Cisternae">Processing of N-linked Oligosaccharide within cis-, medial-, and trans-Golgi Cisternae</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UUXrt.png" alt="trans-Golgi Cisternae"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p648</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>trans-Golgi:</p><ul><li>N-acetylneuraminic acids added (7).</li><li>Galactoses added (6).<br>medial-Golgi:</li><li>Fucose added (5).</li><li>Mannoses removed (3).</li><li>N-acetylglucosamines (GlcNAc) added (2 and 4).<br>cis-Golgi:</li><li>Mannoses removed (1).<br>Anterograde transport occurs by cisternal maturation.</li><li>Golgi cisternae have different enzymes.</li></ul><h2 id="14-4-Later-Stages-of-the-Secretory-Pathway">14.4 Later Stages of the Secretory Pathway</h2><ul><li>The trans-Golgi network sorts proteins into vesicles targeted for different destinations.</li><li>Lysosomal enzymes bear M6P residues that are recognized by M6P-receptors and delivered by a clathrin-coated vesicle pathway to lysosomes.</li><li>Regulated secretory proteins are concentrated and stored until secretion is signaled; constitutively secreted proteins are continuously delivered to the plasma membrane.</li><li>Some proteins are processed into mature form after leaving the trans-Golgi network.</li></ul><h3 id="Vesicle-Trafficking-from-trans-Golgi-Network">Vesicle Trafficking from trans-Golgi Network</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UaDsI.png" alt=" Vesicle Trafficking"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p651</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>(5) Regulated secretory vesicles (unknown coat).</li><li>(4) Constitutive secretory vesicles (unknown coat).</li><li>(3) Clathrin-coated (+AP2) vesicles transport to late endosomes.</li><li>(2) AP complex vesicles transport directly to lysosomes.</li><li>(1) COPI vesicles: retrograde to trans-Golgi (cisternal progression).</li><li>Distal sorting trans-Golgi network: transport vesicles to plasma membrane, endosomes, and lysosomes.</li></ul><h3 id="Dynamin-Pinching-Off-of-Clathrin-Coated-Vesicles">Dynamin Pinching Off of Clathrin-Coated Vesicles</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UdltS.png" alt=" Dynamin Pinching Off of Clathrin-Coated Vesicles"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p652</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Dynamin:<ul><li>Required for pinching off of clathrin-coated vesicles</li><li>Polymerizes around vesicle neck</li><li>Hydrolyzes GTP – conformational change coupled to membrane fusion and vesicle release from the donor membrane.</li></ul></li><li>GTP hydrolysis by dynamin is required for the pinching off of clathrin-coated vesicles (cells incubated with GTP-γ-S nonhydrolyzable analogue of GTP).</li></ul><h3 id="Formation-of-Mannose-6-phosphate-M6P-to-Target-Soluble-Enzymes-to-Lysosomes">Formation of Mannose 6-phosphate (M6P) to Target Soluble Enzymes to Lysosomes</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UwrUf.png" alt=" Dynamin Pinching Off of Clathrin-Coated Vesicles"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p653</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>M6P signal directs newly synthesized enzymes to lysosomes.</p><ul><li>Step 1: cis-Golgi-localized N-acetylglucosamine (GlcNAc) phosphotransferase transfers a phosphorylated GlcNAc group to carbon 6 of one or more mannose residues.</li><li>Step 2: Phosphodiesterase removes the GlcNAc group, leaving a 6-phosphorylated mannose residue on the lysosomal enzyme.</li></ul><h3 id="Trafficking-of-Lysosomal-Enzymes-from-trans-Golgi-Network-and-Cell-Surface-to-Lysosomes">Trafficking of Lysosomal Enzymes from trans-Golgi Network and Cell Surface to Lysosomes</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Uw5V0.png" alt="Trafficking of Lysosomal Enzymes"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p654</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>M6P receptors in trans-Golgi membrane recruit M6P-lysosomal enzymes into clathrin/AP1-coated vesicles (1).</li><li>Clathrin coat disassembles (2). Coat proteins recycled (2a).</li><li>Vesicle fuses with late endosome compartment (3). Acidic pH dissociates M6P-enzyme from receptor.</li><li>Late endosome fuses with a lysosome (4). M6P receptors recycled (4a).</li><li>Some receptors are delivered to the cell surface (5a). Plasma membrane M6P receptors (5) capture missorted M6P-enzymes into clathrin-coated vesicles in the receptor-mediate endocytosis pathway (6). Deliver enzyme to endosome/lysosome (7-8)</li></ul><h3 id="I-Cell-Disease-Mistargeting-of-Lysosomal-Enzymes-to-Extracellular-Matrix">I Cell Disease: Mistargeting of Lysosomal Enzymes to Extracellular Matrix</h3><ul><li>Lack of N-acetylglucosamine phosphotransferase activity.</li><li>Lysosomal enzymes lack M6P targeting signal → constitutively secreted (5a).</li><li>Continued accumulation of undigested lysosomal contents → forms “inclusions bodies”, may eventually kill cells.</li><li>Causes developmental, physiological, and neurological abnormalities.</li><li>Referred to as Mucolipidosis.</li><li>In vitro “cure” – M6P-enzymes added to I-cell fibroblasts – internalized by endocytosis pathway and function on arrival in lysosomes. VERY EXPENSIVE.</li></ul><h3 id="Proteolytic-Processing-of-Proproteins-in-Constitutive-Regulated-Secretory-Pathways">Proteolytic Processing of Proproteins in Constitutive / Regulated Secretory Pathways</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U0BQJ.png" alt="Proteolytic Processing"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p657</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Proproteins matured after leaving trans-Golgi.</li><li>(a) Proalbumin processing – typical of proteins in constitutive secretory pathway: Furin endoprotease cleaves peptide.</li><li>(b) Insulin processing – typical of proteins in regulated secretory pathway:<ul><li>PC2 and PC3 endoproteases – cleave central region of insulin.</li><li>C peptide secreted with insulin. High C peptide levels → kidney problems or insulinoma. Low C peptide → low insulin (T1 diabetes).</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Sorting-Proteins-Destined-for-Apical-and-Basolateral-Membranes-of-Polarized-Cells">Sorting Proteins Destined for Apical and Basolateral Membranes of Polarized Cells</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U0HTP.png" alt="Sorting Proteins Destined "></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p658</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>VSV G protein only on the basolateral membrane (VSV viruses bud only from the basolateral membrane.) Serosal Mucosal</li><li>Influenza HA glycoprotein only on the apical membrane (Influenza viruses bud from only from the apical membrane). Also GPI proteins in some cell types</li><li>IgA internalized at basolateral membrane and sorted to apical membrane by transcytosis</li><li>Some hepatocyte apical membrane proteins sorted initially to basolateral membrane, endocytosed and transcytosed through endosomes to the apical membrane.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>9 Receptor-Mediated Endocytosis|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/18/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-9/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/18/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-9/</id>
    <published>2021-10-18T05:09:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-19T01:38:46.570Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Receptor-Mediated-Endocytosis">Receptor-Mediated Endocytosis</h2><h3 id="Influenza-Virus-Infects-by-Viral-Hemagglutinin-Interaction-with-Host-Cell-Sialic-Acid">Influenza Virus Infects by Viral Hemagglutinin Interaction with Host Cell Sialic Acid</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.antibody-creativebiolabs.com/img/1-7-4-Flu-Virus-4.jpg" alt="The mechanism of influenza virus infection"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.antibody-creativebiolabs.com/flu-virus.htm">© Creative Biolabs</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Host Antigen: Sialic acid; Viral Antigens: Hemagglutinin (H), Neuraminidase (N)<br>Neuraminidase cleaves host Sialic acid, enhances release of new viral particles.<br>Antiviral Neuraminidase inhibitors: Tamiflu (Oseltamivir) and Relenza (Zanamivir). Viral subtypes derive from 18 H and 11 N possible antigens. Vaccine against common H and N antigens. Changes yearly due to antigenic drift.</p><p>Endocytosis activate: [Hemagglutinin]-[Sialic]<br>Lysosome Fuse: H⁺ release to change the pH → Hemagglutinin conformation changed<br>Neuraminidase： Cleave Sialic → Enhance releases<br>Antiviral Neuraminidase inhibitors: Tamiflu (Oseltamivir) and Relenza (Zanamivir).</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><iframe  width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GyNyFqWtFyk"> </iframe></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GyNyFqWtFyk">© Dr.G Bhanu Prakash Animated Medical Videos; 2019 youtube</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="14-5-Receptor-Mediated-Endocytosis">14.5 Receptor-Mediated Endocytosis</h2><ul><li>Clathrin-coated vesicles: [Ligands]::[AP2-targeting sequences]-[Receptors]</li><li>Ligands delivers: Exp: <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr></li><li>Dissociation: Receptor-ligand complexes dissociated in acid environment:<ul><li>receptor → cytoplasm → recycling</li><li>ligand → lysosome    → degradation</li></ul></li><li>Ttransferrin carrier: Iron endocytosis Fe<sup>3+</sup> → endosome and recycle transferrin</li></ul><p>• Extracellular ligands bound to specific cell-surface receptors with cytoplasmic domain AP2-targeting sequences are internalized by clathrin-coated vesicles.<br>• The endocytic pathway delivers some ligands (e.g., <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> particles) to lysosomes, where they are degraded.<br>• The late endosome acidic environment dissociates most receptor-ligand complexes for receptor recycling to the plasma membrane and ligand degradation in lysosomes.<br>• The iron endocytosis pathway releases Fe3+ in the late endosome but recycles the transferrin carrier proteins with the receptor to the plasma membrane.</p><h3 id="Initial-Stages-of-RME-of-Low-Density-Lipoprotein-LDL-Particles">Initial Stages of <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> of Low-Density Lipoprotein (<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>) Particles</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5U9JEQ.png" alt=""><li>© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p661](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392</a>)</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> (a) <strong><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor</strong> complexes invaginated in <strong>AP2-clathrin-coated pit</strong>. <li> (b) Pit <strong>close</strong>s. Dynamin associates with neck region. <li> © <strong>AP2-Clathrin-coated vesicle</strong> containing free in cytoplasm <li> (d) <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor complexes in <strong>decoated endosome.</strong></td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><iframe  width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uPEMuOKksWU"> </iframe></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uPEMuOKksWU">© iotech Review; 2014 youtube</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p><abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr>: Receptor-mediated endocytosis</p><p><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>: low-density lipoprotein</p><ul><li><abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> is used by cells to <strong>import</strong> specific <strong>macromolecules</strong> or complexes too large to be imported by membrane transporters</li><li>Uptake specificity is <strong>receptor-dependent</strong>, in clathrin/AP2-coated vesicles.</li></ul><p>Experiment:</p><ol><li><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> particles (contain cholesterol): labeled with electron-dense, iron-containing ferritin protein (visible with EM)</li><li>Cultured fibroblasts incubated with <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-ferretin at 4°: <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> binds to <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-receptors; <mark>endocytosis process is inhibited</mark></li><li>Cells warmed to initiate endocytosis.</li></ol><p><abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> receptors:</p><ul><li>Some types cluster in clathrin-coated pits by cytoplasmic domain association with AP2 even in absence of ligand.</li><li>Others types diffuse freely in the plasma membrane until a ligand-induced conformational change associates them with AP2.</li><li>Two or more types of receptor-bound ligands, such as <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> and transferrin, can be present in the same coated pit/vesicle.</li></ul><h3 id="Cellular-Uptake-Degradation-of-LDL-by-RME">Cellular Uptake / Degradation of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> by <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr></h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UivKx.png" alt="Cellular Uptake / Degradation of LDL by RME"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p661</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>• <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor complexes completely bound at membrane surface in AP2-clathrincoated pit.<br>• Internalization of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor receptor increases as binding at cell surface decreases.<br>• Degradation begins within 10-15 minutes, as internalization reached its maximum.</p><p>Pulse-chase experiment demonstrates precursor-product relations in cellular uptake of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>.<br>Experiment:</p><ol><li><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> labeled with <sup>125</sup>I</li><li>Cultured normal human skin fibroblasts – incubated with <sup>125</sup>I-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> for 2 hours at 4°C (pulse) – <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> binds to surface <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptors; not endocytosed</li><li>Unbound <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> – washed away</li><li>Shift to 37°C –  activates <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> (chase)</li><li>Results:<ul><li><sup>125</sup>I-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> rapidly disappears from surface (binding) by <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr>.</li><li><sup>125</sup>I-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> in internal vesicles rises coincidently.</li><li>After a 15 min lag – <sup>125</sup>I-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> degradation in lysosomes increases.</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id="Model-of-LDL-Particle">Model of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Particle</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://unicoupi.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/ldl-3-1024x729.jpg" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p661</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>• Cells take up <strong>lipids from the blood</strong> in the form of large, welldefined lipoprotein <strong>complexes</strong> (<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>, VLDL, HDL, Chylomicon).<br>• All classes of lipoproteins have the <strong>same general structure</strong>. Model of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Receptor and <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Binding</p><p>• Shell composed of a <strong>phospholipid monolayer</strong> (not bilayer) containing <strong>cholesterol</strong>. Interacts with <strong>aqueous environment</strong> for transport <strong>in blood</strong>.<br>• <strong>Apolipoprotein B</strong> (ApoB) is <strong>ligand</strong> for <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor.<br>• <strong>Hydrophobic core</strong> is mostly cholesteryl esters/triglycerides (minor neutral lipids [vitamins]).</p><h3 id="Model-of-LDL-Receptor-and-LDL-Binding">Model of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Receptor and <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Binding</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UEGQA.png" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p663</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>(a) <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor at neutral pH (binding <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> at cell surface):<br>- Ligand binding arm seven cysteine-rich repeats (R1–R7) – tightly bind <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> apoB-100 (<strong>R4 and R5</strong> – most critical for <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> binding)<br>- Note receptor NPXY AP2- targeting cytosolic domain.<br>(b) <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor at acidic pH (releasing <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> in endosome):<br>- β-propeller domain histidine residues become protonated.<br>- Positively charged propeller domain binds negatively charged ligand-binding domain → release of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> particle.<br>PS: (b, bottom) <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor at pH 5.3 structure – extensive hydrophobic and ionic interactions between the β propeller and R4 and R5 repeats<br>- Human disease – Familial Hypercholesterolemia<br>- Excessive circulating <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> causes cardiovascular disease.<br>- <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor mutations cause too little <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> uptake/clearance into cells (liver cells).<br>- Several <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor mutations including a single amino acid mutation in NPXY targeting sequence causes inefficient <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> – FH disease.</p><h3 id="LDL-LDL-Receptor-Mediated-Endocytosis"><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>-<abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> Receptor Mediated Endocytosis</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UVepQ.png" alt="LDL-LDL Receptor Mediated Endocytosis"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p662</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Physiologic pH: <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor has high affinity for <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>.<br>Lysosomal pH: <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor has low affinity for <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr>.<br>Receptor recycled</p><h3 id="Clinical-Implications-Familial-Hypercholesterolemia">Clinical Implications: Familial Hypercholesterolemia</h3><ol><li>Excessive circulating <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> causes cardiovascular disease.<br>a. Heterozygous – <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> ~2X elevated in blood<br>b. Homozygous – <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> 4X-6X elevated<br>c. Atherosclerotic plaques<br>b. Premature heart attacks (as early as 20s)</li><li><abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor mutations cause too little <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> uptake or clearance into cells (liver cells).<br>a. <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptors are absent<br>b. Defective <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> binding sites<br>c. Improper folding → premature receptor degradation<br>d. NPXY mutation affects sorting to AP2 vesicles<br>e. Mutation in ApoB ligand, ↓ affinity for <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor</li><li>Cells regulate their cholesterol by<br>a. Inhibition of cholesterol synthesis<br>b. Down-regulation of <abbr title="low-density lipoprotein">LDL</abbr> receptor</li></ol><h3 id="Transferrin-Cycle">Transferrin Cycle</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5UZORe.png" alt="LDL-LDL Receptor Mediated Endocytosis"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p664</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li><p>Transferrin Cycle:</p><ul><li>Ferrotransferrin binds transferrin receptor at cell surface pH 7.0 (1).</li><li>Transferrin receptor forms AP2 clathrin-coated vesicle → <abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> to late endosome (2-4).</li><li>Acidic pH dissociates Fe3+ → Apotransferrin recycled to cell surface.</li><li>Extracellular neutral pH, receptor releases apotransferrin.</li><li>Fe3+ reduced to Fe2+ for use.</li></ul></li><li><p>Transferrin protein comes in two forms, apotransferrin (not bound to Fe3+) and Ferrotransferrin (carries Fe3+ in blood).</p></li><li><p>Transferrin binding to transferrin receptor is pH-dependent:</p><ul><li>Receptor binds Ferrotransferrin at physiologic pH (pH ~7.0).</li><li>Receptor binds Apotransferrin at lysosomal pH (pH ~5.0).</li></ul></li></ul><p><abbr title="Receptor-mediated endocytosis">RME</abbr> endocytic pathway delivers iron to cells without dissociation of the transferrin–transferrin receptor complex in endosomes.<br>Transferrin protein:</p><ul><li>Apotransferrin – no bound Fe3+</li><li>Ferrotransferrin – carries Fe3+ in blood</li><li>Binds to transferrin receptor</li></ul><p>Uptake mechanism:</p><ol><li>Ferrotransferrin dimer with two Fe3+ binds tightly to <strong>transferrin receptor</strong> at the cell surface – ~pH 7.0.</li><li>Transferrin receptor cytoplasmic <strong>tail</strong> interaction with an AP2 adapter complex – incorporates <strong>receptor-ligand</strong> complex into endocytic clathrin-coated vesicles</li><li>Clathrin <strong>disassembly</strong> uncoats vesicle.</li><li>Vesicle <strong>fuses</strong> with late endosome – acidic pH – <strong>Dissociates</strong> Fe3+ from ferrotransferrin – Fe3+ <strong>reduced</strong> to Fe2+ by endosome <strong>reductase</strong> Transported from endosome to cytoplasm Maintains apotransferrin-receptor complex</li><li><strong>Recycling</strong> of receptor-apotransferrin complex to the plasma membrane</li><li>Extracellular neutral pH destabilizes complex – <strong>releases</strong> apotransferrin from receptor</li></ol><h2 id="14-6-Directing-Membrane-Proteins-and-Cytosolic-Materials-to-the-Lysosome">14.6 Directing Membrane Proteins and Cytosolic Materials to the Lysosome</h2><p><abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr> (endosomal sorting complex required for transport)</p><ul><li>Endocytosed membrane proteins targeted for degradation in the lysosome are incorporated into vesicles that bud into the interior of the endosome.</li><li>Cellular components (e.g., <abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr>) that mediate endosome membrane budding are used to pinch off enveloped viruses such as HIV from the plasma membrane of virus-infected cells.</li><li>Autophagy envelopes a region of cytoplasm or an organelle into a double-membrane autophagosome for delivery to a lysosome.</li></ul><h3 id="Delivery-of-Plasma-Membrane-Proteins-to-Lysosome-Interior-for-Degradation">Delivery of Plasma-Membrane Proteins to Lysosome Interior for Degradation</h3><p>Membrane proteins for degradation → delivered to lysosome lumen</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Umt1g.png" alt="Membrane proteins for degradation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p666</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Mechanism:</p><ol><li>Vesicles carrying newly synthesized lysosomal membrane proteins (green) from the trans-Golgi network – fuse with the late endosome</li><li>Endosomes carrying endocytosed plasma-membrane proteins (blue) targeted for degradation – fuse with the late endosome</li><li>Late endosome:<ul><li>Plasma membrane proteins targeted for degradation – incorporated into vesicles that bud into the interior of the late endosome</li><li>Forms a multivesicular endosome</li></ul></li><li>Multivesicular endosome fuses with a lysosome:<ul><li>Internal vesicles (containing targeted membrane proteins)– degraded</li><li>Lysosomal membrane proteins – not degraded</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id="Formation-of-Multivesicular-Endosomes">Formation of Multivesicular Endosomes</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Unkuj.png" alt="Formation of Multivesicular Endosomes"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p667</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Proteins for multivesicular endosome degradation are tagged with ubiquitin at the plasma membrane, in the trans-Golgi network, or in the endosomal membrane (cargo proteins).</li><li>Ubiquitinated Hrs protein on endosomal membrane direct loading of ubiquitinated membrane cargo proteins (blue) into multivesicular endosomes.</li><li>Cytosolic <abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr> protein complexes and Hrs mediate pinching off of inwardly budding vesicles.</li><li>Vps4 ATP hydrolysis drives disassembly and recycling of <abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr> complex proteins.</li></ul><h3 id="HIV-Budding-from-Plasma-Membrane">HIV Budding from Plasma Membrane</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Und2D.png" alt="HIV Budding from Plasma Membrane"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p668</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>• Retrovirus (HIV) budding from plasma membrane exploits <abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr>/Vps4 machinery for multivesicular endosomes.<br>• Ubiquitinated viral <strong>Gag</strong> proteins function like <strong>Hrs</strong> protein → recruit <strong><abbr title="(endosomal sorting complex required for transport)">ESCRT</abbr>/Vps4 complexes</strong> to pinch off viral particle. The Autophagic Pathway<br>• Autophagic pathway delivers cytosolic proteins and organelles to lysosomes for degradation.<br>• ATG proteins induce formation of cup-shaped membrane structure around a portion of the cytosol (right) or an organelle (left) to create am autophagosome.<br>• Autophagosome envelop contents in two complete membranes.<br>• Fusion of autophagosome outer membrane with the lysosome membrane releases a singlemembrane vesicle and its contents into the lysosome interior for degradation.</p><p>Mechanism:<br>ATG proteins induce formation of cup-shaped membrane structure around</p><ul><li>(right) a portion of the cytosol</li><li>(left) an organelle such as a mitochondrion</li><li>Proteins involved include Atg 5, 8, 12, 16 – Atg 8 forms coat around autophagosome</li></ul><p>Step 1: Continued membrane addition and fusion forms autophagosome – envelops contents in two complete membranes<br>Step 2: Fusion of the autophagosome outer membrane with the lysosome membrane –</p><ul><li>Releases a single-membrane vesicle and its contents into the lysosome interior</li><li>Vesicle protein and lipid components – degraded by lysosomal hydrolases</li><li>Amino acids – permease transport across the lysosomal membrane into the cytosol for use in protein synthesis</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>7 Protein translocation|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/16/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-7/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/16/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-7/</id>
    <published>2021-10-17T02:50:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T05:07:51.612Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Protein-Translocation">Protein Translocation</h2><p>• Lodish MCB, 8th ed., pages 583-622. • 13.1 Targeting Proteins To and Across the ER Membrane<br>• 13.2 Insertion of Membrane Proteins into the ER<br>• 13.3 Protein Modifications, Folding, and Quality Control in the ER<br>• 13.4 Targeting of Proteins to Mitochondria and Chloroplasts<br>• 13.5 Targeting of Peroxisomal Proteins</p><p>Protein translocation was also called <em>protein sorting/protein targeting</em>.<br>Two types of protein sorting:</p><ul><li>single-based targeting<ul><li>Newly or completed transcriptions</li><li>Leads insertion in the membrane, trans-membrane into organelles</li></ul></li><li>vesicle based trafficking.<ul><li>Secrete protein, Glogi, lysosome, and plasma membrane</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Targeting-Proteins-To-and-Across-the-ER-Membrane">Targeting Proteins To and Across the ER Membrane</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://media.sciencephoto.com/image/c0151063/800wm/C0151063-Rough_endoplasmic_reticulum,_TEM.jpg" alt="rough ER"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="">© SCIENCE PHOTO LIBRARY</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>All soluble protein are initially delevered into ER.<br>Two main types of protein: Soluble protein and Integral protein.</p><p>Synthesis of:</p><ul><li><p>secreted proteins</p></li><li><p>integral plasma-membrane proteins</p></li><li><p>proteins destined for the ER, Golgi complex, plasma membrane, or lysosome begins on cytosolic ribosomes.</p></li><li><p>A signal sequence, <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr>, and <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> receptor system docks the ribosome on an ER translocation and cotranslationally inserts the nascent protein into or through the ER membrane.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Structure-of-the-Rough-ER">Structure of the Rough ER</h3><ul><li>Convoluted membranes <strong>continuous</strong> with nuclear membrane.</li><li>sER: Cellular <strong>lipid synthesis</strong> (sER).</li><li>rER: <strong>First step in secretory pathway</strong> – rough ER – with attached ribosomes.</li><li><strong>Synthesis</strong> and processing for plasma <strong>membrane</strong> and secreted <strong>proteins</strong>, and proteins functioning in the ER, Golgi complex and lysosomes.</li><li>Protein synthesis on the ER:<ul><li>ER membrane-bound and free cytosolic <strong>ribosomes are identical</strong>.</li><li>Membrane-bound ribosomes: <strong>recruited</strong> to the ER during synthesis of a polypeptide containing an ER signal sequence.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Secretory-Proteins-Enter-the-ER-Lumen">Secretory Proteins Enter the ER Lumen</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Nabeel-Ahmed-14/publication/295090705/figure/fig5/AS:331473874898970@1456040938788/Illustration-of-the-pulse-chase-experiment-a-A-schematic-representation-of-the.png" alt="Pulse-chase experiments"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/295090705_Accurate_prediction_of_cellular_co-translational_folding_indicates_proteins_can_switch_from_post-_to_co-translational_folding">© Daniel A. Nissley, et al. 2016</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li><strong>Pulse-chase experiments</strong>: secretory proteins are in ER lumen right after synthesis.<ul><li>before the synthesis of first 70 AAs.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Pulse radiolabeled amino acids</strong><ul><li>only newly synthesized proteins labeled.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Cells homogenized</strong>: shears rough ER into small vesicles called microsomes.</li><li><strong>Purified microsomes</strong> treated with a protease: (–) Detergent: proteins in ER are protected from digestion. (+) Detergent: dissolves ER membrane; proteins not protected from digestion.<ul><li>Detergent: disrupt the membrane system to expose the secrete protein</li></ul></li><li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: newly made proteins are inside the microsomes (lumen of the rough ER) after synthesis.</li></ul><h3 id="Simultaneous-Translation-Translocation">Simultaneous Translation / Translocation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5tcLuQ.png" alt="Simultaneous Translation / Translocation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p587</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Hydrophobic N-terminal signal sequence <strong>targets</strong> secretory proteins to ER membrane during translation from free cytosolic ribosomes.</li><li><strong>Initiates</strong> translocation of the growing polypeptide across the ER membrane</li><li>Signal sequences <strong>cleaved</strong> from most secretory proteins after translocation.</li><li>Cell-free experiments demonstrate that translocation of secretory proteins into microsomes is coupled to translation – <strong>cotranslational insertion</strong></li></ul><h3 id="Cotranslational-Translocation">Cotranslational Translocation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/322280842/figure/fig1/AS:941343769636891@1601445252402/Co-translational-translocation-in-eukaryotes-relies-on-SRP-for-targeting-to-the-Sec61.gif" alt="Cotranslational Translocation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/322280842_Inhibitors_of_protein_translocation_across_membranes_of_the_secretory_pathway_novel_antimicrobial_and_anticancer_agents">© Victor Van Puyenbroeck, et al. 2018</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://o.quizlet.com/ttIovhs8meU4Lrwi1AoeMw_b.png" alt=""></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p589</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ol><li><strong>SS transcription</strong>: N-terminal ER signal sequence (SS) emerges from the ribosome first.</li><li><strong><abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> recognition</strong>: Signal recognition particle (<abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr>) binds SS – arrests protein synthesis.</li><li><strong>SS, SPR, Ribosome; SRPr complex</strong>: SPR-ribosome complex binds <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> receptor in ER membrane; interaction strengthened by the binding of <strong>GTP</strong> to both the <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> and its receptor.</li><li><strong><abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> dissociates</strong>: Transfer of nascent polypeptide–ribosome to translocon; opens translocation channel. <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> and <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> receptor both hydrolyze bound GTP; dissociates <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> from ribosome and receptor; restarts protein synthesis.</li><li><strong>SS cleaved</strong>: Peptide passes thru translocon into ER lumen; signal sequence cleaved.</li><li><strong>extrudes</strong>: Growing peptide chain extrudes thru translocon into ER.</li><li><strong>Ribosome Dissociated</strong>: Translation finishes; ribosome is released</li><li><strong>Folded</strong>: Translocated protein folds into native conformation and translocon closes.</li></ol><h3 id="Nucleoside-hydrolysis-reactions-that-regulate-processes-using-a-timer-like-function">Nucleoside hydrolysis reactions that regulate processes using a timer-like function</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">GTP</th><th style="text-align:left">ATP</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><li> Ef-tu in protein synthesis<li> G-protein signaling<li> Ran in nuclear import/export <li> <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> and <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> receptor <li> Tubulin dynamic instability <li> Sar1 in vesicle budding <li> Rabs in vesicle fusion <li> Dynamin in bud neck closure</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Actin for assembly<li> Hsp70 for client binding/release<li> Glucokinase for positive cooperativity</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Post-translational-Translocation">Post-translational Translocation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://o.quizlet.com/Q3STS5qIW8.MvMS2RCH24Q_b.png" alt="Post-translational Translocation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p589</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>BiP: (Hsp70 family ATP-dependent molecular chaperone) BiP bind peptide could prevent it’s backward sliding.</p><ol><li>Direct interaction: SS + translocon. N-terminal segment of the protein enters the ER lumen; signal peptidase <strong>cleaves</strong> SS.</li><li><strong>BiP</strong> + <strong>Sec63</strong> complex: provide driving force for unidirectional translocation across the ER membrane.</li><li><strong>Random inward sliding</strong>: exposes more nascent protein.</li><li><strong>BiP-ADP binding</strong>: ratchets nascent protein into ER. BiP ATP hydrolysis essentially powers protein translocation across membrane.</li><li><strong>Releases</strong>: ATP for ADP exchange releases BiP from nascent protein.</li><li><strong>Folding</strong>: Protein folds into native conformation.</li></ol><h2 id="13-2-Insertion-of-Membrane-Proteins-into-the-ER">13.2 Insertion of Membrane Proteins into the ER</h2><ul><li>Topogenic sequences:<ul><li><strong>N-terminal signal sequences</strong></li><li>Internal sequence<ul><li><strong>internal stop-transfer anchor sequences</strong></li><li><strong>internal signal-anchor sequences</strong></li></ul></li><li>direct the insertion of nascent proteins into the ER membrane.</li></ul></li><li>Topogenic sequences can be predicted by computer by identify hydrophobic topogenic segments.</li><li><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> anchor: Initiate as Type I but cleaved and transferred into <abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> molecue</li></ul><h3 id="Classes-of-ER-Membrane-Proteins">Classes of ER Membrane Proteins</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NkIIg.png" alt="Classes of ER Membrane Proteins"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p594</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Classified by<ul><li><mark>O</mark>rientation</li><li><mark>L</mark>ocations of N/C-termini</li><li>the <mark>T</mark>ypes of targeting signals.</li></ul></li><li><mark>α helices</mark> segments (20- 25 A, Hydrophobic) → Embed.</li><li>Hydrophilic regions fold into conformations outside membrane.</li><li>Type IV: n × α helices.</li><li><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> anchor: protein in membrane by phospholipid anchor.</li></ul><h3 id="Type-I-Insertion-Orientation">Type I Insertion/Orientation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NkHRs.png" alt="Type I Insertion/Orientation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p595</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Topology:</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:right">ER Lumen</th><th style="text-align:center">Transmembrane Domain</th><th style="text-align:left">Cytosol</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:right">N-</td><td style="text-align:center">Single</td><td style="text-align:left">-C</td></tr></tbody></table><ol><li>Translocation initiation and <abbr title="Single sequence">Ss</abbr> cleavage.</li><li>Ppeptide elongates.</li><li>Elongation until hydrophobic <em><strong>stop-transfer anchor sequence</strong></em> enters translocon → prevents further translocation.</li><li><ul><li>Stop-transfer anchor sequence (<strong>α-helix</strong>) <strong>moves laterally into membrane</strong>.</li><li><mark>Translocon closes</mark>.</li></ul></li><li>Newly synthesized AA remain <mark>in cytosol</mark>.</li><li>Synthesis completes; ribosomal subunits are <mark>released</mark>.</li></ol><p>PS: cotraslation translocation<br>Sec61α domain, plug peptide.<br>Exp: <abbr title="Human growth hormone">HGH</abbr> receptor</p><h3 id="Types-II-and-III-Insertion-Orientation">Types II and III Insertion/Orientation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://tshi.page/ox/img/mem-insert-type-iii-iii.png" alt="Types II and III Insertion/Orientation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p596</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Have single internal hydrophobic <strong>signal-anchor sequence</strong> (<abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr>; serves as both ER signal sequence and membrane anchor).</li></ul><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Category</th><th style="text-align:left">Type I</th><th style="text-align:left">Type II</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">N-terminal <abbr title="Single sequence">Ss</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">None</td><td style="text-align:left">None</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Yes</td><td style="text-align:left">Yes</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Positive charges adjacent to <abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">towards cytosol</td><td style="text-align:left">towards cytosol</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> binds</td><td style="text-align:left">internal <abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">internal <abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Positively charged residues</td><td style="text-align:left">N</td><td style="text-align:left">C</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">cytosol</td><td style="text-align:left">C</td><td style="text-align:left">N</td></tr></tbody></table><p><abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr> functions both <abbr title="Single sequence">Ss</abbr> &amp; <abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr>, which is recognition and anchor.</p><p>Type II: Start as Type I but not be cleaved, as a result, the N terminal still on the cytosol side.<br>Type III: N-terminal was anchored immediately since the <abbr title="signal-anchor sequence">SAS</abbr> is so closes to N-terminal. As a result, rest of sequence can’t enter the lumen.</p><h3 id="Topology-Orientation-of-ER-Membrane">Topology/Orientation of ER Membrane</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NkXLV.png" alt="Topology/Orientation of ER Membrane"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p598</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Red: Topogenic Sequences<br>Blue: Soluble, hydrophilic sequences</p><p>The high dense charged residues adjacent to SA were in the cytosol side.</p><h3 id="GPI-Anchored-Proteins"><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr>-Anchored Proteins</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NkxdU.png" alt="Topology/Orientation of ER Membrane"><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p599</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><li>  <abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> anchor covalently attaches protein in <strong>extracellular plasma membrane</strong>. <li> (a) <mark><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> molecule</mark>: hydrophobic <strong>fatty acyl chains</strong> with polar <strong>phosphate groups and carbohydrate moieties</strong>. <li> (b) <mark><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr>-anchor</mark>: 1. Type I protein was synthesized. Transmembrane domain was cleaved and transferred into <abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> by <strong>Transamidase</strong>. <li> Biological Functions: 1, Higher mobility; 2, Not cytosol side residues which might anchor to cytoskeleton;</td></tr></tbody></table><p><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr>: Amphipathic glycosylphosphatidylinositol; Amphipathic<br><abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr> Transamidase: remove the membrane span to the <abbr title="glycosylphosphatidylinositol (糖基磷脂酰肌醇)">GPI</abbr>-linked protein.<br>Tag contacts with ER would transfer to the cell surface through body infusion.</p><h2 id="13-3-Protein-Modifications-Folding-and-Quality-Control-in-the-ER">13.3 Protein Modifications, Folding, and Quality Control in the ER</h2><ul><li>Oligosaccharides, disulfide bonds, and prolyl isoform modification; Cleavage</li><li>ER <strong>chaperones</strong> + <strong>Lectins</strong>:<ul><li>help &amp; accelerates correct folding,</li><li>transport to the cytosol to <strong>ubiquitin</strong>.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Hinder</strong>: Only good protein → Golgi complex in vesicles.</li></ul><h3 id="N-Linked-Oligosaccharide-Precursor-Biosynthesis">N-Linked Oligosaccharide Precursor Biosynthesis</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://media.cheggcdn.com/media%2F3f8%2F3f8c3e48-3918-4759-a87f-15b20e7c9f06%2Fphpdmepck.png" alt="N-Linked Oligosaccharide Precursor Biosynthesis"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p602</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>N-linked oligosaccharide → RER.</li><li>Oligosaccharide precursor + dolichol phosphate.</li><li>Sugar residues added sequentially as activated sugar-NDPs.</li><li>Steps 1-3: Two N-acetylglucosamine (GlcNAc) and five mannose residues added on ER membrane cytosolic face.</li><li>Step 4: intermediate is flipped to ER membrane luminal face.</li><li>Steps 5-6: Additional sugar-NDPs flipped to the luminal face and transferred to the growing oligosaccharide precursor.</li><li>Tunicamycin <strong>blocks</strong> step 1, inhibits all N-linked glycosylation.</li></ul><p>PS:</p><ul><li>Precursor contain 14 residues and very conservative among eukaryotic.</li><li>Function: Glc₃Man₉(GlcNAc)₂</li><li>formation: Dolichol Phosphate -[pyrophosphate bond]- GlcNAc₂ (Core)→ Man₉ (Branches) → Glc₃ (Tag)</li><li>Asn-X-Ser/Thr: Not all, Not predictable.</li><li>Glycosidase: remove Glc₃ → Act as a signal that the oligosaccharide is complete and ready to be transferred to a protein.</li></ul><p>Mucose; extra cellular protein have abundant of glycosylated residues.</p><p>Glucose is important: ER quality contra mechanisms for protein folding.</p><ul><li>Protein is maturing, Glucose are being kicked out.</li><li>Protein has be sensed weather it is folded completely.</li><li>The fate was determined by the glucose.</li></ul><h3 id="N-Linked-Glycosylation-and-Processing">N-Linked Glycosylation and Processing</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NEnBV.png" alt="N-Linked Glycosylation and Processing"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p603</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Promotes protein <strong>folding</strong>, <strong>stability</strong>, <strong>adhesion</strong>, and <strong>recognition</strong>.</li><li>Step 1: Oligo precursor transferred into N residues(Asn-X- Ser/Thr)</li><li>Steps 2–4: Remove: Glucose and mannose residues (plays a role in the <mark>correct folding</mark> of many ER proteins).</li><li>Transfer the protein from ER to Golgi.</li><li>Misfolded proteins <strong>delocated</strong> into lumen into the cytosol for degradation.</li></ul><p>PS:<br>Examples</p><ul><li>Leukocytes → Cell adhesion molecules</li><li>ABO blood system</li></ul><h3 id="Protein-Disulfide-Isomerase-PDI">Protein Disulfide Isomerase (PDI)</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs12276-020-0401-5/MediaObjects/12276_2020_401_Fig1_HTML.png" alt="PDI"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s12276-020-0401-5#Fig1">© Bei Xiong, et al</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Disulfide bonds rearrangement.</li><li>Active site contains two cysteines that can have reduced dithiol or oxidized disulfide forms.</li><li>Functions:<ul><li>Formation: Forms disulfide with PDI. Substrate second thiol forms disulfide within substrate, releasing <strong>reduced PDI</strong>. Reduced PDI is <strong>oxidized by Ero1</strong>, reforming <strong>active site</strong> disulfide bond.</li><li>Rearrangement: Reduced PDI reacts similarly to rearrange disulfide bond within substrate. Reaction is repeated until substrate is folded into thermodynamically most stable conformation.</li></ul></li></ul><p>thiol group: sulfhydryl group.<br>Lectins: carbohydrate binding protein calnexin (On the membrane) and calreticulin (in the lumen) bind selectively to certain N-linked oligosaccharides to help protein folding, reducing peptides aggregate.</p><p>Only in the ER:</p><ol><li>for a disulfide bond, Is a mixed disulfide bond, using disulfide bond to connect.</li><li>Correct disulfide bond in cell.</li></ol><h3 id="Summary-Hemagglutinin-HA-Folding-Assembly">Summary: Hemagglutinin (HA) Folding/Assembly</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NQwU1.png" alt="Hemagglutinin (HA) Folding/Assembly"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p605</a></td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NQcKe.png" alt="Hemagglutinin (HA) Folding/Assembly"><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p605</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><li> 1. BiP, and Calreticulin bind nascent protein to prevent premature folding into incorrect conformation.<li> 2. PDI → disulfide bonds → Folding allows trimer formation<li> 3. Complete influenza virion with HA₀ (HA₁ + HA₂) trimer spikes protruding from viral membrane surface.</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Peptidyl-Prolyl-Isomerase-PPI-of-X-pro-peptide-bonds">Peptidyl-Prolyl Isomerase (PPI) of X-pro peptide bonds</h3><ul><li>Accelerates rotation about peptidyl-prolyl bonds in <strong>unfolded segments</strong> of a polypeptide</li><li>Rate-limiting step in the folding of protein domains</li></ul><h3 id="Ire1-The-Unfolded-Protein-Response">Ire1: The Unfolded Protein Response</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5N3brD.png" alt="Ire1"></th><th style="text-align:left"><li>1. [Bip]-[Ire1]: heterodimer: Ire1 homodimer was prevented <li>2. Unfolded protein↑ → Bip↓ : [Bip]-[Ire1] → Bip + Ire1 <li>3. Ire1 + Ire1 → [Ire1]₂ homodimer → Unspliced Hac1 mRNA → Spliced Hac1 mRNA → Translation → Hac1 TF → Nuclear → Gene expression</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p606</a></td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="13-4-Targeting-of-Proteins-to-Mitochondria-and-Chloroplasts">13.4 Targeting of Proteins to Mitochondria and Chloroplasts</h2><ul><li><mark>States</mark>: Mitochondrial and chloroplast <strong>proteins</strong> encoded by nuclear genes are <strong>synthesized on cytosolic</strong> ribosomes, and maintained in an <strong>unfolded</strong> state by <strong>chaperones</strong>.</li><li><mark>Targeting Sequences</mark>: <strong>N-terminal</strong> targeting sequences direct post-translational transport of the unfolded proteins through <strong>translocons</strong> into the organelles.</li><li><mark>Direction</mark>: Multiple internal <strong>targeting sequences direct</strong> protein targeting inside the organelles to different membrane and lumen <strong>destinations</strong>.</li><li><mark>PS</mark>: Energy required, usually two system: one for targeting the organelles, one for sorting to the part of the organelle.</li></ul><h3 id="Organelle-targeting-sequences-are-similar-in-their-location-and-general-function-but-differ-in-sequence-characteristics">Organelle targeting sequences are <strong>similar in</strong> their location and general <strong>function, but differ in sequence characteristics.</strong></h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NGf91.png" alt="Targeting Sequences That Direct Proteins from the Cytosol to Organelles"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p609</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Import-of-Mitochondrial-Proteins">Import of Mitochondrial Proteins</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://os.bio-protocol.org/attached/image/20210616/20210616185647_2464.jpg" alt="Import of Mitochondrial Proteins"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://bio-protocol.org/e4057">© bio protocol, 2021</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>N-terminal targeting sequence<ul><li><mark>Variety</mark>: share common motif but different in sequence</li><li><mark>Composition</mark>: rich in hydrophobic (A, L), + charged, and hydroxlated (S, T). But lack of - charged (D, E).</li><li><mark>Property</mark>: Amphipathic α-helix → one side hydrophobic, one side opsitive charged.</li></ul></li><li>Required for uptake:<ul><li>Matrix-targeting sequence</li><li>Respiring mitochondria (proton-motive force)</li><li>ATP</li><li>cytosolic chaperone proteins that maintain the precursor proteins in an unfolded conformation.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Import-into-Mitochondrial-Matrix">Import into Mitochondrial Matrix</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NYTFH.png" alt="Targeting Sequences That Direct Proteins from the Cytosol to Organelles"><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p611</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><li>1. Cytosol: Protein + chaperones. (Hsp70, Hsp90) <li>2. <mark>Initiating</mark>: <abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr> + <em>import receptor</em>. <li>3. <abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr> → outer membrane translocon (Tom40, <em>general import pore</em>). <li>4. Protein → Tom → inner translocon (Tim). <li>5. Matrix Hsp70+Cargo: Import↑. <li>6. [Hsp70]-[Cargo] + ATP → ADP + Pi + Cargo; <strong>Targeting Sequence Cleaved</strong> <li>7. Folds (may use other chaperones).</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Matrix-targeting sequence (<abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr>)</p><h3 id="Three-Pathways-to-Inner-Mitochondrial-Membrane">Three Pathways to Inner Mitochondrial Membrane</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NsqLd.png" alt="Three pathways to the inner mitochondrial membrane from the cytosol"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p615](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Path</th><th style="text-align:left">Signal</th><th style="text-align:left">Receptor</th><th style="text-align:left">Insertion</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Path A</td><td style="text-align:left">N’ <abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Tom and Tim</td><td style="text-align:left">Stop-transfer anchor sequence: Tim block Transfer</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Path B</td><td style="text-align:left">N’ <abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Tom and Tim</td><td style="text-align:left">Oxa1: insert protein</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Path C</td><td style="text-align:left">Internal Sequence</td><td style="text-align:left">Tom</td><td style="text-align:left">Different Tim incorporates multiple hydrophobic segments</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Two-Pathways-to-Mitochondria-Intermembrane-Space">Two Pathways to  Mitochondria Intermembrane Space</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NywOH.png" alt="Two Pathways to Intermembrane Space"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p616](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left"></th><th style="text-align:left">Path A</th><th style="text-align:left">Path B</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Signal Sequence</td><td style="text-align:left"><abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr> (removed in matrix)</td><td style="text-align:left">No <abbr title="Matrix-targeting sequence">MTS</abbr> or Tim targeting sequences.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Inner membrane</td><td style="text-align:left">Stop transfer sequence → releases from Tim</td><td style="text-align:left">Don’t involved</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Release</td><td style="text-align:left">Inner membrane protease</td><td style="text-align:left">Stay at here and form disulfide bonds to prevent reverse translocation</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Two-Pathways-to-Chloroplasts-Intermembrane-Space">Two Pathways to  Chloroplasts Intermembrane Space</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5Nchon.png" alt="Two Pathways to Chloroplasts Intermembrane Space"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p616](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Through Toc|Tic → <abbr title="基质">Stromal</abbr> import sequence cleavage → <abbr title="类囊体">Thylakoid</abbr> targeting sequence exposes.<br><mark>Path A:</mark></li><li><abbr title="类囊体">Thylakoid</abbr> - targeting sequence binds <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> → <abbr title="Signal recognition particle">SRP</abbr> receptor and translocon.</li><li>Translocation of protein into thylakoid lumen.</li><li><abbr title="类囊体">Thylakoid</abbr>- targeting sequence-removed.<br><mark>Path B:</mark></li><li><strong>Twin arginine signal</strong> induces <abbr title="twin-arginine translocation">Tat</abbr> (Twin-arginine translocation).</li><li>pH gradient across thylakoid membrane drives translocation. (Bound metal Ion)</li><li>Cleavage of <abbr title="twin-arginine translocation">Tat</abbr> sequence.</li></ul><h2 id="13-5-Targeting-of-Peroxisomal-Proteins">13.5 Targeting of Peroxisomal Proteins</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/18/5NhVR1.png" alt="Two Pathways to Chloroplasts Intermembrane Space"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p616](<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Luminal proteins are from cytosolic ribosomes, <strong>contain a targeting sequence</strong>, and are incorporated into the <strong>peroxisome post-translationally</strong>.</li><li><strong>Folded</strong> luminal proteins are <strong>imported by</strong> a system involving a <strong>cytosolic receptor</strong> protein and <strong>translocation machinery</strong> on the peroxisomal <strong>membrane</strong>.</li><li><strong>Peroxisomal membrane proteins</strong> contain different <strong>targeting sequences</strong> than <strong>peroxisomal matrix</strong> proteins and are imported by a <strong>different pathway</strong>.</li></ul><p>Targeting sequence (PTS1): C-terminal peroxisomal recognized by Pex5 receptor<br>Cytosolic Pex5 receptor<br>Pex14: receptor/channel</p><p>Peroxisome luminal proteins:</p><ul><li>Encoded by <strong>nuclear genes</strong> and synthesized on <strong>free ribosomes</strong> in the cytosol.</li><li>Incorporated into preexisting or newly generated peroxisomes.</li><li>PTS1 + Pex5 → [PTS1]-[Pex5] →  [PTS1]-[Pex5]-[Pex14] → [Pex5]-[Pex14] → PTS1 + Lumen.</li><li>Pex10: [Pex5]-[Pex14] + Ub → Pex14 + [Pex5]-[Ub]→ + ATP → ADP + Pex5 + Ub</li><li>Can be PTS2/Pex7 instead of PTS1/Pex5.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Online Blast with Biopython</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/15/Bioinfor/biopython-blast/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/15/Bioinfor/biopython-blast/</id>
    <published>2021-10-15T16:41:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:25:51.819Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Quick-Start">Quick Start</h2><p>source: <a href="https://www.tutorialspoint.com/biopython/biopython_overview_of_blast.htm">© Biopython</a></p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PYTHON"><figure class="iseeu highlight /python"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio.Blast <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> NCBIWWW<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio.Blast <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> NCBIXML<br><br>sequence_data = <span class="hljs-built_in">open</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;blast_example.fasta&quot;</span>).read()<br>result_handle = NCBIWWW.qblast(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;blastn&quot;</span>, <span class="hljs-string">&quot;nt&quot;</span>, sequence_data)<br>E_VALUE_THRESH = <span class="hljs-number">1e-20</span><br><br><span class="hljs-keyword">with</span> <span class="hljs-built_in">open</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;results.xml&#x27;</span>, <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;w&#x27;</span>) <span class="hljs-keyword">as</span> save_file:<br>  blast_results = result_handle.read()<br>  save_file.write(blast_results)<br><br>print(sequence_data)<br>E_VALUE_THRESH = <span class="hljs-number">1e-20</span><br><span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> record <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> NCBIXML.parse(<span class="hljs-built_in">open</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;results.xml&quot;</span>)):<br>    <span class="hljs-keyword">if</span> record.alignments:<br>       print(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;\n&quot;</span>)<br>       print(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;query: %s&quot;</span> % record.query[:<span class="hljs-number">100</span>])<br>       <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> align <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> record.alignments:<br>                print(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;match: %s &quot;</span> % align.title[:<span class="hljs-number">100</span>])<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><pre>  >gnl|alu|X55502_HSAL000745 (Alu-J)  TGCCTTCCCCATCTGTAATTCTGGCACTTGGGGAGTCCAAGGCAGGATGATCACTTATGC  CCAAGGAATTTGAGTACCAAGCCTGGGCAATATAACAAGGCCCTGTTTCTACAAAAACTT  TAAACAATTAGCCAGGTGTGGTGGTGCGTGCCTGTGTCCAGCTACTCAGGAAGCTGAGGC  AAGAGCTTGAGGCTACAGTGAGCTGTGTTCCACCATGGTGCTCCAGCCTGGGTGACAGGG  CAAGACCCTGTCAAAAGAAAGGAAGAAAGAACGGAAGGAAAGAAGGAAAGAAACAAGGAG  AG  query: gnl|alu|X55502_HSAL000745 (Alu-J)  match: gi|120310614|gb|AC190318.8| Rhesus Macaque BAC CH250-278P13 () complete sequence  match: gi|149944763|gb|AC204073.5| Rhesus Macaque BAC CH250-450C10 () complete sequence  match: gi|218436709|dbj|AP007219.1| Macaca fuscata fuscata DNA, clone: MSB2-167F16, complete sequence  match: gi|1777294620|ref|XM_009195938.4| PREDICTED: Papio anubis SEC14 like lipid binding 5 (SEC14L5), tran</pre><h2 id="Tricks">Tricks</h2><p>Blast Sequence from Uniprot with Organism Option</p><p>From: <a href="https://www.biostars.org/p/439571/">zorbax; Biostars 2020</a></p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PYTHON"><figure class="iseeu highlight /python"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> urllib.request<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> SeqIO<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio.Blast <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> NCBIWWW<br><br>url = <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;https://www.uniprot.org/uniprot/Q9LZP9.fasta&#x27;</span><br>urllib.request.urlretrieve(url, <span class="hljs-string">&quot;chain_N.faa&quot;</span>)<br><br>record = SeqIO.read(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;chain_N.faa&quot;</span>, <span class="hljs-built_in">format</span>=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;fasta&quot;</span>)<br>result_handle = NCBIWWW.qblast(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;blastp&#x27;</span>, <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;nr&#x27;</span>, record.seq,<br>                               entrez_query=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;txid3702[ORGN]&quot;</span>)<br><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><h2 id="Download-best-matched-seq-from-the-blast-result">Download best matched seq from the blast result</h2><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PYTHON"><figure class="iseeu highlight /python"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> Entrez<br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># Tell NCBI who you are</span><br>Entrez.email=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;example@outlook.com&quot;</span><br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># Acquire the sequences</span><br><span class="hljs-comment"># If you are searching for DNA sequences, then db=&quot;nucleotide&quot;</span><br><br>handle = Entrez.efetch( db=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;protein&quot;</span>, <span class="hljs-built_in">id</span>=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;NP_172363.1&quot;</span>, rettype=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;fasta&quot;</span>, retmode=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;text&quot;</span>)<br>print(handle.read())<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><h3 id="Esearch-in-terminal">Esearch in terminal</h3><p>We can use esearch to dwonload the fast file<br>source: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK179288/">NCBI Book</a></p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="BASH"><figure class="iseeu highlight /bash"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">conda install -c bioconda entrez-direct<br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># for nucleotide</span><br>esearch -db nucleotide -query <span class="hljs-string">&quot;KAG7629426.1&quot;</span> | efetch -format fasta<br><span class="hljs-comment"># for protein sequences</span><br>esearch -db protein -query <span class="hljs-string">&quot;KAG7629426.1&quot;</span> | efetch -format fasta<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><h2 id="Practices">Practices</h2><p>Find the homologs gene from 10 different species by blast</p><p>organism information: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Taxonomy/Browser/wwwtax.cgi?mode=Tree&amp;id=38039&amp;lvl=3&amp;lin=f&amp;keep=1&amp;srchmode=1&amp;unlock">NCBI</a></p><ol><li>Find a list of organism</li></ol><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PYTHON"><figure class="iseeu highlight /python"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio.Blast <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> NCBIWWW<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio.Blast <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> NCBIXML<br><span class="hljs-keyword">from</span> Bio <span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> SeqIO<br><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> urllib.request<br><br><br><br>Organ_list = [<span class="hljs-string">&quot;9527&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;499232&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9597&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9601&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;61851&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;716690&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9480&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9521&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;174599&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;37295&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;1861701&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;1812036&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;30596&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9604&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9504&quot;</span>,<br>  <span class="hljs-string">&quot;9480&quot;</span>]<br><br><span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> i <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> Organ_list:<br>    record = SeqIO.read(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;chain_N.faa&quot;</span>, <span class="hljs-built_in">format</span>=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;fasta&quot;</span>)<br>    result_handle = NCBIWWW.qblast(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;blastp&#x27;</span>, <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;nr&#x27;</span>, record.seq,<br>                                   entrez_query=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;txid&quot;</span>+ i +<span class="hljs-string">&quot;[ORGN]&quot;</span>)<br><br>    <span class="hljs-keyword">with</span> <span class="hljs-built_in">open</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&#x27;results.xml&#x27;</span>, <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;w&#x27;</span>) <span class="hljs-keyword">as</span> save_file:<br>      blast_results = result_handle.read()<br>      save_file.write(blast_results)<br>    E_VALUE_THRESH = <span class="hljs-number">1e-20</span><br>    Num = <span class="hljs-number">0</span><br>    <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> record <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> NCBIXML.parse(<span class="hljs-built_in">open</span>(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;results.xml&quot;</span>)):<br>        Num += <span class="hljs-number">1</span><br>        <span class="hljs-keyword">if</span> record.alignments:<br>           print(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;\n&quot;</span>)<br>           print(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;query: %s&quot;</span> % record.query[:<span class="hljs-number">100</span>])<br>           <span class="hljs-keyword">for</span> align <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> record.alignments:<br>                    align.title.split(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;|&quot;</span>)[<span class="hljs-number">1</span>]<br>                    <span class="hljs-keyword">if</span> Num &lt; <span class="hljs-number">4</span>:<br>                        A = align.title<br>                        handle = Entrez.efetch( db=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;protein&quot;</span>, <span class="hljs-built_in">id</span>=A.split(<span class="hljs-string">&quot;|&quot;</span>)[<span class="hljs-number">1</span>], rettype=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;fasta&quot;</span>, retmode=<span class="hljs-string">&quot;text&quot;</span>)<br>                        print(handle.read())<br><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Blast hundreds of sequence with Biopython scripts</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Bio" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Bio/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Python" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Python/"/>
    
    <category term="Bioinformatic" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Bioinformatic/"/>
    
    <category term="Scripts" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Scripts/"/>
    
    <category term="Biopython" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biopython/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Enzymatic Catalysis, Catalytic Mechanisms 10| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/08/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-10/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/08/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-10/</id>
    <published>2021-10-08T13:40:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:07:04.318Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Enzymatic-Catalysis-Catalytic-Mechanisms">Enzymatic Catalysis, Catalytic Mechanisms</h2><blockquote><p>1.General Properties of Enzymes<br>2.Activation Energy and the Reaction Coordinate<br>3.Catalytic Mechanisms4.Serine Proteases (pp. 342-347)</p></blockquote><blockquote><ul><li>Give examples of various levels of substrate specificity, and explain specificity differences exhibited by serine proteases</li><li>Give examples of reactions that utilize coenzymes NAD, FAD, Coenzyme A, and lipoic acid (metabolism lectures), and specify the role of the coenzyme</li><li>Describe catalysis in terms of a reaction-coordinate energy diagram</li><li>Classify enzymes by type of reaction</li><li>Explain catalysis by enzymes in terms of chemical mechanisms</li><li>Elaborate the catalytic mechanism of a chymotrypsin</li><li>Explain divergent and convergent evolution</li><li>Discuss the similarity of primary structure vs. tertiary structure in proteins as evidence supporting the existence of homology</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Enzymes-differ-from-chemical-catalysts">Enzymes differ from chemical catalysts</h2><ul><li>rates↑; Reaction specifity↑</li><li>Mider reaction conditions</li><li>Capacity for regulation</li></ul><h3 id="How-Enzymes-Work">How Enzymes Work</h3><ul><li>trhough the foramtion of weak bonds between the enzyem and the substrate.</li><li>help arrange the substrate in a position favorable for reaction</li></ul><h3 id="Catalysis-by-Transition-state-Stabilization">Catalysis by Transition-state Stabilization</h3><p>CH_3_ than H, rate increased 315 times: transition-state stabilization<br>Carbon -&gt; Aceessi  for the hydroxyl group;</p><p>L-Proline → [Planar transition stte] → D-Proline<br>L-Proline : 109.5°; transition state: 20°</p><p>I have no chemical background, so go on hell<br>I am so tird. Thats increadible. Let’s keep type so I do fall into sleep.</p><p>alkane → ahlcohole → aldchyl → Exrebexyl<br>R-CH₃ → R - CH₂OH → R-CH=O → R-C=C=H</p><hr><h3 id="Substrate-Specificity">Substrate Specificity</h3><ol><li>Lock Key model:<ul><li>Hexokinase: 6C sugure, glucose, very specifics.</li><li>Founder: Fisher (Projection)</li><li>Enzyme distinguish different sugar model</li></ul></li><li>Something like Ahlcohole Dehydrase methanol, Ethanol<ul><li>Methanol → Carboxyl acid (toxity)</li><li>Drinking Ethanol to inhibitor Methanol metabolism</li></ul></li></ol><h3 id="Example-of-“high”-specificity-stereospecificity">Example of “high” specificity (stereospecificity)</h3><p>Citrate ←(Aconitase)→ Isocitrate</p><p>Enzyme is so large to interacte with the complex.</p><p>If you rotated the molecue,</p><h3 id="Example-of-“low”-specificity-geometric">Example of “low” specificity (geometric)</h3><p>Chymotrypsin:</p><ul><li>Peptide: <code>RCO::NHR' + H₂O → RCOO¯ + H₃N⁺R'</code></li><li>Ester: <code>RCO::OR' + H₂O → RCOO¯ + HOR' + H¯</code></li></ul><p>Trypsin; Elastase</p><h3 id="Example-of-enzyme-that-uses-a-coenzyme-cosubstrate">Example of enzyme that uses a coenzyme/cosubstrate</h3><p>Ethano ←(ADH)→ Acetaldehyde</p><p>Adenosine: Oxidized Form ←→ Reduced Form</p><p>NAD⁺ \ NADP⁺<br>V<sub>B</sub>, whichi needs by Mitochondria: nicotinamide riboside</p><p>As aging, the V<sub>B</sub> gets low, supply in precouser to aging mouse, mitochondria could,<br>In humane: hearing lost in loud noise rescue.</p><h3 id="Acid-base-Catatlysis">Acid-base Catatlysis</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:right">Keto →</th><th style="text-align:center">Transition state</th><th style="text-align:left">→ Enol</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:right"></td><td style="text-align:center">Form 1</td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:right"></td><td style="text-align:center">Form 2 + Acide</td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:right"></td><td style="text-align:center">Form 3 + Base</td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Different forms has difference entropy.</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://cdn.britannica.com/32/16232-004-90FEF74C/Equation.jpg" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.britannica.com/science/acid-base-reaction/Acid-base-catalysis">© Britannica</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Covalent-Catatlysis">Covalent Catatlysis</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="http://faculty.smu.edu/svik/5310/5310lectures/covalent.gif" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="http://faculty.smu.edu/svik/5310/5310lectures/lect14.html">© smu.edu</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Metal-Ion-Catalysis">Metal Ion Catalysis</h3><p>Zn Coordinate with His to do complex things.</p><h3 id="Catalysis-by-Proximity-and-Orientation">Catalysis by Proximity and Orientation</h3><h3 id="Catalytic-triad-of-chymotrypsin-and-other-serine-proteases">Catalytic triad of chymotrypsin and other serine proteases</h3><h3 id="Serine-protease-mechanism-Exam">Serine protease mechanism (Exam)</h3><p>Imtermider: not transition state, it is physical, detactable, and exist.S</p><h3 id=""></h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubs.acs.org/na101/home/literatum/publisher/achs/journals/content/jacsat/2004/jacsat.2004.126.issue-44/ja047010a/production/images/medium/ja047010an00001.gif" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/ja047010a">© Maya Topf and W. Graham Richards</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>🐶 🐔</p><p>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cell-programmed nutrient partitioning in the tumour microenvironment.</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/07/Paper/paper-cancer-mi/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/07/Paper/paper-cancer-mi/</id>
    <published>2021-10-07T18:32:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T15:27:35.158Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Cell-programmed-nutrient-partitioning-in-the-tumour-microenvironment">Cell-programmed nutrient partitioning in the tumour microenvironment.</h2><p>Cite: Reinfeld, Bradley I., et al. “Cell-programmed nutrient partitioning in the tumour microenvironment.” Nature 593.7858 (2021): 282-288.</p><h2 id="Abstract">Abstract</h2><p><abbr title="positron emission tomography">PET</abbr> could use for toumor image.</p><p>Cacncer Cell Marker: Glucose intacke; Lactate generated (Warburg metabolism)<br>So as the umour-infltrating immune cells.<br>As a result, the immune cell was restricted and evaluated.</p><p>Thesis: <mark>immune cells dysregulated: <strong>cell-intrinsic programs</strong> or by <strong>competition</strong>?</mark></p><p>Our Solution:</p><ul><li><abbr title="positron emission tomography">PET</abbr>:  tracers to measure the access to and uptake of glucose and glutamine</li></ul><p>Result:</p><ul><li>Intratumoral glucose:<ul><li>myeloid cells &gt; T cells &gt; Cancer cells</li></ul></li><li>cancer cells<ul><li>Cancer Cell &gt;  all other cells</li></ul></li></ul><p>Hypothesis:</p><ul><li>Metabolism in Result was:<ul><li>Programmed in cell-intrinsic manner through <abbr title="Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1)">mTORC1</abbr> and related genes.</li></ul></li></ul><p>Variation:</p><ul><li>tumour-resident cell: glutamine↓ → glucose↑</li><li>glutamine metabolism → glucose uptake↑</li></ul><p>Conclusion: cell-intrinsic programs drive the preferential acquisition of glucose and glutamine by immune and cancer cells, respectively.</p><p>Cell-selective partitioning of these nutrients could be exploited to develop therapies and imaging strategies to enhance or monitor the metabolic programs and activities of specifc cell populations in the <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr>.</p><h2 id="Intro">Intro</h2><p>Cancer cell; Rapidly proliferating cell, and activated immune cells: convert glucose to lactate very quickly.</p><p><abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> <abbr title="positron emission tomography">PET</abbr> imaging to detect cancer</p><h2 id="Resutl">Resutl</h2><p><img src="https://media.springernature.com/lw685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-021-03442-1/MediaObjects/41586_2021_3442_Fig1_HTML.png?as=webp" alt="Fig 1"></p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Figures</th><th style="text-align:left">Illustration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">A, B</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>human renal cell carcinoma (<abbr title="human renal cell carcinoma">RCC</abbr>) and mouse subcutaneous MC38 tumours <li>the mass spectrometry resutl</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">C, D</td><td style="text-align:left"><li><abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> <abbr title="positron emission tomography">PET</abbr> on mouse</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">E</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>CD45⁺: Immune Cells <li> CD45¯ in Tumour Cells</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">F</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>High <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> signle in Tumor cells. <li> <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> in immune cell: CD45⁺ &gt; CD45¯</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">G, H</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> CD45⁺ immune cells have <mark>No spatial distribution favouring</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">I, J</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Same result shows in  in mouse subcutaneous CT26 and renal carcinoma (Renca) tumours</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">K</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>  orthotopic Renca tumours: FDG↑ in immune cells as compared to CD45¯ tumour cells</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">I</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>  mouse model (GEMM) of breast cance has similar result</td></tr></tbody></table><p><img src="https://media.springernature.com/lw685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-021-03442-1/MediaObjects/41586_2021_3442_Fig2_HTML.png?as=webp" alt="Fig 2"></p><p>Myeloid cells take up the most glucose</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Figures</th><th style="text-align:left">Illustration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">A, B</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr>: <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr> T cells &gt; splenic T cells;  <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr> T cells ≈ cancer cell <li> suggesting that these cells are not deprived of glucose</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">C, D</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> myeloid cells (non-T cell CD45⁺ cells; CD11B⁺ selection) were isolated <li> <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr>: CD11B⁺ myeloid cells &gt; immune cells in MC38 tumors &gt; cancer cells</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">E</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Two domain, LY6G−LY6Chi cells, from CD45⁺ CD11B⁺ MC38 tumour</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">F</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>  Isolated F4/80<sup>hi</sup> cells had a histiocytic morpholog</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">G, H</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> high <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> avidity: <abbr title="monocytic myeloid-derived suppressor cells">M-MDSCs</abbr> by microbeads(GR1⁺) <abbr title="tumour-associated macrophages">TAMs</abbr> by microbeads(F4/80⁺)</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">I-K</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> extracellular flux assays; <abbr title="extracellular acidification rate">ECAR</abbr>; <abbr title="oxygen consumption rate">OCR</abbr> <li>  <abbr title="tumour-associated macrophages">TAMs</abbr> and <abbr title="monocytic myeloid-derived suppressor cells">M-MDSCs</abbr> consume the most glucose per</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">cell in the <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr> and maintain robust glucose metabolism.</td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr></tbody></table><p><img src="https://media.springernature.com/lw685/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1038%2Fs41586-021-03442-1/MediaObjects/41586_2021_3442_Fig3_HTML.png?as=webp" alt="Fig 3"></p><p><abbr title="Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1)">mTORC1</abbr> programs metabolism in the <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr></p><p><abbr title="Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1)">mTORC1</abbr>: supports <abbr title="合成代谢">anabolic</abbr> metabolism and nutrient uptake<br><abbr title="phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6">pS6</abbr>: monitor the <abbr title="Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1)">mTORC1</abbr> pathway activity in tumour myeloid cells</p><p>CD11B+ myeloid cells</p><p>Cell type:</p><ul><li><p>Other CD45⁺ Cell: T cell CD45+ c :: To characterize the non-T cell CD45⁺ cells, myeloid  CD11B⁺ (microbeads).</p></li><li><p>CD3⁺: CD3⁺ T cells</p></li><li><p>CD4⁺: CD4⁺ T cells)</p></li><li><p>CD8⁺: CD8⁺ T cells</p></li><li><p>CD11B⁺/CD45⁺: Myeloid:</p></li><li><p>CD14; CA9</p></li></ul><p>The hypothesis is <abbr title="Mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1)">mTORC1</abbr> which supports <abbr title="合成代谢">anabolic</abbr> metabolism and nutrient uptake. <abbr title="phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6">pS6</abbr> is a protein which under the upstream of the mTOR signal pathway. <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr> can suppress the <abbr title="phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6">pS6</abbr> without affect the tumor’s weight, concentrations of glucose, glutamine; lactate in the <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr>; but led to significant decreases in <abbr title="phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6">pS6</abbr> levels, T cell infiltration, Ki67 levels in cancer cells and T cells, and the cell size of <abbr title="tumour-associated macrophages">TAMs</abbr> (Fig. 3d). Treatment with rapamycin also resulted in significant decreases in <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> uptake in myeloid and cancer cells.<br>f, g, h show that Rapa led to a in myeloid cell metabolism ex vivo, whereas cancer cells and T cells remained unchanged</p><p>decrease in myeloid cell metabolism<br>ex vivo, whereas cancer cells and T cells remained unchanged</p><p>Hk1 was broadly expresse, Hk2, the hexokinase isoforms 2, rate-limiting step of glycolysis was highly expressed in myeloid cells.</p><p>iron transporter CD71 and the amino acid transporter CD98</p><p>This has implications for metabolism-directed agents as<br>well as therapies that target myeloid cells, with the potential to either enhance or impair tumour-related inflammation. <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr>-resident cells have the capacity to increase glucose uptake like upreguate the mTOR singal pathway.</p><p>Veh? :  spleen vehicle;  rapamycin- and the vehicle-treated samples;   8 mice for CD4+/CD8+ vehicle; glutamine plasma and TIF vehicle(5% Tween‐80, 5% PEG‐40??),</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Figures</th><th style="text-align:left">Illustration</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">A</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> <abbr title="fluorescence minus one; a control which determine where your gates should be set.">FMO</abbr>, <abbr title="peripheral blood mononuclear cells">PBMC</abbr>, and <abbr title="clear cell renal cell carcinoma">ccRCC</abbr>  <li> Ridgelines <li> Different <abbr title="phosphorylated ribosomal protein S6">pS6</abbr> PE expression level in different group of cells.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">B</td><td style="text-align:left"><li></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">C</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> mouse MC38 tumours</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">D</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> mice bearing MC38 tumours: rapamycin (4 days) → measured <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> uptake <li> <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr> did not affect: weight; concentrations of glucose, glutamine; lactate in the <abbr title="tumour microenvironment">TME</abbr> <li> <mark>but</mark> pS6↓ significant, T cell infiltration↓, Ki67 levels↓ in cancer cells and T cells, and the cell size↓ of <abbr title="tumour-associated macrophages">TAMs</abbr></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">E</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>  MC38 tumour; <li> <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr>:  myeloid and cancer cells’s <abbr title="F-fluorodeoxyglucose">FDG</abbr> uptake↓ (significant)</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">F - H</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> MC38 tumours <li>  <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr>: myeloid cell metabolism　ex vivo<mark>↓</mark>　<li>  cancer cells and T cells remained unchanged</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">I</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Untreated tumours: CPA and unbiased clustering based only on (metabolism-related transcripts) grouped samples by cell identity (RNA-Seq)</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">J, K</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr>: (flow cytometry) HK1<mark>↓</mark> across tumour cell populations <li> HK2<mark>↓</mark> specifically in <abbr title="tumour-associated macrophages">TAMs</abbr> <li> potentially underlying the differences between tumour cell types in glucose uptake</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">L, M</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> <abbr title="雷帕霉素">Rapamycin</abbr>: GLUT1: unchanged; <li> protein levels of the iron transporter CD71 and the amino acid transporter CD98 <mark>↓</mark></td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Cell-programmed nutrient partitioning in the tumour microenvironment.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Paper" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Paper/"/>
    
    <category term="Diseases" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Paper/Diseases/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Paper" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Paper/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Enzymatic Catalysis, Catalytic Mechanisms 9| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/05/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-9/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/05/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-9/</id>
    <published>2021-10-05T14:29:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:53.880Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Enzymatic-Catalysis-Catalytic-Mechanisms">Enzymatic Catalysis, Catalytic Mechanisms</h2><ol><li>General Properties of Enzymes</li><li>Activation Energy and the Reaction<br>Coordinate</li><li>Catalytic Mechanisms</li><li>Serine Proteases (pp. 342-347)</li></ol><h2 id="Learning-Goals">Learning Goals</h2><ul><li>Give examples of various levels of substrate specificity, and explain specificity differences exhibited by serine proteases</li><li>Give examples of reactions that utilize coenzymes NAD, FAD, Coenzyme A, and lipoic acid (metabolism lectures), and specify the role of the coenzyme</li><li>Describe catalysis in terms of a reaction-coordinate energy diagram</li><li>Classify enzymes by type of reaction</li><li>Explain catalysis by enzymes in terms of chemical mechanisms</li><li>Elaborate the catalytic mechanism of a chymotrypsin</li><li>Explain divergent and convergent evolution</li><li>Discuss the similarity of primary structure vs. tertiary structure in proteins as evidence supporting the existence of homology</li></ul><h2 id="Enzymes-differ-from-chemical-catalysts">Enzymes differ from chemical catalysts</h2><ul><li>Higher reaction rates</li><li>Milder reaction conditions</li><li>Greater reaction specificity</li><li>Capacity for regulation</li></ul><h3 id="How-Do-Enzymes-Work">How Do Enzymes Work?</h3><ul><li>Enzymes accelerate reaction rates through the formation of weak bonds (hydrogen bonds, hydrophobic bonds, ionic bonds, van der Waals interactions) between the enzyme and the substrate.</li><li>Enzymes use the energy from the formation of these weak bonds help arrange the substrate in a position favorable for a chemical reaction. Catalysis by Transition- state Stabilization Rate 315 times faster when R=CH3 than when R=H</li></ul><h3 id="Specific">Specific</h3><p>Geomitric complementarity and electronic complementarity contribute the specific of the enzyme.</p><ul><li>Stereospecific: target into one kind of chiral only.</li><li>Geometric Specificity: identities of the chemical groups on their substrates.</li></ul><h3 id="Transition-State-Analogues">Transition State Analogues</h3><ul><li>The transition state is a “fleeting molecular moment” where events such as bond breakage, bond formation, and charge development have proceeded to a point at which decay to either substrate or product is equally likely.</li><li>Stable molecules designed to resemble this transition state are called transition state analogues. They often bind to enzymes more tightly than either the substrate or the product. This principal has been used to increase the effectiveness of pharmaceuticals.</li><li>Most of the HIV protease inhibitors used to treat AIDS are transition state analogues.</li></ul><h3 id="Transition-state-Analogs">Transition-state Analogs</h3><h3 id="The-properties-of-enzymes-control-the-fate-of-most-cellular-metabolites">The properties of enzymes control the fate of most cellular metabolites</h3><p>The ~ 500 reactions that comprise human metabolism are all catalyzed by enzymes.<br>Lehninger, Figure 15-1</p><h3 id="Enzymes-can-be-classified-according-to-the-reactions-they-catalyze">Enzymes can be classified according to the reactions they catalyze</h3><h3 id="Oxidation-states-of-biological-carbon-molecules">Oxidation states of biological carbon molecules</h3><h3 id="Oxidation-states-of-biological-carbon-molecules-v2">Oxidation states of biological carbon molecules</h3><h3 id="Oxidation-states-of-biological-sulfur">Oxidation states of biological sulfur</h3><h3 id="Biological-oxidation-reduction-reactions-utilize-mobile-or-protein-bound-electron">Biological oxidation-reduction reactions utilize mobile or protein-bound electron</h3><p>carriers Oxidized Forms<br>NAD+<br>NADP+<br>FAD<br>FMN<br>Reduced Forms<br>NADH<br>NADPH<br>FADH2<br>FMNH2<br>NAD+ Nicotinamide Adenine Dinucleotide<br>NADP+ Nicotinamide Adenine Dinucleotide<br>Phosphate<br>FAD Flavin Adenine Dinucleotide<br>FMN Flavin Mononucleotide</p><p>Electrons on NADH and FADH2 are used primarily to generate ATP via electron transport and oxidative phosphorylation. Electrons on NADPH are used to provide reducing equivalents during synthetic reactions.</p><ol><li>Oxidoreductases<br>catalyze redox reactions Lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) is a glycolytic enzyme present in a number of different tissues. LDH isozymes (enzymes with different structures that catalyze the same reaction) are sometimes measured in serum as an indicator of cell damage.</li><li>Transferases catalyze the transfer of a functional group from one molecule to another<br>Hexokinase is an transferase that transfer a phosphate from ATP to a hexoses (six-carbon sugars), forming hexose-6-phosphate. In most organisms, glucose is the most important substrate and of hexokinases, and glucose-6-phosphate is the most important product.</li><li>Hydrolyases catalyze the transfer of a donor group to water. Water is added and 2 molecules are formed from 1.<br>Glucose 6-phosphatase is a hydrolase in the gluconeogenic pathway that removes a phosphate group from the C-6 hydroxyl group of glucose to form glucose and inorganic phosphate.</li><li>Lyases add or remove elements of carbon dioxide, ammonia or water (without making two molecules from one).<br>Fumerase is an lyase enzyme in the Tricarboxylic Acid Cycle. Note that water is added, but this enzyme does not make 2 molecules from one.</li><li>Isomerases are enzymes that catalyze intramolecular rearrangements. All the atoms in the substrate are also present in the product, just in a different configuration.<br>Phosphoglucomutase is an isomerase that interconverts glucose 6-phosphate and glucose 1- phosphate. This enzyme is required for the synthesis of glycogen and complex carbohydrates.</li><li>Ligases catalyze synthetic reactions where 2 molecules are joined at the expense of a “high energy phosphate bond” , usually ATP or GTP. No part of the ATP or GTP ends up in the product.<br>Pyruvate carboxylase is a ligase important in the gluconeogenesis. It is also used to replenish intermediates in the Tricarboxylic Acid Cycle</li></ol><h3 id="Substrate-Specificity">Substrate Specificity</h3><ul><li>Lock-and-key model refers to complementarity between enzymes and substrates</li><li>Induced fit refers to conformational change upon substrate binding – accommodation of multiple substrates</li></ul><h2 id="Example-of-“high”-specificity-stereospecificity">Example of “high” specificity (stereospecificity)</h2><p>3-point- attachment results in stereospecific product</p><h3 id="Example-of-“low”-specificity-geometric">Example of “low” specificity (geometric)</h3><h3 id="Example-of-enzyme-that-uses-a-coenzyme-cosubstrate">Example of enzyme that uses a coenzyme/cosubstrate</h3><h3 id="MECHANISMS-OF-CATALYSIS">MECHANISMS OF CATALYSIS</h3><ul><li>Acid-base Catalysis</li><li>Covalent Catalysis</li><li>Metal Ion Catalysis</li><li>Catalysis by Transition- state Stabilization<br>Rate 315 times faster when<br>R=CH3 than when R=H</li><li>Catalysis by Proximity and Orientation</li><li>Catalytic triad of chymotrypsin and other serine proteases<br>ES complex</li><li>Serine protease mechanism<br>ES complex Tetrahedral intermediate</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Compose keys in Manjaro</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/02/Blog/compouse-keys/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/02/Blog/compouse-keys/</id>
    <published>2021-10-02T21:57:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-08T14:35:59.599Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Show-all-keys">Show all keys</h2><p>Show all able compose keys with command.</p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="BASH"><figure class="iseeu highlight /bash"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">cat <span class="hljs-string">&quot;/usr/share/X11/locale/<span class="hljs-subst">$(grep --max-count=1 <span class="hljs-string">&quot;<span class="hljs-variable">$&#123;LANG%.*&#125;</span>.UTF-8\$&quot;</span> /usr/share/X11/locale/locale.dir | cut --delimiter=/ --fields 1)</span>/Compose&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><p>⫰</p><h2 id="Math">Math</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">keys</th><th style="text-align:left">Result</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">o o</td><td style="text-align:left">°</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">o A</td><td style="text-align:left">Å</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">&gt; =</td><td style="text-align:left">≥</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">&lt; =</td><td style="text-align:left">≤</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">x x</td><td style="text-align:left">×</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">&gt; &gt;</td><td style="text-align:left">»</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">&lt; &lt;</td><td style="text-align:left">«»</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Direction">Direction</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">keys</th><th style="text-align:left">Result</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">&lt; -</td><td style="text-align:left">←</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">| ^</td><td style="text-align:left">↑</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">| v</td><td style="text-align:left">↓</td></tr></tbody></table><h1>Others</h1><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">keys</th><th style="text-align:left">Result</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">o c</td><td style="text-align:left">©</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">o r</td><td style="text-align:left">®</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">= Y</td><td style="text-align:left">¥</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">= E</td><td style="text-align:left">€</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Meme">Meme</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">keys</th><th style="text-align:left">Result</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">&lt; 3</td><td style="text-align:left">♥</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Frequent used Compose Key</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Linux" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Linux/"/>
    
    <category term="others" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Linux/others/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Blog" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Blog/"/>
    
    <category term="Manjaro" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Manjaro/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Carbohydrate Biochemistry 8| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/01/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-8/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/10/01/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-8/</id>
    <published>2021-10-01T13:22:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-02T14:17:27.003Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Carbohydrate-Biochemistry">Carbohydrate Biochemistry</h2><blockquote><ul><li>Glycated hemoglobin (HbA1C)</li><li>Lactose intolerance</li><li>Glycoprotein synthesis</li><li>INfluenza virus Infection</li><li>Heparin &amp; heparan sulfate</li><li>Peptidoglycans of bacterial wall</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Glycate-hemoglobin-HbA1C">Glycate hemoglobin (HbA1C)</h2><blockquote><p>HbA1c is a consequence of high blood sugar (Glc) caused by diabetes</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Normal Haemoglobin Fractions<br>Haemoglobin HbA (a2/b2): 95-98%<br>HbA2 (a2/d2): 1.5-3.5%<br>HbF (a2/g2): &lt;2%<br>Several minor hemoglobins migrate more rapidly than<br>HbA in an electric field called HbA1.<br>HbA1 is made up of HbA1a + HbA1b + HbA1C.</p></blockquote><h3 id="What-is-HbA1C">What is HbA1C</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left"></th><th style="text-align:left">Suger</th><th style="text-align:left">Terminal</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">HbA1a1</td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>fructose-1,6 diphosphate</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">β - N-terminal</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">HbA1a2</td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>glucose-6-phosphate</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">β - N-terminal</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">HbA1b</td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>pyruvic acid</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">α- amino terminus</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">HbA1C</td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>glucose attached</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">β - N-terminal</td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>• HbA1C makes up &gt;90% of HbA1.<br>• Normally less than 6% of Hb is HbA1C</p></blockquote><h3 id="How-is-HbAiC-is-formed">How is HbAiC is formed</h3><p>2 Glc residues -&gt; Pre-HbA1C -&gt; HbA1C</p><p>Note: Glucose is attache … to produce HbA1C molecules.</p><h3 id="How-can-we-detect-Hb-subspecies">How can we detect Hb subspecies?</h3><p>cation-exchange chromatography</p><h3 id="Why-is-A1C-clinically-important">Why is A1C clinically important?</h3><ul><li>Disease marker for Diabetes</li></ul><h2 id="Lactose-Intolerance">Lactose Intolerance</h2><ul><li><p>Lactose intolerance</p><ul><li>Inability to digest lactose.</li></ul></li><li><p>Lactose</p><ul><li>Milk sugar, galactose - Glc</li></ul></li><li><p>Galactose (Gal)</p><ul><li><mark>C-4-epimer of Glc</mark></li></ul></li><li><p>chemically link in Lactose</p><ul><li>β-1,4-galactosidic linkage</li></ul></li><li><p>Cause of the lactose intolerance</p><ul><li>Lack/deficiency of lactase(β-galactosidase)</li></ul></li><li><p>Biosynthesis</p><ul><li><mark>α-lactalbumin</mark></li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Glycoproteins">Glycoproteins</h2><blockquote><p>Biosynthesis of O-glycans does not require dolichol phosphate.<br>Biosynthesis of N-glycans requires dolichol phosphate.</p></blockquote><h3 id="Synthesis">Synthesis</h3><ul><li>Sialic aicd</li><li>Hemagglutinin</li><li>Neuraminidase</li></ul><h3 id="Three-Major-Type">Three Major Type</h3><ul><li>A: mammal and birds</li><li>B &amp; C: Human and not categorized into subtypes</li></ul><h3 id="Influenza-Virus-Infection">Influenza Virus Infection</h3><h3 id="Type-of-Influenza-viruses">Type of Influenza viruses</h3><h3 id="Treatment-of-Influenza-Virus-Infection">Treatment of Influenza Virus Infection</h3><h3 id="Tamiflu-and-Relenza">Tamiflu and Relenza</h3><h3 id="Heparin-and-heparan-sulfate">Heparin and heparan sulfate</h3><h3 id="Fondaparinux">Fondaparinux</h3>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>6 Protein Folding and Degradation|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/30/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-6/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/30/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-6/</id>
    <published>2021-09-30T14:30:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:40.201Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Protein-Folding-and-Degradation">Protein Folding and Degradation</h2><blockquote><p>• Lodish MCB, 8th ed., pages 81-105 and 622-631.<br>• 3.2 Protein Folding<br>• 3.3 Protein Binding and Enzyme Catalysis<br>• 3.4 Regulating Protein Function<br>• 13.6 Transport Into and Out of the Nucleus</p></blockquote><h2 id="Protein-Folding">Protein Folding</h2><p>Principles of protein folding:</p><ul><li>AA Seq. → 3D Structure and Function.</li><li>Assisted by: ATP-dependent chaperones and chaperonins</li><li>Misfolded/denatured proteins → Diseasecan<ul><li>Exp: amyloid fibril: Alzheimer &amp; Parkinson.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Factors-that-Affect-Protein-Folding-Structure">Factors that Affect Protein Folding/Structure</h3><p>Hypothetical protein folding pathway:</p><ul><li>Primary → Secondary → Tertiary</li><li>Native conformation: lowest free energy</li></ul><p>Forces that govern folding</p><blockquote><ul><li>Hydrophobic interaction (favors)</li><li>Conformational entropy (disfavors)</li><li>Steric hindrance limits dihedral angles off central α-carbon</li><li>van der Waals contacts (packing)</li><li>Hydrogen bonds</li><li>Electrostatic interactions</li></ul></blockquote><p>PS:</p><ul><li>Planar peptide bonds<ul><li>φ and ψ: steric clash</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="PS-How-AA-Seq-determing-the-high-dimensions-information">PS: How AA Seq determing the high dimensions information</h3><p>For example, :</p><ul><li>Steric effect: a large side chain, such as that of (<strong>W</strong>), might sterically block one region of the chain from packing closely against another region</li><li>Charge effect: a side chain with a positive charge (<strong>A</strong>) , might attract a segment of the polypeptide that has a complementary negatively charged side chain (e.g., <strong>D</strong>).</li><li>Secondary structure: Example we have already discussed is the effect of the aliphatic side chains in heptad repeats in promoting the association of helices and the consequent formation of coiled coils. Thus a polypeptide’s primary structure determines its secondary, tertiary, and quaternary structures.</li></ul><h3 id="Steric-hindrance-and-secondary-structure">Steric hindrance and secondary structure</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Values of dihedral angles φ and ψ are excluded by contact between bulky groups - steric hindrance (clash)</li><li>“Allowed” regions of Ramachandran Plot correspond to major secondary structures</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Molecular-Chaperone-Families">Molecular Chaperone Families</h2><blockquote><p>• stabilize unfolded or partly <strong>folded</strong> proteins and prevent <strong>aggregation</strong> during synthesis, membrane translocation, assembly, and degradation.<br>• Molecular chaperones bind exposed segments and surfaces of unfolded proteins.<br>• Hsp60-Hsp10 family chaperones (<abbr title="Mitochondria">Mito</abbr> and <abbr title="Chloroplast">chlp</abbr>) manage folding of enzymes and proteotoxic stress<br>• Hsp70-Hsp40 family chaperones (in <abbr title="cytoplasmic">cyto</abbr>, ER, <abbr title="nuclear">nuc</abbr>,<abbr title="Mitochondria">mito</abbr>, <abbr title="Chloroplast">chlp</abbr>) manage protein translocation across membranes and proteotoxic stress<br>• Hsp90 family chaperones (<abbr title="cytoplasmic">cyto</abbr>, <abbr title="nuclear">nuc</abbr>, ER, <abbr title="Mitochondria">mito</abbr>, <abbr title="Chloroplast">chlp</abbr>) regulate signaling and gene expression and manage proteotoxic stress<br>• Hsp100 (AAA+) family chaperones (<abbr title="cytoplasmic">cyto</abbr>, <abbr title="Mitochondria">mito</abbr>, <abbr title="Chloroplast">chlp</abbr>) unfold proteins for degradation and manage proteotoxic stress<br>• Hsp25 family chaperones (in <abbr title="cytoplasmic">cyto</abbr>) manage actin assembly and proteotoxic stress - do not utilize ATP</p></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Molecular Chaperones</th><th style="text-align:left">Chaperonins</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Small protein which <mark>bind</mark> to a short segment of a target and stabilize unfold or part folded protein.</td><td style="text-align:left">Large protein which form a <mark>folding chamber</mark> into which all or part of unfolded protein, give it time and an appropriate environment to fold properly.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><li>Hsp70; <li>Hsp40; <li>Hsp90;</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Hsp60; <li> Hsp10</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Functions:</p><ul><li>Preventing aggregation</li><li>Fold newly made proteins</li><li>disassmble ptentially toxic protein aggregates duet to …</li></ul><h3 id="Chaperones-Hsp60-Hsp10-ATP-cycle">Chaperones: Hsp60-Hsp10 ATP cycle</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0968000498011931-gr1.gif" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0968000498011931">© Alexandra Richardsona, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Video:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--NcNeLc1mo">3D Animation; 2014 Youtube</a></li><li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VjJ2XL__788">Ibiology; 2014 Youtube</a></li></ul><p>Hsp60: Huge cylindrical supramolecular assemblies</p><p>Two groups:</p><ul><li>Group I: The Prokaryotic Group<ul><li>GroEL/GroES</li></ul></li><li>Group II: The Eukaryotic Group<ul><li>TriC</li></ul></li></ul><ol><li>ATP + GroEL → ADP:<ul><li>unfolded protein in</li><li>lid of GroES sealed</li></ul></li><li>ATP → ADP → protein fold</li><li>ATP → ADP → GroES and peptide release</li><li>Pepetide enter another chamber → Release/Repeats</li></ol><h3 id="Chaperonins-Hsp70-Hsp40-ATP-cycle">Chaperonins: Hsp70-Hsp40 ATP-cycle</h3><blockquote><ol><li>Hsp40-bound “client” protein binds to Hsp70</li><li>Hsp40 J-domain triggers ATP hydrolysis, Hsp70 closes, Hsp40 released</li><li>Waiting/folding</li><li>ADP/ATP exchange triggers opening of Hsp70</li><li>Release of client protein</li></ol></blockquote><h4 id="Hsp70">Hsp70</h4><p>Monomeric</p><p>Families of heat-shock protein Hsp70 homologs:</p><ol><li>Hsp70 in <abbr title="Mitochondria">Mito</abbr>; 2. Bip in ER, 3. DnaK in</li></ol><p>Heat-shock: large expressed after heat-shock in bacteria.</p><ol><li>+ATP → Open conformation → Expose Hydrophobic Region  → Bond client.</li><li>ATP → ADP → Close conformation → helping folding</li><li>ADP Release → conformation change → Target release</li><li>ATP bond → binds another target</li><li>Check:<ul><li>appropriate folded → Cannot bind again</li><li>inappropriate folded → bind again</li></ul></li></ol><h4 id="Hsp40">Hsp40</h4><p>Four main families of <strong>nucleotide exchange factors</strong>:</p><ul><li>GrpE: bacteria</li><li>BAG; HspBP; Hsp110</li></ul><p>Hsp40 (co-chaperone) facilitate Hsp70 processes.</p><ul><li>Increasing the ATP hydrolysis. ×100 ~ ×1000</li><li></li></ul><h3 id="Hsp90-ATP-cycle">Hsp90 ATP cycle</h3><blockquote><ol><li>Hs70-bound “client” protein binds to Hsp90</li><li>ATP binding triggers closing of Hsp90</li><li>Waiting/folding</li><li>ADP hydrolysis and release</li><li>Release of client protein Hsp70-bound Hsp70</li></ol></blockquote><p>Dimer protein</p><p>Usually recognizing <strong>partially folded protein</strong>, highly conserved among species.</p><p>Four families: two in cytosol, one in <abbr title="Mitochondria">Mito</abbr>, and one in ER.<br><strong>Important</strong>: Helping miss folded protein under the stress, convert them into <strong>active</strong> form or held in a <strong>functional conformation</strong>.</p><ol><li>open conformation → Bind target</li><li>+ATP → Closed conformation</li><li>ATP → ADP → target release</li></ol><p>Else:</p><ul><li>Cooperate with Hsp70</li><li>Influenced by covalent modification</li><li>Facilitate identification and degradation</li></ul><h3 id="AAA-Protein-Family">AAA+ Protein Family</h3><blockquote><p>Aggregate disassembly</p><ul><li>Hsp100 of yeast</li><li>ClpB of E. coli</li></ul><p>Vesicular transport complex disassembly</p><ul><li>NEM-sensitive factor for SNARE disassembly</li><li><mark>Vps4</mark> for ESCRT disassembly</li></ul><p>DNA-binding protein assembly</p><ul><li>Clamp loader<br>Export of mRNA from nucleus</li><li><mark>Dbp5</mark><br>Protein translocation across membranes</li><li>p97 for ER-associated degradation (ERAD)<br>Protein degradation</li><li>ClpA, ClpX of E. coli</li><li>“Cap” of 26S proteasome (6 in 19S cap)<br>Molecular motor</li><li>Dynein for organellar transport along microtubules</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p>(ATPases associated with various cellular activities, homologous to hexameric nucleic-acid helicases)</p></blockquote><h2 id="3-4-Regulating-Protein-Function">3.4 Regulating Protein Function</h2><ol><li>At the level of <strong>synthesis</strong>, <strong>degradation</strong>, or through noncovalent or covalent <strong>interactions</strong>.</li><li>Proteins marked for <strong>destruction</strong> with a polyubiquitin tag by ubiquitin ligases are degraded in <strong>proteasomes</strong>.</li><li><strong>Allosteric mechanisms</strong> act as switches, reversibly turning protein activity on and off.</li><li>Higher-order regulation includes the intracellular <strong>compartmentation</strong> of proteins.</li><li>Proline cis/trans <strong>isomerizations</strong>.</li><li><strong>Alters structure</strong> of a protein SH2 domain.</li><li><strong>Can influence protein activity</strong>.???</li><li>Proline <strong>isomerase</strong> may act as switch to regulate protein activity.</li></ol><p>From Textbook:</p><ol><li>ALtering the rate of protein synthesis and degradation</li><li>Change the intrinsic activity, Exp: active or in active conformation</li><li>Change the location and the concentration within the cell.</li></ol><h2 id="Ubiquitin-and-Proteasome-Mediated-Proteolysis">Ubiquitin- and Proteasome-Mediated Proteolysis</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5YZdYQ.png" alt="26S Proteasome"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p98</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Proteasome">Proteasome</h3><p>Structures:</p><ol><li><mark>ATPas</mark>: AAA+ family: Red</li><li>Ubiquitin recepor: Yellow</li><li>Deubiquitinase Enzyme: Green</li></ol><h3 id="Ubiquitin-and-Formation">Ubiquitin and Formation</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Ubiquitin’s type</th><th style="text-align:left">Features</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Monoubiquitinylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Single Ubiquitin</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Multyubiquitinylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Multiple, single ubiquitin</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Polyubiquitinylation</td><td style="text-align:left">A polymeric chain of ubiquitin</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Degradation in Proteasome</p><ol><li><mark>Actication</mark>: ATP + ubiquitin (Ub) → activate Enzyme E1<ul><li>E1 - Ub</li></ul></li><li><mark>Ttransfers</mark> Ub → E2 (step 2 )<ul><li>E2 - Ub</li></ul></li><li><mark>Formation</mark>: Ubiquitin ligase (E3) transfer Ub  →  Lysine–NH2 and forming an isopeptide bond<ul><li>UB - Peptide</li></ul></li><li><ul><li>more Ub by repeating steps 1 – 3</li></ul><ul><li>n * (Ub) - Pepide</li></ul></li><li>polyubiquitinylatd targed → Ub receptors (19S cap)<ul><li>went into proteasome</li></ul></li><li>deubiquitinase enzyme (19S cap) → Ub remove</li><li>a. +ATP → unfold → the 20S core (<br>b. coordinately with step 6: protein → short peptide → release (7c)</li></ol><p>Degradation: Proteosome recognition, 1. de-Ub protein, 2. unfolds protein; protein transferred to core proteolysis chamber, protein cleaved into short peptides (2-24 aa) and released for further degradation by soluble proteases.</p><h3 id="Determination-of-polyubiquitin-function-by-the-lysine-used-for-inter-ubiquitin-isopeptide-bonds">Determination of polyubiquitin function by the lysine used for inter-ubiquitin isopeptide bonds</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5YZI61.png" alt="Polyubiquitinylation"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, 104</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Signaling: Lys-63;<br>Proteasomes: Lys-48:Gly-76 isopeptide.<br>T-lymphocyte control: Lys-33<br>Cell division: Lys-11</p><h2 id="Misfolded-Proteins-can-form-Amyloid-Aggregates">Misfolded Proteins can form Amyloid Aggregates</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5YZbTO.png" alt="Misfolded Proteins"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p88</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Amyloid aggregate plaques form inside or outside many cell types.</strong></li><li>Flat sheets form protofilaments, assemble into thicker fibrils, and into larger aggregates or macroscopic plaques.</li><li>Cause neurodegenerative amyloidosis diseases, including Alzheimer’s disease, Parkinson’s disease, and transmissible spongiform encephalopathy (“mad cow” disease).</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Clinical-Case-Alzheimer’s-Disease">Clinical Case: Alzheimer’s Disease</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5YZLkD.png" alt="plaques and fibrillary tangles"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Molecular-Cell-Biology-Harvey-Lodish/dp/1464183392">© Lodish, Molecular Cell Biology, Eight Edition, p88</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>68 yo male seen in ER with apparent confusion, disorientation of where he is or the present date.<br>• Most common form of dementia.<br>• Affects 1 in 10 people over 65 and 50% of people over 85.<br>• Plaques (Aβ peptide) and tangles (tau microtubule-associated protein) results in gradual and progressive loss of neurons and cognitive function over a period of 4-15 years (memory lapse, language impairment, loss of motor functions).</p></blockquote><p><a href="www.nia.nih.gov/Alzheimers/Publications/adfact.htm">Alzheimer’s Disease Fact Sheet; 2021 NCBI</a></p><h2 id="Prion-Diseases-Transmissible-Spongiform-Encephalopathies">Prion Diseases &amp; Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies</h2><blockquote><p>TSE - spongiform neurodegeneration, astrocytic gliosis.<br>Prion - proteinaceous infectious agent, considered heretical concept for transmission.<br>Lehninger Box 4-6</p></blockquote><h3 id="Transmissible-Spongiform-Encephalopathies">Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies</h3><blockquote><ol><li>Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease (<abbr title="familial CJD">CJD</abbr>)</li><li>Gerstmann-Straussler-Scheinker syndrome (<abbr title="Gerstmann-Straussler-Scheinker syndrome">GSS</abbr>)</li><li>Fatal Familial Insomnia (<abbr title="familial fatal insomnia">FFI</abbr>)</li><li><abbr title="Fore tribe in New Guinea">Kuru</abbr>: Fore tribe in New Guinea</li><li>Wild Animals and Livestock (bovine, mink, feline, elk, sheep)</li></ol></blockquote><h3 id="The-Prion-Hypothesis-for-TSEs">The Prion Hypothesis for TSEs</h3><blockquote><p>PrP<sup>Sc</sup> + PrP<sup>c</sup> → 2PrP<sup>Sc</sup></p></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:center">Synfrome</th><th style="text-align:left">Etiology</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">Sporadic</td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="sporadic CJD">sCJD</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Spontaneous conversion of PrPc to PrPsc (usually not mutant)</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Acquired</td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="Fore tribe in New Guinea">Kuru</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Ritualistic endocannabilism</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"></td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="iatrogenic CJD">iCJD</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Exposure to contaminated growth hormone, gonadotrophins, dura mater, cornea or surgical instruments</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"></td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="variant CJD">vCJD</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Ingestion of <abbr title="bovine spongiform encephalopathy">BSE</abbr>-contaminated food products</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Familial</td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="familial CJD">fCJD</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left">Germline mutation in PRNP locus</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"></td><td style="text-align:center"><abbr title="Gerstmann-Straussler-Scheinker syndrome">GSS</abbr>; <abbr title="familial fatal insomnia">FFI</abbr></td><td style="text-align:left"></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>From: Hilton (2006) J Pathol 208: 134, Table 1 Iatrogenic <abbr title="familial CJD">CJD</abbr> 2004</p></blockquote><h2 id="Diseases-involving-Amyloid-Formation-Know-the-normal-and-abnormal-proteins-the-disease-and-specific-mechanisms">Diseases involving Amyloid Formation: Know the normal and abnormal proteins, the disease, and specific mechanisms.</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Disease</th><th style="text-align:left">Type II</th><th style="text-align:left">Alzheimer’s disease</th><th style="text-align:left">Prion disease</th><th style="text-align:left">Huntington’s disease</th><th style="text-align:left">Parkinson’s disease</th><th style="text-align:left">ALS</th><th style="text-align:left">Spinal Cerebellar Ataxia</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Protein</td><td style="text-align:left">Amylin</td><td style="text-align:left">Amyloid Precursor Protein (APP)</td><td style="text-align:left">PrPc</td><td style="text-align:left">Huntingtin protein</td><td style="text-align:left">α-synuclein</td><td style="text-align:left">SOD</td><td style="text-align:left">ataxin</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Function</td><td style="text-align:left">Glycemic regulation with insulin</td><td style="text-align:left">ECM, migration during development</td><td style="text-align:left">Unk.</td><td style="text-align:left">Unclear, MAP, vesicle trafficking</td><td style="text-align:left">Unclear, MAP, vesicle trafficking</td><td style="text-align:left">Destroy oxygen radicals</td><td style="text-align:left">Unclear</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Abnormal protein</td><td style="text-align:left">n/a</td><td style="text-align:left">Aβ42(β-Amyloid)</td><td style="text-align:left">PrPsc</td><td style="text-align:left">mHTT, Trinucleotide repeats (polyQ)</td><td style="text-align:left">Lewy bodies</td><td style="text-align:left">n/a</td><td style="text-align:left">Trinucleotide repeats (polyQ), and nonPolyQ</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Effects</td><td style="text-align:left">Apoptosis of β islet cells</td><td style="text-align:left">Neuronal death</td><td style="text-align:left">Neuronal death</td><td style="text-align:left">Neuro-tramsmitter release, neuronal death</td><td style="text-align:left">Neuro-transmitter release, dopaminergic neuronal death</td><td style="text-align:left">Dementia neuronal atrophy</td><td style="text-align:left">Neuronal deat</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="13-6-Transport-Into-and-Out-of-the-Nucleus">13.6 Transport Into and Out of the Nucleus</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jeroen-Vangindertael/publication/323073291/figure/fig41/AS:614206873284615@1523449738399/A-GP210-proteins-forming-nuclear-pore-complexes-were-labeled-with-Alexa647-and.png" alt=""></th><th style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Roderick-Lim/publication/7370146/figure/fig7/AS:670340590088219@1536833059661/maging-the-nuclear-pore-complex-NPC-by-various-microscopy-techniques-a-Thin-section-of.jpg" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/323073291_An_introduction_to_optical_super-resolution_microscopy_for_the_adventurous_biologist">© Jeroen Vangindertael, et al; 2018</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/7370146_From_the_trap_to_the_basket_Getting_to_the_bottom_of_the_nuclear_pore_complex">© Roderick Lim, et al; 2006</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mario_Tagliazucchi/publication/276836976/figure/fig10/AS:270235693482015@1441440618772/a-Scheme-of-the-nuclear-pore-complex-NPC-a-protein-complex-in-the-nuclear-membrane.png" alt=""></td><td style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Anita-Corbett/publication/8598881/figure/fig2/AS:285611622715392@1445106525506/Structure-of-the-nuclear-pore-complex-A-Schematic-diagram-of-the-nuclear-pore-complex.png" alt=""></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="">© Mario Tagliazucchi, et al; 2015 </a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/8598881_Hot_trends_erupting_in_the_nuclear_transport_field_Workshop_on_Mechanisms_of_Nuclear_Transport">© Anita H Corbett, et al; 2004</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>• Unidirectional transport of a protein larger than 40 kDa through large, complex nuclear pore complexes requires a nuclear-localization or nuclear-export signal, nuclear transport receptors, Ran G-proteins, and localized Ran?GEFs and GAPs.<br>• Other molecules, including mRNPs, are transported by a Ran-independent pathway.</p></blockquote><p>Nucleoporins:</p><ul><li>Structural nucleoporins (circule the memrain)</li><li>Membrane nucleoporins (Y complex)</li><li>FG nucleoporins (matrix on the pour center)</li></ul><p>Transport Into and Out of the Nucleus</p><ul><li><p>The <abbr title="nuclear envelope">Nu Env</abbr>: <abbr title="nuclear pore complexes">NPCs</abbr>, ×30 different nucleoporins.</p><ul><li>FG-nucleoporins: multiple repeats of a short hydrophobic sequence (FG-repeats), line the <mark>central transporter channel</mark> and play a role in the <mark>transporter</mark>.</li></ul></li><li><p>&gt;40 kDa: nuclear transport receptors interact</p></li><li><p><mark>nuclear-localization signal (NLS) or a nuclear-export signal (NES)</mark> on the proteins in/out.</p><ul><li>NLS: Nucleus-restricted proteins</li><li>NLS+NES: proteins that shuttle between the nucleus and cytoplasm</li></ul></li><li><p>Each type of NESs/<abbr title="Nuclear-Localization Signals">NLSs</abbr> is thought to interact with a <mark>specific nuclear transport receptor</mark>.</p></li><li><p>Transient interactions: Protein-[NES/NLS] + receptor.</p><ul><li>Transport receptors + FG-repeats: very rapid diffusion through the <abbr title="nuclear pore complexes">NPC</abbr>,</li></ul></li><li><p>Ran: a monomeric G protein</p><ul><li>Localization of the Ran guanine (<strong><abbr title="Ganine nucleotide exchange factor">Ran-GEF</abbr></strong>) <strong>in the nucleus</strong> and of the Ran GTPase-activating protein (<strong><abbr title="GTPase-activating protein">Ran-GAP</abbr></strong>) <strong>in the cytoplasm</strong> creates a gradient <strong>with high concentrations of Ran⋅GTP in the nucleoplasm and of Ran⋅GDP in the cytoplasm</strong>.</li><li>The interaction of a <strong>cargo complex</strong> with <strong>Ran⋅GTP</strong> in the <strong>nucleoplasm</strong> causes dissociation of the <strong>complex</strong>, releasing the cargo into the <strong>nucleoplasm</strong>, whereas the <strong>assembly of an export cargo complex</strong> is stimulated by interaction with <strong>Ran⋅GTP in the nucleoplasm</strong>.</li></ul></li><li><p>Most <strong>mRNPs</strong> are exported from the <strong>nucleus</strong> by binding to a <strong>heterodimeric <abbr title="Messenger Ribonuclear Protein Complex">mRNP</abbr> exporter</strong>. <strong>RNA helicase</strong> associated with the <strong>cytoplasmic filaments of the <abbr title="nuclear pore complexes">NPC</abbr></strong> that <strong>removes the heterodimeric <abbr title="Messenger Ribonuclear Protein Complex">mRNP</abbr></strong> exporter once the transport complex has reached the cytoplasm.</p></li></ul><h2 id="Nuclear-Localization-Signals-NLSs-Direct-Proteins-to-Cell-Nucleus">Nuclear-Localization Signals (<abbr title="Nuclear-Localization Signals">NLSs</abbr>) Direct Proteins to Cell Nucleus</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/10/17/5YeJ39.png" alt="Pyruvate kinase Experiment"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6096007/">© Kalderon D, et al; 1984</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p><abbr title="Nuclear-Localization Signals">NLSs</abbr> is a 7 residue sequence rich in the terminal of the protein, exp: PLLLRLV</p><ul><li>All nuclear proteins come from cytosol.</li><li>They all have <abbr title="Nuclear-Localization Signals">NLSs</abbr></li><li>Experiment:<ul><li>(a) Pyruvate kinase: in the cytosol for glycolysis.</li><li>(b) Chimeric pyruvate kinase containing SV40 NLS at its N-terminus: transported into the nucleus.</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Nuclear-Import">Nuclear Import</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Terence-Allen-2/publication/12547805/figure/fig1/AS:341225950466050@1458366014093/Nuclear-import-A-schematic-representation-of-nuclear-import-through-the-NPC-The.png" alt="Nuclear Import"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/12547805_The_nuclear_pore_complex_Mediator_of_translocation_between_nucleus_and_cytoplasm">© Terence David Allen, et al. 2000</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Ran &amp; nuclear transporter receptor was purified.</p><p>In Cytosol:</p><ol><li>Importin + NLS-[Cargo].</li><li>Importin-NLS-Cargo passively diffuses.</li></ol><p>In nucleus:</p><ol start="3"><li><abbr title="Ganine nucleotide exchange factor">Ran-GEF</abbr>: Ran-GDP + GTP  → Ran-GTP + GDP</li><li>Importin binds Ran-GTP → Cargo release.</li><li>Importin-Ran-GTP diffuses through <abbr title="nuclear pore complexes">NPC</abbr>.</li></ol><p>Back in cytosol.</p><ol start="6"><li>Ran-GTP reacts with <abbr title="GTPase-activating protein">Ran-GAP</abbr> → part of cytoplasmic filament.</li><li>GTP hydrolysis → low affinity for Importin → releases Importin.</li></ol><p>RanL a small monomeric G protein: GTP/GDP-bound conformation: supply the energy<br><abbr title="Nuclear transport receptor.">NTR</abbr> binds to the <abbr title="Nuclear-Localization Signals">NLSs</abbr>: Recognition</p><h3 id="Monomeric-G-Proteins-The-GTPase-Switch">Monomeric G Proteins: The GTPase Switch</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://biologicmodels.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/710x528_23032935_12778728_1523454624.jpg" alt="GTPase"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://biologicmodels.com/product/h-ras-gtpase-3k8y/">© biologicmodels</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>GTPase:<ul><li>GTP-bound: Active “on” conformation → interacts with target proteins to regulate their activities.</li><li>GDP-bound: inactive “off” conformation → intrinsic GTPase activity → hydrolyzes GTP to GDP.<br>GEF: Guanine nucleotide exchange factor, stimulates exchange of GDP-(off) to GTP-bound (on) forms.<br>GAP: GTPase-activating protein, stimulates GTP (on) hydrolysis to GDP (off).</li></ul></li></ul><p>Examples: Ras, Ran, Rho, ARF</p><h3 id="Ran-Dependent-Export">Ran-Dependent Export</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Terence-Allen-2/publication/12547805/figure/fig2/AS:341225950466051@1458366014114/Nuclear-export-A-schematic-representation-of-nuclear-export-through-the-NPC-The.png" alt="Nuclear Import"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/12547805_The_nuclear_pore_complex_Mediator_of_translocation_between_nucleus_and_cytoplasm">© Terence David Allen, et al. 2000</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>In Nucleus:</p><ol><li>[Ran-GTP]-[Exportin]-[Cargo] → passive diffusion.</li></ol><p>In Cytosol:</p><ol start="2"><li><abbr title="GTPase-activating protein">Ran-GAP</abbr>: [Ran-GTP]-[Exportin]-[Cargo] → Ran-GTP + Cargo + Exportin</li><li>Passively diffuse: Ran-GDP &amp; Exportin → into Nucleus.</li></ol><p>Back in nucleus:<br>4. <abbr title="Ganine nucleotide exchange factor">Ran-GEF</abbr>: Ran-GDP + GTP → Ran-GTP + GDP</p><h3 id="Ran-Independent-mRNA-Nuclear-Export">Ran-Independent mRNA Nuclear Export</h3><p><abbr title="Nuclear Export Factor 1">NXF1</abbr>: Nuclear Export Factor 1<br><abbr title="Nuclear Export Transport 1">NXT1</abbr>: Nuclear Export Transport 1<br><abbr title="Messenger Ribonuclear Protein Complex">mRNP</abbr>: Messenger Ribonuclear Protein Complex</p><p>Nucleoplasm:</p><ul><li>Passive diffusion： Heterodimeric <abbr title="Nuclear Export Factor 1">NXF1</abbr>/<abbr title="Nuclear Export Transport 1">NXT1</abbr> + mRNPs.<br>Cytosol</li><li>Dissociation: RNA helicase (Dbp5) + ATP + [<abbr title="Nuclear Export Factor 1">NXF1</abbr>/<abbr title="Nuclear Export Transport 1">NXT1</abbr>]-[<abbr title="Messenger Ribonuclear Protein Complex">mRNP</abbr>] →  <abbr title="Nuclear Export Factor 1">NXF1</abbr> + <abbr title="Nuclear Export Transport 1">NXT1</abbr> + mRNA + ADP + Pi</li><li>Recycling: Ran-dependent import recycles <abbr title="Nuclear Export Factor 1">NXF1</abbr> and <abbr title="Nuclear Export Transport 1">NXT1</abbr></li></ul><hr><hr><p>Vesicular Traffic</p><p>Class I Presentation to CO8⁺ T Cells [go to find the pic and make more notes.]<br>Cross presentaiton<br>P: 1110</p><p>Class II Presentation to CD4⁺ T Cells<br>P: 1112</p><p>Lodish MCB, 8th ed., pages 631-659.</p><h2 id="Techniques-for-Studying-the-Secretory-Pathway">Techniques for Studying the Secretory Pathway</h2><h3 id="Protein-Transport-through-the-Secretory-Pathway">Protein Transport through the Secretory Pathway</h3><h3 id="Secretory-and-Endocytic-Pathways">Secretory and Endocytic Pathways</h3><h3 id="Sec-Mutants-Identify-5-Stages-of-Secretory-Pathway">Sec Mutants Identify 5 Stages of Secretory Pathway</h3><p><mark>Exam</mark>: Classes , what machine could be broken/mutant</p><h3 id="Coated-Vesicles-Involved-in-Protein-Trafficking">Coated Vesicles Involved in Protein Trafficking</h3><p><mark>Coated Vesicles table, 1, 2, 4</mark></p><h3 id="Docking-Fusion-of-Vesicle-w-Target-Membrane">Docking/Fusion of Vesicle w/Target Membrane</h3><p>Coil-Coil structure is really staby, not easty to recycle.</p><h3 id="KDEL-Receptor-Retrieval-of-ER-Resident-Luminal-Proteins-from-the-Golgi">KDEL Receptor Retrieval of ER-Resident Luminal Proteins from the Golgi</h3><p>slide difference pH between in cis and trans Golig: help the cargo binds and releaes (pH trigger).</p><h3 id="Dynamin-Pinching-Off-of-Clathrin-Coated-Vesicles">Dynamin Pinching Off of Clathrin-Coated Vesicles</h3><p>High energy state to close the bud neck</p><p>14.2 Molecular Mechanisms of Vesicle Budding and Fusion<br>14.3 Early Stages of the Secretory Pathway<br>14.4 Later Stages of the Secretory Pathway</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK545242/bin/Lineweaver__Burke__Plot.jpg" alt="Lineweaver-Burk plots"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK545242/">© Keith P. Delaune; Khalid Alsayouri.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Exam:</p><p>Draw cell component<br>G protein regulation and fedality</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lipids, Membranes and Membrane Proteins|Graduate Biochemistry 7| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/29/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-7/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/29/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-7/</id>
    <published>2021-09-29T05:16:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-03T23:51:00.214Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Overview">Overview</h2><blockquote><ul><li>A cell is a membrane-rich environment</li><li>Classes of lipids</li><li>Structure of lipids</li><li>Polymorphic phase behavior of lipids</li><li>The lipid bilayer membrane</li><li>The fluid mosaic model of biological membranes</li><li>Classes and functions of membrane proteins</li><li>Folding and structure of membrane proteins</li><li>Hydropathy plots</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="A-cell-is-a-membrane-rich-environment">A cell is a membrane-rich environment</h2><h2 id="Classes-of-Lipids">Classes of Lipids</h2><blockquote><ul><li>Fatty acid (e.g. palmitate, oleate)<br>Energy storage metabolite<br>Building block of other lipids</li><li>Triacylglycerols (fat)<ul><li>Energy storage</li></ul></li><li>Glycerophospholipids<br>Form lipid bilayer membrane<br>Signal transduction</li><li>Sphingolipids<br>Form lipid bilayer membranes<br>Signal transduction</li><li>Steroids<br>Rigidify membranes (Cholesterol)<br>Membrane-crossing hormones (e.g. Estrogen)</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Fatty-Acids-structure-and-nomenclature">Fatty Acids - structure and nomenclature</h2><blockquote><p>Fatty acid rules of nomenclature</p><ul><li>Carbon numbering start at carboxyl carbon</li><li>Double bonds are numbered at the first carbon</li><li>cis configuration is normal (trans is specified)</li></ul><p>Syntax for nomenclature<br>length:#double bonds (list of double bond locations)</p><p>16:0 = palmitic acid<br>18:1(9) = oleic acid (sometimes written 18:1(Δ9))<br>20:4(5,8,11,14) = arachidonic acid</p></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center">palmitic acid</th><th style="text-align:center">oleic acid</th><th style="text-align:center">arachidonic acid</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=985&amp;t=l" alt="palmitic acid"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=445639&amp;t=l" alt="oleic acid"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=444899&amp;t=l" alt="arachidonic acid"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"></td><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">© PubChem ID= 985, 445639, 444899</a></td><td style="text-align:center"></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Typical eukaryotic fatty acid structure</p><ul><li>Even number of carbons</li><li>Non-conjugated double bonds (double bonds are separated by at least one CH2)<br>Double bonds are normally cis If a double<br>bond is trans it is specified in the name</li></ul></blockquote><p>PS:<br><strong>Even number</strong>: Synthesis and degraded of the fatty acid are occur two carbons at a time.<br><strong>Conjugated double bounds</strong>: Conjugated double bounds could make fluorescence. Exp: Retinol, or vitamin A, has five conjugated double bonds and absorbs the violet part of the spectrum, thus appearing as yellow.<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup><br><strong>Cis</strong>: As the picture above, the hydrogen atoms are on the same side.</p><p>Palmitic acid<br>Oleic acid</p><h2 id="Classes-of-diacyl-lipids">Classes of diacyl lipids</h2><p>The two backbone molecules in diacyl lipids:</p><ul><li>Glycerol (Glycerophospholipids)</li><li>Serine (Sphingolipids)</li></ul><blockquote><p>Diacyl lipids are the main structural component of bilayers and are the <mark>ONLY component that will form bilayers in pure form</mark>.</p></blockquote><p><mark>Be able to draw the base of this two lipids.</mark></p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center">Glycerol</th><th style="text-align:center">Serine</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=753&amp;t=l" alt="Glycerol"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=5951&amp;t=l" alt="Serine"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Two fatty acids connect to two hydroxyl groups independently, the rest hydroxyl group connect to the phosphate acid which could connect the variety head.</td><td style="text-align:center">Two fatty acids connect to Amino group and carboxyl group. R chain connect variety heads</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?sid=85336641&amp;t=l&amp;version=4&amp;deposited=t" alt="1,2-diacyl-sn-glycero-3-phospholipid"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=101893017&amp;width=1000&amp;height=1000" alt="Sphingolipid C"></td></tr></tbody></table><p>© PubChem</p><h2 id="Variety-of-Glycerophospholipid-head">Variety of Glycerophospholipid (head)</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:center"></th><th style="text-align:center"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=446066&amp;t=l" alt="Phosphatidic acid"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=5327011&amp;t=l" alt="Phosphatidylethanolamine"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=6441487&amp;t=l" alt="Phosphatidylcholine"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidic acid</td><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidylethanolamine</td><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidylcholine</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=52927225&amp;t=l" alt="Phosphatidylserine"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imgsrv.fcgi?cid=9547096&amp;t=l" alt="Phosphatidylinositol"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=53480090&amp;width=600&amp;height=600" alt="Phosphatidylglycerol"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidylglycerol</td><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidylserine</td><td style="text-align:center">Phosphatidylinositol</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"></td><td style="text-align:center">© PmdChem</td><td style="text-align:center"></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ul><li>second messenger molecule</li><li>Often phosphorylated on one o<br>several hydroxyls</li></ul></blockquote><p>No head</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=6026790&amp;width=600&amp;height=150" alt="Diacylglycerol"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">© PubChem ID=6026790</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>A signaling molecule</p><p><strong>Phosphatidic acid</strong>: is rare in memebrane but it’s intermediate of the metabolic.<br><strong>Phosphatidylcholine</strong>: Most abundant glycerophospholipid found in eukaryotic membrane. Innert, not strong interaction with others. (Outside of the membrane)<br><strong>Phosphatidylethanolamine</strong>: Charge and much activity than Phosphatidylcholine, inside the cell.<br><strong>Phosphatidylglycerol</strong>: also abundant in prokaryotic cell.<br><strong>Phosphatidylserine</strong>: active, inside the cell. Common in eukaryotic cell. It’s not a sugar group, it is a sample carbon base ring.<br><strong>Phosphatidylinositol</strong>: Negative Charged, signaling molecule. Second messenger.</p><h2 id="Sphingolipid-Headgroups">Sphingolipid Headgroups</h2><h3 id="Sphingomyelin">Sphingomyelin</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=44260125&amp;width=900&amp;height=300" alt="Sphingomyelin"></th><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rest/pug/compound/smiles/png?record_type=2d&amp;smiles=P(%3DO)(%5BO-%5D)(OC)OCC%5BN%2B%5D(C)(C)C&amp;image_size=300x220" alt="Phosphocholine"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">Sphingomyelin</td><td style="text-align:center">Phosphocholine group</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Cerebrosides">Cerebrosides</h3><blockquote><ul><li><mark>Simple sugars</mark></li><li>Galactose, lactose, glucose (uncharged)</li></ul></blockquote><p><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=127034832&amp;width=900&amp;height=400" alt="Cerebrosides"></p><h3 id="Gangliosides">Gangliosides</h3><blockquote><ul><li>More complex carbohydrates<br>(anionic) Found in brain</li></ul></blockquote><p><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=9963963&amp;width=600&amp;height=400" alt="Ganglioside GM1"></p><h2 id="Fatty-acid-melting-points">Fatty acid melting points</h2><p>The longer the chain, the higher the melting point.<br>The more double bounds, the lower the melting point.</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=3018404&amp;width=680&amp;height=150" alt="montan-wax"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">© PubChem ID= 3018404</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Melting point:82-95 °C.</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=5280450&amp;width=680&amp;height=150" alt="montan-wax"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">© PubChem ID= 5280450</a></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Melting point:-9 °C.</td></tr></tbody></table><p>PS: Cells control the fluid of the membrane by change the type of lipid (melting point) to achieve specific biology purpose.</p><p><mark>Four common fatty acid you should remember</mark></p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Symbol</th><th style="text-align:left">Common name</th><th style="text-align:left">Systematic name</th><th style="text-align:left">Structure</th><th style="text-align:left">mp (°C)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">14:0</td><td style="text-align:left">Myristic Acid</td><td style="text-align:left">Tetradecanoic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">CH₃(CH₂)₁₂COOH</td><td style="text-align:left">52</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">16:0</td><td style="text-align:left">Palmitic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">Hexadecanoic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">CH₃(CH₂)₁₄COOH</td><td style="text-align:left">63.1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">20:0</td><td style="text-align:left">Arachidic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">Eicosanoic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">CH₃(CH₂)₁₈COOH</td><td style="text-align:left">75.4</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">24:0</td><td style="text-align:left">Lignoceric acid</td><td style="text-align:left">Tetracosanoic acid</td><td style="text-align:left">CH₃(CH₂)₂₂COOH</td><td style="text-align:left">84.2</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Phospholipases-and-cyclooxygenases">Phospholipases and cyclooxygenases</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Konstantin-Balashev-3/publication/291957430/figure/fig19/AS:668710163451907@1536444335125/Phospholipases-classification-according-to-their-action-of-on-phospholipid-substrate.png" alt="Phospholipases"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/291957430_Atomic_Force_Microscopy_AFM_with_applications_spanning_from_nanoscale_biocatalysis_and_characterization_of_molecularly_ordered_nanostructures_to_molecular_biology">© Konstantin Balashev</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Phospholipases A<sub>1</sub>, <mark>A<sub>2</sub></mark>, B, C, and D.<br>Most phospholipids was cleaved by Phospholipase A<sub>2</sub></p><p><strong>cyclooxygenases</strong></p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://media.springernature.com/full/springer-static/image/art%3A10.1186%2Fgb-2004-5-9-241/MediaObjects/13059_2004_Article_756_Fig3_HTML.jpg?as=webp" alt="cyclooxygenases"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/gb-2004-5-9-241">© NV Chandrasekharan</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Cyclooxygenases (COXs) catalyze the rate-limiting step in the production of <mark>prostaglandins</mark>, which is an signal molecule and both <mark>soluble in water and lipids</mark>.</p><h2 id="Cholesterol-and-other-steroids">Cholesterol and other steroids</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=5997&amp;width=300&amp;height=300" alt="Cholesterol"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/">© PubChem ID= 5997</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ul><li>Cholesterol is a component of biological membranes</li><li>Up to 50% of a membrane’s lipid can be cholesterol</li><li>It <mark>rigidifies or stiffens</mark> bilayers</li><li>Cholesterol is converted to bile acids (used in digestion) and steroid hormones (used for signaling)</li><li>Steroid hormones freely cross membranes and act directly on nuclear receptors</li></ul></blockquote><p>The hydroxyl group of the cholesterol makes it float on the cell membrane.<br>In the <abbr title="Red blood cell">RBC</abbr>, the cholesterol in cytomembrane could up to 50% and which makes the membrane very rigidity. (try to keep it’s shape when it through the catepillars) Lake of most membrane proteins. As a contrast, the mitochondria’s membrane does not have cholesterol and has very high fluidity which needs to go constant conformation change. One of the fluidity membrane we know are rod and cone cell which are light recept cells. They need to interact quickly. As a result, they are made highly portion of the saturated fatty acids and very little of cholesterol.</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center">Steroid Hormones</th><th style="text-align:center">© PubChem</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=5754&amp;width=300&amp;height=300" alt="Cortisol"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=6013&amp;width=300&amp;height=300" alt="Testosterone"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=5839&amp;width=300&amp;height=300" alt="Aldosterone"></td><td style="text-align:center"><img src="https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/image/imagefly.cgi?cid=5757&amp;width=300&amp;height=300" alt="Β-Estradiol"></td></tr></tbody></table><p>These hormones are both soluble in water and lipids. So they can pass membrane easily.</p><h2 id="Polymorphic-Phase-Behavior-of-Lipids">Polymorphic Phase Behavior of Lipids</h2><blockquote><ul><li>All lipids spontaneously separate from water</li><li>The form of the lipid phase depends on the molecular “shape” of the molecule</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Head-group-end">Head group end</h3><p>Molecular shap hypothesis:</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Lipid Type</th><th style="text-align:left">Composition</th><th style="text-align:right">Types in below</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Fatty acid Other detergents</td><td style="text-align:left">micelle</td><td style="text-align:right">Type 1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Diacyl Lipid</td><td style="text-align:left">bilayer</td><td style="text-align:right">Type 0</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Diacyl Glycerol</td><td style="text-align:left">inverse micelle</td><td style="text-align:right">Type 2</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Core of the membrane is the most hydrophobic environment we can find.<br>In the core of folded protein, the hydrophobic core coudl have a few polar groups. But not poler group in Membrane core. Which gaves the membrane a <mark>barrier property</mark></p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.mdpi.com/cosmetics/cosmetics-03-00037/article_deploy/html/images/cosmetics-03-00037-g002.png" alt="Polymorphic Phase Behavior of Lipids"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2079-9284/3/4/37/htm#">© Chandrashekhar V. Kulkarni</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="“Fluid-Mosaic”-model-of-biological-membranes">“Fluid Mosaic” model of biological membranes</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Veronika-Novotna-3/publication/319189817/figure/fig1/AS:806585173553154@1569316299796/The-fluid-mosaic-model-of-the-plasma-membrane-2.jpg" alt="Fluid Mosaic"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/figure/The-fluid-mosaic-model-of-the-plasma-membrane-2_fig1_319189817">© Veronika Novotná, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Living cells actively maintain a certain membrane fluidity by adjusting the composition of the lipids in their membranes.</p></blockquote><p>The lipids are the solvents, the proteins are solutes.<br>This drawing is <mark>wrong</mark>. The membrane can pack more protein than it. Exp: Mitochondria.</p><h2 id="Secondary-Structure-Types-in-Membranes">Secondary Structure Types in Membranes</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Guangshun-Wang/publication/5516641/figure/fig1/AS:601654864928799@1520457106577/Fig-1-Structural-biology-of-E-coli-membrane-proteins-The-complexity-of.png" alt=""></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/5516641_NMR_of_Membrane-Associated_Peptides_and_Proteins">© Guangshun Wang</a></td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center">Header One</th><th style="text-align:center">Header Two</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">Water</td><td style="text-align:center"></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Interface</td><td style="text-align:center">15 Å</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Core</td><td style="text-align:center">30 Å</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Interface</td><td style="text-align:center">15 Å</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:center">Water</td><td style="text-align:center"></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Membrane-spanning proteins have very few polar groups groups, such as the peptide back bone exposed to the core of the bilayer.</p></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Membrane Protein</th><th style="text-align:left"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">α-helix</td><td style="text-align:left"><blockquote><li>19-25 residues to span the membrane<li>Self hydrogen-bonding<li>Mostly hydrophobic along the membrane-spanning segment<li>About 25% of ALL proteins are helical membrane proteins</blockquote></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">β-barrel</td><td style="text-align:left"><blockquote><li>8-12 residues are required to span membrane<li>Not self Hydrogen bonding<li>Dyad repeat motif (alternating hydrophobic/hydrophilic)<li>Found in the outer membranes of some bacteria and in mitochondria</blockquote></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Membrane integral protein challenges:</p><ul><li>Residues: Hydrophobic residues on the menbrane core area</li><li>Carbon back-bond: Form hydrogen bond with itself.</li></ul><p>Typically, the surface of the proteins interacted with membrane are even more hydroponically than the core of folded protein.</p><p>30Å membrane core takes about 20 residues of α-helix.<br>β-barrel only find in gram-negative bacterial, mitochondrial and chloroplasts. (Human, about 50 β-barrel gene and only on mitochondria genome. 2% of gene is β-barrel in E. coli)</p><h2 id="Structure-of-Bovine-Rhodopsin">Structure of Bovine Rhodopsin</h2><p>A protin in eye cell membrane.<br>Salt bridges and hydrogen bonds are rare in membrane protein.</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><iframe style="width: 500px; height: 300px;" frameborder="0" src="https://embed.molview.org/v1/?mode=balls&pdbid=1f88&bg=white&chainType=ribbon&chainColor=spectrum"></iframe></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://molview.org/?pdbid=1f88">© Molview, PDBID=1f88</a> Rhodopsin Dimer</td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Structure of Rhodopsin<br>Spacefilling</p><ul><li>Side View Top View</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p>Structural features of membrane proteins</p><ul><li>Exterior is very hydrophobic over ~30 Å slab of the membrane</li><li>Interior has amino acid composition like that of a soluble protein</li><li>Helices are close-packed</li><li>Salt-bridges and helix-helix hydrogen bonds are rare</li><li>ionizable residues are nearly always salt bridged.</li><li>Helix-helix interactions are mainly driven by van der Waals packing</li></ul></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Ling-Peng-7/publication/255956206/figure/fig15/AS:705841674072064@1545297177166/Schematic-representation-of-glycophorin-A-Glycophorin-A-is-a-membrane-protein-with-131.png" alt="Glycophorin A"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/255956206_Photoactivatable_Lipid_Probes_for_Studying_Biomembranes_by_Photoaffinity_Labeling">© Yi Xia</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>The human erythrocyte protein Glycophorin A has a single membrane-spanning α-helix</p></blockquote><h3 id="Hydropathy-Analysis">Hydropathy Analysis</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Ian-Humphery-Smith/publication/6961802/figure/fig1/AS:457412860747776@1486067133748/GC-content-of-an-exon-that-failed-to-be-expressed-The-GC-content-plot-was-generated.png" alt="Sliding Window Hydropathy Plot"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/6961802_Analysis_of_High_Throughput_Protein_Expression_in_Escherichia_coli">© Yair Benita, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Take the 19 amino acids in a box from the chain and calculate the hydrophobicity, and them you slid it one by one to make the Sliding Window Hydropathy Plot.</p><h2 id="Glut1">Glut1</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><iframe style="width: 500px; height: 300px;" frameborder="0" src="https://embed.molview.org/v1/?mode=balls&pdbid=4pyp&bg=white&chainType=ribbon&chainColor=spectrum"></iframe></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://molview.org/?pdbid=4pyp">© Molview, PDBID= 4pyp </a> Rhodopsin Dimer</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0301462215000502-gr2.jpg" alt="Glut1"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0301462215000502">© MobeenRaja, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><hr class="footnotes-sep"><section class="footnotes"><ol class="footnotes-list"><li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p><a href="https://people.chem.umass.edu/samal/269/color.pdf">A Brief Discussion on Color; umass.edu</a> <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></section>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Integrins Form an Expanding Diffusional Barrier that Coordinates Phagocytosis</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/26/Paper/paper-immune-integrins/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/26/Paper/paper-immune-integrins/</id>
    <published>2021-09-26T18:59:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-18T15:27:37.274Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Integrins-Form-an-Expanding-Diffusional-Barrier-that-Coordinates-Phagocytosis">Integrins Form an Expanding Diffusional Barrier that Coordinates Phagocytosis</h2><p>cite: <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26771488/">Freeman, Spencer A., et al. “Integrins form an expanding diffusional barrier that coordinates phagocytosis.” Cell 164.1-2 (2016): 128-140.</a></p><h2 id="Brief">Brief</h2><blockquote><p>To create the large zone of Src-family kinase (SFK) phosphorylation required for phagocytosis, a cascade of integrin activation, emanating from antigen contact sites, generates an expanding actin-based diffusion barrier that restricts the access of the bulky phosphatase molecules that target SFK.</p><p><em><strong>Highlights</strong></em></p><ul><li>Tyrosine phosphatases are excluded from sites of phagocytosis</li><li>An expanding diffusion barrier prevents phosphatase access to sites of phagocytosis</li><li>Integrins activated by phagocytic receptors generate the diffusion barrier</li><li>Activated integrins bridge sparse phagocytic receptors and coordinate phagocytosis</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Summary">Summary</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0092867415015676-fx1.jpg" alt="Graphical Abstract"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867415015676">© Spencer A Freeman, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Phagocytosis-activate">Phagocytosis activate</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Phagocytosis is initiated by lateral clustering of receptors, which in turn activates Src-family kinases (<em><strong>SFKs</strong></em>).</li><li>Activation of SFKs requires <em><strong>depletion of tyrosine phosphatases</strong></em> from the area of particle engagement.</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Fcg">Fcg</h3><blockquote><ul><li>The mobility of CD45 increased markedly upon engagement of <em><strong>Fcg receptors</strong></em>. While individual CD45 molecules <em><strong>moved randomly</strong></em>, they were displaced from the advancing phagocytic cup by an expanding diffusional barrier.<ul><li>By micropatterning IgG, the ligand of Fcg receptors, we found that the <em><strong>barrier extended</strong></em> well beyond the perimeter of the receptor-ligand engagement zone.</li><li>Second messengers generated by Fcg receptors activated integrins, which formed an actin-<abbr title="被拴住">tethered</abbr> diffusion barrier that excluded CD45. The expanding integrin wave facilitates the zippering of Fcg receptors onto the target and integrates the information from sparse receptor-ligand complexes, coordinating the progression and ultimate closure of the phagocytic cup.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Introduction">Introduction</h2><ul><li><p>Phagocytosis is initiated by a clustering of receptors.</p></li><li><p>Fcg receptor could recognize the Fc portion of IgG in phagocytic response.</p></li><li><p>The Multiplicity of IgG stimulate the Src-family kinase (<em><strong>SFKs</strong></em>)</p></li><li><p>CD45 and CD148 on phagocytes are <strong>tyrosine phosphatases</strong>.</p></li><li><p><em><strong>SFKs</strong></em> activation needs the <strong>remove of phosphatases</strong>.</p></li><li><p>Upon binding ligand, B/T cell receptors to form a central supermolecular activation center (<em><strong>cSMAC</strong></em>)</p></li><li><p>phosphatases are displaced to the periphery</p></li><li><p>exofacial domain of Fcg receptors is notably shorter (z6 nm) than phosphatases. So, how they excluded CD45 and CD148?</p></li></ul><blockquote><ul><li>integrins as progressive diffusional barriers that serve to integrate the signals emanating from immobile Fcg receptor microclusters.</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Result">Result</h2><h3 id="Activation-of-Fcg-Receptors-Increases-the-Mobility-of-CD45">Activation of Fcg Receptors Increases the Mobility of CD45</h3><p><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0092867415015676-gr1_lrg.jpg" alt=""></p><blockquote><p>(A) Human macrophages incubated with <abbr title="聚苯乙烯">polystyrene</abbr> beads opsonized with 0.5 mg IgG/107 particles. Cells were fixed after 45 s and stained for CD45 (green), pY (red), and IgG (cyan, inset). Scale bar, 10 μm.</p><p>(B–F) Single CD45 particles were visualized in macrophages using anti-CD45 Fab fragments labeled with Qdots (B, inset).</p><p>(B) Macrophages were seeded onto either BSA-coated or IgG-coated coverslips and particles tracked for 20 s at 33 Hz. CD45 trajectories were analyzed by MSS; the motion type for each trajectory is color coded as follows: blue, confined; cyan, free; and red, linear. Scale bar, 5 μm.</p><p>(C–E) CD45 motion type ©, median confinement diameter (D), and median diffusion coefficient (E) for cells seeded on BSA (20 min), IgG (20 min), or BSA + LatA (15 + 5 min) were determined from 10-s recordings. Horizontal lines are means of ≥17 cells from three independent experiments; &gt;1,000 trajectories were analyzed per condition.</p><p>(F) Three trajectories from (B) shown with color-coded time course. Depletion zones drawn in (B) and (F) delineate the area depleted of CD45. They were drawn to approximate the contour of the F-actin ring.</p></blockquote><p>(A) shows that the CD45 was depleted from the phagocytic site. But the pY was recruited. As a result, they formed a phagocytic cup which had py in the center which was circled by CD45</p><p>(B) shows the migration of the CD45 during the phagocytosis.<br>Resting: When the cell didn’t perform phagocytosis<br>2/5/10 min: 2/5/10 min after the cell perform phagocytosis</p><blockquote><ul><li>Contrary to the predictions made by the model of Yamauchi et al. (2012), fewer than 3% of the CD45 molecules moved linearly either at rest or during phagocytosis (Figures 1B and 1C).<ul><li>Yamauchi et al. (2012) proposed that myosin II facilitates the redistribution of CD45 during phagocytosis.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>© The different diffusion types of the CD45 contour with different particles.</p><p>engaging Fcg receptors increased the fraction of CD45 undergoing free diffusion from 47% ± 14% to 70% ± 11% (means ± SD) at the expense of confined molecules, which decreased proportionately</p><p>(D) the mean diameter of the remaining confinement zones increased.</p><h3 id="CD45-Is-Progressively-Displaced-by-a-Diffusion-Barrier">CD45 Is Progressively Displaced by a Diffusion Barrier</h3><p><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0092867415015676-gr2.jpg" alt="CD45 Is Progressively Displaced by a Diffusion Barrier"></p><p>MMS: diffusing freely<br>Video evidence: CD45 bounce off the edge of the zone of depletion</p><p>Play/Download: <img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0092867415015676-mmc2.mp4" alt="Video"></p><p>IgG dots on the slice:  printed IgG onto glass coverslips</p><h3 id="The-Area-of-Depletion-of-CD45-Extends-beyond-Regions-of-Microclustered-Fcg-Receptors">The Area of Depletion of CD45 Extends beyond Regions of Microclustered Fcg Receptors</h3><p>This is a fine day.</p><p>Fcg : Fcγ</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Integrins Form an Expanding Diffusional Barrier that Coordinates Phagocytosis</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Paper" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Paper/"/>
    
    <category term="Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Paper/Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Immune" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Paper/Biology/Immune/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Papers" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Papers/"/>
    
    <category term="Immune" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Immune/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fly crossover</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/25/Flies/fly-cross/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/25/Flies/fly-cross/</id>
    <published>2021-09-25T15:23:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-27T22:19:06.123Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Fly-Crossover">Fly Crossover</h2><p>Met_ {RNAi} （III）<br>Gre_ {RNAi}  （III）<br>Hnf4_ {RNAi}  （III）<br>UAS-GFP （II）</p><p>Target:</p><ul><li><p>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO}；\frac{Hnf4_ {RNAi}}{TM_ 6b}$</p></li><li><p>$Sp/CyO；Met_ {RNAi} /TM<sub>6</sub>b$</p></li><li><p>$Sp/CyO；Gre_ {RNAi} /TM<sub>6</sub>b$</p></li></ul><h2 id="Line-1">Line 1</h2><p>$$<br>;\frac{+}{+};\ Hnf4_ {RNAi}\ \ \ \times\ \ \  ;\frac{Sp}{CyO};\ \frac{Dr}{TM_ 6b}<br>$$</p><p>F<sub>1</sub>:</p><ul><li>$;\frac{Sp}{+};\ \frac{Dr}{Hnf4_ {RNAi}}$</li><li>$;\frac{CyO}{+};\ \frac{Dr}{Hnf4_ {RNAi}}$</li><li>$;\frac{Sp}{+};\ \frac{Hnf4_ {RNAi}}{TM_ 6b}$</li><li>$;\frac{CyO}{+};\ \frac{Hnf4_ {RNAi}}{TM_ 6b}$</li></ul><h2 id="Line-2">Line 2</h2><p>$$<br>;UAS_ {GFP}; \ \ \times \ \ ;\frac{Sp}{CyO};\frac{Dr}{TM_ 6b}<br>$$</p><p>F<sub>1</sub>:</p><ul><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{Sp};\frac{Dr}{+}$</li><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{Sp};\frac{TM_ 6b}{+}$</li><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{Dr}{+}$</li><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{TM_ 6b}{+}$</li></ul><p>L<sub>2</sub>F<sub>2</sub>:</p><p>$$  ;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{Dr}{+} \ \ \times<br>\ \ ;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{TM_ 6b}{+}$$</p><ul><li>Ch2:<ul><li>$\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO}$; $UAS_ {GFP}$</li><li>$CyO$ <mark>Dead</mark></li></ul></li><li>Ch3:<ul><li>$\frac{Dr}{+}$; $\frac{CyO}{+}$; $\frac{Dr}{CyO}$</li></ul></li></ul><hr><ul><li>$;UAS_ {GFP};\frac{Dr}{+}$</li><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{Dr}{TM_ 6b}$</li><li>$;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{+}{+}$</li><li>$;\frac{CyO}{CyO};\frac{TM_ 6b}{+}$</li></ul><h2 id="L1F1-L2F2-crosses">L1F<sub>1</sub>; L2F<sub>2</sub> crosses</h2><p>$$<br>;\frac{UAS_ {GFP}}{CyO};\frac{Dr}{CyO}<br>\ \ \times\ \ s<br>$$</p><p>$$<br>R^2 = 0.9889<br>$$</p><p>$$<br>y = -28.1452x + 135.5281<br>$$</p><p>x = (y - 135.5281) / (-28.1452)</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Fly crossover experiment</summary>
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Protein Analysis|Graduate Biochemistry 6| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/24/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-6/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/24/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-6/</id>
    <published>2021-09-24T13:31:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-05T05:45:45.760Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Purification-and-Analysis-Overview">Purification and Analysis Overview</h2><blockquote><ul><li>Methods of protein separation and purification</li><li>Protein solubility</li><li>Isoelectric focusing</li><li>Principles of chromatography<ul><li>Polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis</li><li>Gel filtration</li><li>Ion exchange/Hydrophobic interaction</li><li>Affinity Chromatography</li></ul></li><li>Ultracentrifugation<br><em><strong>Methods of protein analysis</strong></em></li><li>Summary of primary information</li><li>Protein sequencing by Edman degradation</li><li>Mass spectrometry</li><li>Methods of determining protein three dimensional structure</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Methods-of-Macromolecule-Separation">Methods of Macromolecule Separation</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Method of Separation</th><th style="text-align:left">Physical Basis</th><th style="text-align:left">sensitivity</th><th style="text-align:left">Specifity</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#Protein-Solubility">Precipitation</a></td><td style="text-align:left">Solubility (charge, isoelectric point)</td><td style="text-align:left">μg - kg</td><td style="text-align:left">Very low</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#Mass-Spectrometry">Mass Spectrometry</a></td><td style="text-align:left">Molecular Mass</td><td style="text-align:left">fg - ug</td><td style="text-align:left">Very High</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Nondenaturing PAGE</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Charge/mass, shape</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>μg - mg</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>High</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#SDS-PAGE"><em><strong>SDS PAGE</strong></em></a></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Molecular Weight</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>μg - mg</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>High</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#Isoelectric-focusing"><em><strong>Isoelectric focusing</strong></em></a></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Isoelectric point</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>μg - mg</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Moderate</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Capillary Electrophoresis</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Charge/mass</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>ng - μg</strong></em></td><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>High</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark><a href="#Gel-Filtration-Chromatography">Gel Filtration</a></mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Size and shape</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>ng - mg</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>High</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark><a href="#Ion-Exchange-Chromatography">Ion Exchange</a></mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Net charge</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>ng - mg</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Moderate High</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark><a href="#Hydrophobic-Interaction-Chromatography">Hydrophobic interaction Chromatography</a></mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Hydrophobicity</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>ng - mg</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>High</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark><a href="#Affinity-Chromatography">Affinity Chromatography</a></mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Specific molecular interactoin</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>ng - mg</mark></td><td style="text-align:left"><mark>Very High</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#Density-Gradient-Ultracentrifugation"><strong>Density Gradient Ultracentrifugation</strong></a></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>Molecular weight, density and shape</strong></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>μg - g</strong></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>Moderate</strong></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="#Ultracentrifugation"><strong>Equlibrium Density Ultracentrifugation</strong></a></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>Density</strong></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>μg - g</strong></td><td style="text-align:left"><strong>Moderate</strong></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Legend:</p><ul><li><em><strong>Electrophoresis techniques</strong></em></li><li><mark>Chromatography techniques</mark></li><li><strong>Ultracentrifugation techniques</strong></li></ul><h3 id="Protein-Solubility-in-Salt">Protein Solubility in Salt</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>Salting in</strong></em></p><ul><li>Increase in solubility with increasing salt at low ionic strength</li><li>Proteins unfold at low ionic strength and irreversibly aggregate</li></ul><p><em><strong>Salting out</strong></em></p><ul><li>Protein precipitation at high ionic strength driven by ionic charge shielding and solvent effects</li><li>Solubility is minimum at isoelectric point (ionic effect)</li><li>Effectiveness of salting out in <strong>Hoffmeister series</strong> (solvent effect):<ul><li>Anions: SO4&gt;H2PO4&gt;CH3COO&gt;Br&gt;I&gt;ClO4&gt;SCN</li><li>Cations: NH4,Cs,K,Na&gt;Li&gt;Mg&gt;Ca&gt;Ba</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><p>PS: Increase the salt, you shield the charge surface of the protein</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://wou.edu/chemistry/files/2019/08/Salting-in-out-2-768x599.png" alt="Salting In and Salting Out"></th><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Richard-Burgess-5/publication/229422294/figure/fig1/AS:669381373722633@1536604364653/Ammonium-sulfate-solubility-curve-for-a-hypothetical-protein-This-represents-the-log.png" alt="Ammonium sulfate solubility curve"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Saltin_in_%26_Salting_out.png">© Michel Awkal 2020</a></td><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/229422294_Chapter_20_Protein_Precipitation_Techniques">© Richard R Burgess 2009</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Solting in: The unsaturated ions on the surface of the protein can interacted with other ions to increase the soluability of the protein.</p><h3 id="Isoelectric-focusing">Isoelectric focusing</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Blake-Meyers/publication/6626845/figure/fig6/AS:667197747757081@1536083747895/Fractionation-of-proteins-by-preparative-isoelectric-focusing-A-Protein-samples.jpg" alt="Isoelectric focusing"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/6626845_Use_of_Massively_Parallel_Signature_Sequencing_to_Study_Genes_Expressed_During_the_Plant_Defense_Response">© Blake C Meyers 2007</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Isoelectric point (pI) is the pH at which positive and negative charges are equally abundant on a molecule.<br>pI for the <strong>G</strong> is ~6;<br>pI for <strong>D</strong> is ~3.5<br>pI for <strong>K</strong> is ~ 9.5</p></blockquote><blockquote><ul><li>Isoelectric focusing is equilibrium electrophoresis</li><li>Ampholytes - Mixtures of buffer molecules covering a range of pKa values stabilize the pH gradient in an electric field</li><li>Charged molecules, including the ampholytes, will move toward the location where their net charge is zero. This is the isoelectric point, or pI.</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Chromatography">Chromatography</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>Principle of Chromatography</strong></em></p><ul><li>Molecules in a mobile medium move through a stationary phase with which they can interact.</li><li>Differential interactions with the stationary phase are the basis for physical separation of molecules</li></ul><p><em><strong>Some stationary phases</strong></em></p><ul><li>Paper (paper Chromatography)</li><li>Bare silica (Thin layer chromatography)</li><li>Functionalized Silica (Column Chromatography)</li><li>Various polymers (acrylamide, dextran, agarose, and others)</li></ul><p>Mobile phase is usually liquid</p></blockquote><h3 id="SDS-PAGE">SDS PAGE</h3><p>Sodium Dodecyl Sulfate Polyacrylamide Gel Electrophoresis</p><blockquote><p>Acrylamide gel:</p><ul><li>Polymerized acrylamide</li><li>Macromolecule movement is hindered</li><li>Movement driven by electric field</li><li>Mobility is determined by charge, size and shape</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p>SDS: A detergent that denatures proteins</p></blockquote><ul><li>with/withough reducing agent:<ul><li>breaking the disulfide bond</li></ul></li></ul><blockquote><p>Proteins denatured in SDS:</p><ul><li>3 SDS bound per amino acid</li><li>Constant charge/mass</li><li>Mobility α ln(mass)</li></ul></blockquote><ul><li>SDS can also solubilize hydrophobic AA</li><li>Useful but may lots some information.</li></ul><h3 id="Gel-Filtration-Chromatography">Gel Filtration Chromatography</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Marcell-Wolf/publication/305215444/figure/fig5/AS:614360984612865@1523486481230/Size-exclusion-chromatography-also-called-gel-filtration-separates-proteins-according.png" alt="Gel Filtration Chromatography"></th><th style="text-align:left"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Rufika-Abidin/publication/313851127/figure/fig7/AS:590027151138817@1517684843651/Principles-of-size-exclusion-chromatography-A-Magnified-diagram-of-a-media-bead-and-its.png" alt="Gel Filtration Beets"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/305215444_Effective_interactions_in_liquid-liquid_phase_separated_protein_solutions_induced_by_multivalent_ions">© Marcell Wolf, 2015</a></td><td style="text-align:left"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/313851127_Murine_polyomavirus_VLP_as_a_platform_for_cytotoxic_T_cell-based_influenza_vaccine_candidates">© Rufika Shari Abidin</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>Vo = Void Volume, Excluded Volume<br>V<sub>i</sub> = Included Volume<br>V<sub>T</sub> (Total solvent volume) = V<sub>o</sub>+V<sub>i</sub></p><p>For each mocromolecule<br>V<sub>p</sub> = Penetrable volume<br>V<sub>e</sub> (Protein Elution Volume) = V<sub>o</sub>+V<sub>p</sub></p><p>σ (fractional retention) = V<sub>p</sub>/V<sub>i</sub><br>V<sub>p</sub>/V<sub>i</sub> = (V<sub>e</sub> - V<sub>o</sub>)/(V<sub>T</sub> - V<sub>o</sub>)</p></blockquote><ul><li>Polymer pours beets.</li><li>separated the protein by its size</li><li>You can’t tell the protein is monomor, dimer or etc.</li><li>small proteins randomly filtered inside of the beets and causing transfer delay.</li></ul><h3 id="Ion-Exchange-Chromatography">Ion Exchange Chromatography</h3><blockquote><ul><li><p><strong>Retention</strong> is due to <strong>ionic interactions</strong> with fixed charges on stationary phase</p></li><li><p><strong>Counterions</strong> compete for binding sites</p></li><li><p>Three phases: binding, elution, regeneration</p></li></ul><p>Binding:</p><ul><li>Cation exchange: fixed anions</li><li>Anion exchange: fixed cations</li></ul><p><em>Typical Ionic groups</em></p><ul><li>Diaminoethylamino (DEAE)</li><li>Carboxymethyl (caboxylate)</li><li>Sulfoethyl/Sulfobenzyl (sulfate)</li></ul></blockquote><p>The material is charged:</p><ul><li>Same charge: not interacted</li><li>opposite Charge: Reacted</li></ul><h3 id="Hydrophobic-Interaction-Chromatography">Hydrophobic Interaction Chromatography</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Binding to stationary phase is hydrophobic</li><li>Elution is with organic solvents (Acetonitrile, methanol, isopropanol, hexane)</li><li>Often used in High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC).</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Affinity-Chromatography">Affinity Chromatography</h3><blockquote><ul><li><p>Retention is due to specific interaction</p></li><li><p><em><strong>Typical affinity molecules:</strong></em></p><ul><li>Antibody</li><li>Ligand/substrate/inhibitor</li><li>Lectin (carbohydrates)</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><ul><li>Nickel-Nitrilotriacetate or Ni-NTA Binds to engineered poly Histidine</li></ul></blockquote><p>PS: Some specific interact between the protein and the ?agent</p><h3 id="Example-of-Enzyme-Purification">Example of Enzyme Purification</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Purification Step</th><th style="text-align:center">Total Acitivity</th><th style="text-align:center">% recovery</th><th style="text-align:center">Specific Activity</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Crude Extract</td><td style="text-align:center">31800</td><td style="text-align:center">100</td><td style="text-align:center">1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Acid Precipitate</td><td style="text-align:center">59900</td><td style="text-align:center">189</td><td style="text-align:center">10.1</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Amm. Sulfate Precipitate</td><td style="text-align:center">57200</td><td style="text-align:center">175</td><td style="text-align:center">27.2</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">GTP ( affinity)</td><td style="text-align:center">37300</td><td style="text-align:center">117</td><td style="text-align:center">3962</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Mono Q (ion exchange)</td><td style="text-align:center">14300</td><td style="text-align:center">45</td><td style="text-align:center">6304</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Gel filtration</td><td style="text-align:center">11000</td><td style="text-align:center">35</td><td style="text-align:center">11620</td></tr></tbody></table><div id="echarts6674" style="width: 85%;height: 400px;margin: 0 auto"></div><script src="https://cdn.bootcss.com/echarts/3.8.0/echarts.common.min.js"></script><script type="text/javascript">        // 基于准备好的dom，初始化echarts实例        var myChart = echarts.init(document.getElementById('echarts6674'));        // 指定图表的配置项和数据        var option = option = {  tooltip: {    trigger: 'axis',    axisPointer: {      type: 'shadow'    }  },  legend: {    data:['Total Acitivity', '% recovery', 'Specific Activity']  },  grid: {    left: '3%',    right: '4%',    bottom: '3%',    containLabel: true  },  xAxis: [    {      type: 'category',      data: ['Crude Extract', 'Acid Precipitate', 'Amm. Sulfate Precipitate ', 'GTP ( affinity)',      'Mono Q (ion exchange)', 'Gel filtration'],      axisLabel: { interval: 0, rotate: 15 },    }  ],  yAxis: [    {      type: 'value'    }  ],  series: [    {      name: 'Total Acitivity',      type: 'bar',      label: {        show: true,        rotate: 90,        align: 'left',        verticalAlign: 'middle',        position:  'insideBottom',        formatter: '{c} | {a}',        distance: 15      },      emphasis: {        focus: 'series'      },      data: [31800 , 59900, 57200, 37300 , 14300 , 11000]    },    {      name: '% recovery',      type: 'bar',      label: {        show: true,        rotate: 90,        align: 'left',        verticalAlign: 'middle',        position:  'insideBottom',        formatter: '{c} | {a}',        distance: 15      },      emphasis: {        focus: 'series'      },      data: [100 , 189 , 175 , 117, 45 , 35]    },    {      name: 'Specific Activity',      type: 'bar',      label: {        show: true,        formatter: '{c} | {a}',      },      emphasis: {        focus: 'series'      },      data: [1,10.1, 27.2, 3962, 6304, 11620]    },  ]};        // 使用刚指定的配置项和数据显示图表。        myChart.setOption(option);</script><h3 id="Ultracentrifugation">Ultracentrifugation</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>Bouyant</strong></em> force depends on:</p><ul><li>Density Difference between molecule and solvent</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Frictional</strong></em> force depends on:</p><ul><li>Molecular shape</li><li>Solvent viscosity</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Centrifugal</strong></em> force depends on:</p><ul><li>Molecular weight</li><li>Rotation speed</li><li>Distance from center</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Ultracentrifugation</strong></em></p><ul><li>Can be used to obtain information on molecular weight, molecular shape and intermolecular interactions</li><li>Sedimentation velocity (S=Svedbergs)</li><li>Sedimentation equilibrium</li></ul></blockquote><h4 id="Density-Gradient-Ultracentrifugation"><em><strong>Density Gradient Ultracentrifugation</strong></em></h4><blockquote><ul><li>Sucrose gradient:<ul><li>Gradient is man-made and impermanent</li><li>Sample applied at top</li><li>Separation is by sedimentation velocity</li></ul></li></ul><p>CsCl density Gradient:</p><ul><li>Gradient is formed by centrifugal force</li><li>Equilibrium position of macromolecule determined by its density</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Protein-Sequence-Determination">Protein  Sequence Determination</h3><h4 id="Primary-Information">Primary Information</h4><blockquote><ul><li>Number of chains<ul><li>Dansyl Chloride reaction (Voet, Voet &amp; Pratt pg 109)</li><li>One cycle of Edman degradation</li><li>SDS PAGE (under reducing conditions)</li></ul></li><li>Primary Sequence<ul><li>Fragmentation, purification of fragments and Edman sequencing or mass spectroscopy</li><li>Requires overlapping fragments<ul><li>Common fragmentation methods:<ul><li>Cyanogen Bromide (cleaves C-term side of Met)</li><li><mark>Trypsin</mark> (cleaves C-term side of Arg, Lys)</li><li>Chymotrypsin (cleaves C-term side of Trp, Phe, Tyr)</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul></li><li>Disulfide linkages<ul><li>SDS PAGE (reduced and non-reduced)</li><li>Fragmentation, purification and partial sequencing with disulfide bonds oxidized/reduced</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Protein-Sequencing">Protein Sequencing</h2><blockquote><p><em><strong>Principles of Edman degradation:</strong></em></p><ul><li>Cyclic, sequential removal and identification of N-terminal amino acids</li><li>Identification is done by High Pressure Liquid Chromatography (HPLC)</li><li>Can sequence 50-100 residues</li><li>Sequence determination requires overlapping fragments</li></ul></blockquote><ol><li>Derivitization: Phenylisothiocyanate (PITC)</li><li>Acid cleavage: PTC polypeptide terminal remove</li><li>Acid reduction: Polypeptide like of residue</li><li>Separation and Identification</li></ol><blockquote><p>(Back to 1.)<br>cite: Voet, Voet &amp; Pratt pg 113</p></blockquote><h3 id="Mass-Spectrometry">Mass Spectrometry</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>Principle of Mass Spectrometry</strong></em></p><ul><li>Acceleration of a molecule in an electric field depends on the mass/charge ratio</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Protein Mass Spectrometry</strong></em><br>MALDI TOF - Matrix assisted laser desorption - Time of flight<br>ESI - Electrospray ionization</p><p>Both methods can be used to determine the molecular weight of proteins up to ~ 105 Daltons</p><p>Molecular weight determination is unambiguous</p></blockquote><h3 id="Proteomics-by-mass-spectrometry">Proteomics - by mass spectrometry</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>Genomics</strong></em>: The study of the an organism’s genetic information.<br><em><strong>Proteomics</strong></em>: The study of large scale protein expression pattern in a cell type or tissue.</p><p>Genomic information is fixed. Proteomic information depends on life cycle, environment, cell type etc.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Below: Two-dimensional gel electrophoresis of an E. coli whole cell extract.<br>Modern MALDI/SELDI mass spectrometers can identify these proteins<br>Often done by cutting out spots, digesting proteins with trypsin and getting the mass of the fragments by mass spec.</p></blockquote><h3 id="Determination-of-Protein-Structure">Determination of Protein Structure</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Two methods are used to determine protein structure:<ul><li>X-ray crystallography</li><li>Two-dimensional Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>X-ray crystallography</strong></em></p><ul><li>purify protein</li><li>grow crystals</li><li>collect X-ray diffraction patterns</li><li>determine electron density in three dimensions</li><li>solve protein structure</li></ul><p><em><strong>Advantages:</strong></em></p><ul><li>Can solve very large proteins/complexes</li><li>Gives atomic-level resolution</li></ul><p><em><strong>Disadvantages:</strong></em></p><ul><li>crystallization is often difficult or impossible</li><li>crystal contacts can distort structure</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Determination-of-Protein-Structure-v2">Determination of Protein Structure</h3><blockquote><p><em><strong>2D NMR Spectroscopy</strong></em></p><ul><li>purify protein</li><li>collect multidimensional NMR spectra in solution</li><li>assign peaks and crosspeaks to specific residues</li><li>calculate distances between residues from the strength of the crosspeaks</li><li>solve structure using distance constraints<br><em><strong>Advantages:</strong></em></li><li>no crystallization required</li><li>structure is a solution structure<br><em><strong>Disadvantages:</strong></em></li><li>Only small proteins (&lt;200 residues) can be solved</li><li>Resolution is not at atomic level</li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Protein Folding|Graduate Biochemistry 5| Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/22/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-5/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/22/LearnNotes/tulane-biochem-5/</id>
    <published>2021-09-22T13:33:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T21:30:00.316Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Protein-Stability-and-Folding">Protein Stability and Folding</h2><blockquote><p>Overview</p><ul><li>Post translational modifications</li><li>The interactions that drive protein folding</li><li>The interactions that drive protein unfolding</li><li>The net stability of folded proteins</li><li>Free energies of protein folding</li><li>Mutation studies</li><li>The Levinthal paradox</li><li>Folding pathways</li><li>Molecular Chaperones</li><li>Degradation of proteins<br>Reading: All of Chapter 6</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Proteolysis">Proteolysis</h2><ul><li>segments-cleave</li><li>signal peptide cleaved in Membrane/secreted proteins</li><li>proproteins: hormones; enzyems</li><li>The final hormone is cleaved</li></ul><blockquote><ul><li>Some proteases are synthesized as zymogens which are activated by cleavage of a segment from the protein</li></ul></blockquote><p>Significant: Table (half life), soluable<br>Exp: Insulin</p><p>PS: Some maturation of proteins are involved with pro-peptides cleavage. <a href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/03/29/LearnNotes/edx-biochm-5/#Enzyme-Chymotrypsin">Insulin is an classical example.</a><br>Insulin has not much of structure amino acid, lack of an hydrophobic core.<br>6 Cystines and form 3 pair of disulfide bonds. Insulin’s primary structure has not enough information to drive it to the native structure. As a result, people believe that insulin has a memory of each processes to fold.</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://cdn.rcsb.org/images/structures/hi/2hiu/2hiu_assembly-1.jpeg" alt="Insulin"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.rcsb.org/structure/2HIU">© PDB ID=2hiu</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Amino-Acid-Modulation">Amino Acid Modulation</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Modulation Type</th><th style="text-align:left">Added Group</th><th style="text-align:left">Location / targets</th><th style="text-align:left">Reversible / Not</th><th style="text-align:left">General Features</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Glycosylation</td><td style="text-align:left">carbohydrates</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>-N-linkage (on <strong>N</strong>-R) (More common)<li>-O-linked (on <strong>S</strong>, <strong>T</strong>)</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"><li>Variety; long; branched; Charged; Ionized; Large</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Hydroxylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Carboxyl</td><td style="text-align:left"><li><strong>L</strong> &amp; <strong>P</strong> are hydroxylated on —CH₂ groups<li>Requires Ascorbate (V<sub>C</sub>)<li> mainly in collagens(<strong>Gly</strong>-X-Y)<li> <strong>P</strong> - 3 or 4 hydroxy proline</td><td style="text-align:left">Irreversible</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>Lack of V<sub>C</sub>, cell depart</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Methylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Methyl</td><td style="text-align:left"><li><strong>K</strong> and <strong>H</strong> are methylated on –NH₃, NH₂ groups;<li><strong>K</strong> can also be trimethylated (3 Methyl groups)</td><td style="text-align:left">Reversible</td><td style="text-align:left"><li><mark>Doesn’t loose it’s charge</mark>. the Amine group still keep charge.<li>Spatial Increased and effect the interactions with other atoms.<li> DNA binding proteins (<strong>K</strong> phosphate the DNA)</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Acetylation/Acylation</td><td style="text-align:left">R-Carboxyl (myristate)</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>Amino group of the R chain to for a peptide bond<li><strong>K</strong>; <strong>H</strong>; Terminal AA</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>R Chain are reversible;<li>Terminal are usually not reversible</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>Charge is <mark>removed</mark>.<li>More hydrophobic <li> Increase the interact with cell membrane.<li>Reversible; Highly Controlled</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Carboxylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Carboxyl</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> The γ-carbon of <strong>E</strong> can be carboxylated</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"><li> The <strong>E</strong> have two carboxyl groups.<li>Mainly blood coagulation enzymes.<li> Requires V<sub>K</sub></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Sulfation</td><td style="text-align:left">Sulfate</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>the hydroxyl of <strong>T</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">Permenent</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> more polar, give hydrogen bonds<li>large polar ionic sulfate group</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Prenylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Isoprenyl chains</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>C-terminal of <strong>C</strong> residue through a thioether (C-S-C) linkage.</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"><li> Promoting interact with membranes<li> Signal transduction proteins are prenylated</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Amidation</td><td style="text-align:left">Amnie group</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> C-terminal carboxyl group</td><td style="text-align:left"></td><td style="text-align:left"><li>polar but not ionizable.</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Phosphorylation</td><td style="text-align:left">Phosphate groups</td><td style="text-align:left"><li> The hydroxyl group in the R chain. <li><strong>T</strong>; <strong>S</strong>; <strong>Y</strong><li><strong>H</strong> Could be also be phosphorylated in some case</td><td style="text-align:left">Reversible</td><td style="text-align:left"><li>Large polar group</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Axel-Schmidt-4/publication/329134617/figure/fig1/AS:960135673413644@1605925591623/Reactions-catalyzed-by-isoprenyl-diphosphates-synthases-Dimethylallyl-diphosphate.png" alt="Prenylation"></th><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/61/Prenyl_group.png" alt="Isoprenyl Group"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/329134617_Isoprenyl_diphosphate_synthases_the_chain_length_determining_step_in_terpene_biosynthesis">© Raimund Nagel, et al</a></td><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prenylation">© Wiki</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Protein-Folding">Protein Folding</h2><h3 id="Interactions">Interactions</h3><blockquote><p><strong>The forces that stabilize folded proteins</strong></p><ul><li>The hydrophobic effect</li><li>Hydrogen bonding</li><li>Ionic interactions</li><li>van der Waals interactions (London dispersion force)</li><li>Disulfide crosslinks<br>cite: Kauzmann, W. (1959) “Some factors in the interpretation of protein unfolding” Adv. In Proteins Chemistry. 14:1.</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>The hydrophobic effect</strong></p><ul><li>The unfavorable interaction between hydrophobic sidechains and water is reduced when a protein folds into its native structure</li><li>Up to 75% of hydrophobic residues are buried in folded proteins</li><li>Its contribution greatly favors folded state</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><strong>Hydrogen bonding</strong></p><ul><li>Every residue in a protein has at least one H-bond donor and at least one H-bond acceptor (the peptide bond)</li><li>Concentration of H-bonding groups in a protein is ~25M</li><li>Most potential H-bonding groups are, in fact, H-bonded in the interior of folded proteins</li><li>H-bonds define secondary structure geometry</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>The forces that stabilize folded protein</strong></em></p><ul><li>The hydrophobic effect</li><li>Hydrogen bonding</li><li>Ionic interactions</li><li>van der Waals interactions (London dispersion force)</li><li>Disulfide crosslinks</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Ionic interactions</strong></em></p><ul><li>Salt bridges form between acidic and basic residues</li><li>Majority of salt bridges are on surface</li><li>Buried salt bridges are conserved</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>van der Waals Interaction</strong></em></p><ul><li>Contribution is from tight packing of protein core</li><li>Protein density is ~1.3 g/ml (H20=1.0 g/ml Ethanol=0.8 g/ml)</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Disulfide Crosslinking</strong></em></p><ul><li>Covalent crosslinks between the sulfurs of cysteine residues</li><li>Generally nonlocal</li><li>Significant (but not dominant) contribution to stability</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="The-forces-that-destabilize-folded-protein"><em><strong>The forces that destabilize folded protein</strong></em></h2><blockquote><ul><li>Conformational entropy</li><li>Hydrogen bonds to water</li><li>Electrostatic repulsion</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Conformational-Entropy"><em><strong>Conformational Entropy</strong></em></h3><blockquote><ul><li>Backbone of folded protein has only one (or a few) conformations.</li><li>The backbone of an unfolded protein has 32n conformations (because there are 3 low energy φ and ψ torsion angles for each C<sub>α</sub>)<br>The backbone entropy change favoring unfolding:<br>ΔS = Rln(3<sup>2n</sup>/1) = 2nRln(3) = 1.4 kcal/mol/residue (5.4 kJ/mol/residue)</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Hydrogen-bonds-to-water"><em><strong>Hydrogen bonds to water</strong></em></h3><blockquote><ul><li>Every amino acid has at least two hydrogen-bonding groups</li><li>The concentration of bulk water is ~55 Molar and each water molecule has 4 hydrogen bonding groups. Therefore the favorable energetic contribution of hydrogen bonds to folding may be small<br>However, the unfavorable cost of unmade hydrogen bonds in the interior of the protein is still high</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="Hydrophobic-amino-acids-are-buried">Hydrophobic amino acids are buried</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Residue</th><th style="text-align:center">Exposed</th><th style="text-align:center">Burued</th><th style="text-align:center">Interm ediate</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">S</td><td style="text-align:center">0.70</td><td style="text-align:center">0.20</td><td style="text-align:center">0.10</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">T</td><td style="text-align:center">0.71</td><td style="text-align:center">0.16</td><td style="text-align:center">0.13</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">A</td><td style="text-align:center">0.48</td><td style="text-align:center">0.35</td><td style="text-align:center">0.17</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">G</td><td style="text-align:center">0.51</td><td style="text-align:center">0.36</td><td style="text-align:center">0.13</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">P</td><td style="text-align:center">0.78</td><td style="text-align:center">0.13</td><td style="text-align:center">0.09</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>C</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.32</td><td style="text-align:center">0.54</td><td style="text-align:center">0.14</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">D</td><td style="text-align:center">0.81</td><td style="text-align:center">0.09</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.10</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">E</td><td style="text-align:center">0.93</td><td style="text-align:center">0.04</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.03</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Q</td><td style="text-align:center">0.81</td><td style="text-align:center">0.10</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.09</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">N</td><td style="text-align:center">0.82</td><td style="text-align:center">0.10</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.08</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>L</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.41</td><td style="text-align:center">0.49</td><td style="text-align:center">0.10</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>I</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.39</td><td style="text-align:center">0.47</td><td style="text-align:center">0.14</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>V</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.40</td><td style="text-align:center">0.50</td><td style="text-align:center">0.10</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">M</td><td style="text-align:center">0.44</td><td style="text-align:center">0.20</td><td style="text-align:center">0.36</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>F</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.42</td><td style="text-align:center">0.42</td><td style="text-align:center">0.16</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Y</td><td style="text-align:center">0.67</td><td style="text-align:center">0.20</td><td style="text-align:center">0.13</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>W</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">0.49</td><td style="text-align:center">0.44</td><td style="text-align:center">0.07</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">K</td><td style="text-align:center">0.93</td><td style="text-align:center">0.02</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.05</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">R</td><td style="text-align:center">0.84</td><td style="text-align:center">0.05</td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>0.11</mark></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">H</td><td style="text-align:center">0.66</td><td style="text-align:center">0.19</td><td style="text-align:center">0.15</td></tr></tbody></table><p><mark>C</mark>: Buried Residues<br>V; L; I; F; W; C</p><p><mark>0.01</mark>: Exposed Residues<br>D; E; N; Q; K; R</p><h2 id="Protein-Unfolding">Protein Unfolding</h2><blockquote><ul><li>An unfolded protein has lost its tertiary/quaternary structure and its biological activity</li><li>Depending on the experimental conditions an unfolded protein may be stable or it may aggregate/precipitate</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p><em><strong>Treatments that unfold proteins</strong></em>:<br><strong>High temperature</strong>: many proteins unfold at 50-90 º C<br><strong>pH</strong>: some proteins will unfold when they gain a large net charge<br><strong>Denaturants</strong>: proteins unfold in detergents like sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) or in denaturants like urea and guanidine<br>Unfolding curves are <strong>sigmoidal</strong></p></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Deepak-Kumar-25/post/Why-there-is-difference-in-delta-G-H20-of-a-protein-calculated-by-CD-and-fluorescence-spectroscopy/attachment/5de21914cfe4a777d4f5e9d5/AS%3A830838086324224%401575098644656/image/CD+vs+floure.tif" alt="Unfolding curves"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/post/Why-there-is-difference-in-delta-G-H20-of-a-protein-calculated-by-CD-and-fluorescence-spectroscopy">© Agnishwar Girigoswami</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Net-Stability">Net Stability</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Most proteins have a net stability of ~10 kcal/mol/protein<br>Compare this to the individual contributions:</li><li>Hydrophobic effect ~ 1-2 kcal/mol/amino acid residue</li><li>Conformational Entropy ~1-2 kcal/mol/amino acid residue<br>For a 200 residue protein these contributions can be 400 kcal/mol each but the overall stability will always be ~10 kcal/mol</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Mutational-Studies-of-Protein-Stability">Mutational Studies of Protein Stability</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/280033060/figure/fig2/AS:340154561646621@1458110575853/Ubiquilin-2-proteins-containing-ALS-mutation-have-increased-stability-and-they-slow.png" alt="Mutational Studies of Protein Stability"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/280033060_Defective_Proteasome_Delivery_of_Polyubiquitinated_Proteins_by_Ubiquilin-2_Proteins_Containing_ALS_Mutations">© Lydia Chang</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ul><li>Most mutations are destabilizing<ul><li>The ability to precisely predict the change in folding energy (ΔG) is not very good</li></ul></li><li>Buried residues have a bigger effect than exposed residues</li></ul></blockquote><blockquote><p>[图] Predicting changes in the stability of proteins and protein complexes: a study of more than 1000 mutations. J Mol Biol. 2002 Jul 5;320(2):369-87.</p></blockquote><h2 id="The-Levinthal-Paradox">The Levinthal Paradox</h2><blockquote><p><em><strong>Does a protein find its native configuration by a random search?</strong></em><br>Carbon-carbon bonds reorient each ~ 10-13 sec<br>For a protein of n residues there are 32n<br>conformations<br>If n = 100, then 3<sup>2n</sup> ~ 10<sup>95</sup><br>If 10<sup>13</sup> conformations were sampled every second it would take 10<sup>82</sup> seconds to sample them all…<br>…but the age of the universe is only about 10<sup>17</sup> sec!<br>It is now known that proteins fold on time scales from milliseconds to minutes</p><ul><li>Proteins fold via conserved, hierarchical pathways<br>(This may explain the prevalence of the Greek Key motif)</li></ul></blockquote><p>PS:<br><strong>why 3<sup>2n</sup></strong>:</p><ul><li>2: there are two tortion angles: φ and ψ</li><li>n: n peptides</li><li>3: If each of these bond angles can be in one of three stable conformations<sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup></li></ul><h3 id="Diseases-of-protein-misfolding">Diseases of protein misfolding</h3><blockquote><p>Cystic Fibrosis: Alzheimer’s disease<br>Mad Cow Disease: Retinitus pigmentosa</p></blockquote><h2 id="Molecular-Chaperones">Molecular Chaperones</h2><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0968000498011931-gr1.gif" alt="The GroEL/GroES ATPase cycle"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0968000498011931?casa_token=7xufCboPWDgAAAAA:LMCj9M2w9u8jtBaqNG1NMgc6vulcOsdx8YSzyPY6kDFll-LMDRBoUUKDznaotVdSmzpGMOc">© Alexandra Richardson, 1998</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><p>“Heat shock proteins”<br>Molecular Chaperones<br>Chaperonins</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Chaperones assist protein folding in the cell</p><ul><li>They bind unfolded chains</li><li>They use energy from ATP to bind and release protein chains in a repeating cycle</li><li>ATP turnover rate is slow 1 sec<sup>-1</sup><br>The GroEL/GroES chaperone form E. Coli is well understood</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Other-Proteins">Other Proteins</h3><blockquote><p>Protein Disulfide Isomerase<br>Peptidyl proline cis-trans isomerase</p></blockquote><h2 id="Protein-Degradation-in-the-Cell">Protein Degradation in the Cell</h2><blockquote><p>There are two main pathways for protein degradation in eukaryotic cells<br><em><strong>Lysosomal Degradation</strong></em></p><ul><li>The lysosome is a membrane-encapsulated organelle</li><li>It contains ~50 hydrolytic enzymes</li><li>Lysosomes have acidic pH</li><li>Has both selective and non-selective degradation processes<br><em><strong>Proteasomal Degradation</strong></em></li><li>The proteasome is a large protein machine (MW = 2x106)</li><li>It degrades proteins that have the small protein ubiquitin attached to them</li><li>Ubiquitination rate (degradation rate) is determined by the N-terminal residue</li><li>Ubiquitin (76 residues) is the most highly conserved protein known</li></ul></blockquote><hr class="footnotes-sep"><section class="footnotes"><ol class="footnotes-list"><li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levinthal%27s_paradox">Wikipedia: Levinthal’s paradox</a> <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></section>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Class notes of Graduate Biochemistry in Tulane</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Biochemistry" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Biochemistry/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>5 Membrane Transport|Advanced Cell Biology|Tulane</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/21/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-5/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/21/LearnNotes/tulane-cellbio-5/</id>
    <published>2021-09-21T14:31:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-01T13:26:18.334Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Objectives">Objectives</h2><p>By the end of this session you should be able to:</p><blockquote><ol><li><mark>Compare and contrast</mark> the characteristics of<ul><li>passive diffusion</li><li>facilitated diffusion</li><li>primary active transport</li><li>secondary active transport (cotransport).</li></ul></li><li><mark>Compare and contrast</mark> the properties of the:<ul><li>four classes of ATP-powered pumps</li><li>their effect on the intracellular environment</li></ul></li><li><mark>Describe</mark> how:<ul><li><strong>potassium channels</strong> can generate a hyperpolarized resting potential, common in most living cells.</li></ul></li><li><mark>Explain</mark> how<ul><li>transporters &amp; Ion channels regulate <mark>insulin release</mark> in the pancreas</li></ul></li></ol></blockquote><h2 id="General-information">General information</h2><h3 id="Type-of-membrane-transport-depends-on">Type of membrane transport depends on:</h3><blockquote><ul><li>Characteristics of the substance being transported</li><li>Direction of transport</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Three-main-classes-of-membrane-protein">Three main classes of membrane protein</h3><blockquote><ol><li><mark>ATP-power pump</mark> (carrier, permease) couple with <strong>energy source</strong> for active transport binding of specific solute to transporter which undergo conformation change.</li><li><mark>Channel protein</mark> (ion channel) formation of <strong>hydrophilic</strong> allow passive movement of small inorganic molecule.</li><li><mark>Transporters</mark>:<ul><li>uniport (single)</li><li>Symport (double)</li><li>antiport (double &amp; anti one cis another trans gradient)</li></ul></li></ol></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Mariafrancesca-Scalise/publication/259153787/figure/fig1/AS:297151797186578@1447857917496/Functional-classification-of-membrane-proteins-Channels-are-depicted-in-green-and-I.png" alt="Three main classes of membrane protein"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/259153787_Proteoliposomes_as_Tool_for_Assaying_Membrane_Transporter_Functions_and_Interactions_with_Xenobiotics">© Mariafrancesca Scalise, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Two-types-of-transport">Two types of transport:</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Maria-Mueller-17/publication/268209172/figure/fig1/AS:669095250915334@1536536147328/Overview-of-membrane-transport-proteins-Triangles-indicate-gradients-with-the-tip.png" alt="Two types of transport"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/268209172_STRUCTURE_AND_FUNCTION_OF_CHANNELRHODOPSIN-2_BY_CRYO_ELECTRON_CRYSTALLOGRAPHY">© Maria Müller</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ol><li>Passive transport (diffusion): <mark>NO metabolic energy is needed</mark></li><li>Active Transport: <mark>Metabolic energy is used</mark></li></ol></blockquote><h3 id="Passive-simple-diffusion">Passive (simple) diffusion</h3><blockquote><ul><li><strong>Small noncharged molecules</strong> or <strong>lipid soluble molecules</strong> pass between the phospholipids to enter or leave the cell</li><li>Moving from areas of <strong>high concentration</strong> to areas of <strong>low concentration</strong> (they move down their concentration gradient)</li><li><strong>Example</strong>: Oxygen, carbon dioxide, and most lipids</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Osmosis">Osmosis</h3><blockquote><p>A type of simple diffusion in which water molecules diffuse through a selectively permeable membrane from areas of high water concentration to areas of lower water concentration.</p></blockquote><h3 id="Facilitated-diffusion">Facilitated diffusion</h3><blockquote><ul><li>The substance is moving <strong>down its concentration gradient</strong> through a <strong>membrane protein</strong> (not between the phospholipids)</li><li><strong>Example</strong>: monosaccharide, glucose, <mark>water</mark><ul><li>“Water &amp; oil don’t mix”<br>- That’s why water was not considered as passive diffusion<br>- Aquaporins increase water permeability<br>- Too much mRNA injected into Frog Oocyte could make it absorbing too much water.</li></ul></li></ul></blockquote><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Susanna-Toernroth-Horsefield/publication/23235554/figure/fig2/AS:667685440479244@1536200022868/Overview-of-human-aquaporin-5-A-Top-view-of-the-tetramer-from-the-cytoplasm-along-the.png" alt="Aquaporins"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/23235554_High-resolution_X-ray_structure_of_human_aquaporin_5">© Rob Horsefield, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="GLUT1-Mechanism-Facilitated-Diffusion">GLUT1 Mechanism (Facilitated Diffusion)</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Yan-Chuangye/publication/262532522/figure/fig5/AS:267787981553664@1440857038049/A-working-model-for-GLUT1-Shown-here-are-the-predicted-conformations-outward-open.png" alt="GLUT1 Working Model"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/262532522_Crystal_structure_of_the_human_glucose_transporter_GLUT1">© Dong Deng, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote><ul><li>most commonly expressed glucose transporter</li><li>reversible (depends on concentration gradient); glucose is commonly rapidly phosphorylated in cytoplasm</li><li>ping pong mechanism (protein does not “flip”)</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Facilitated-vs-Passive-Diffusion">Facilitated vs. Passive Diffusion</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Florina-Iliescu/publication/269702922/figure/fig2/AS:295266373652497@1447408397664/The-drug-release-profiles-for-simple-diffusion-bulk-microneedles-facilitated-diffusion.png" alt="Facilitated vs. Passive Diffusion"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/269702922_A_PARALLEL_BETWEEN_TRANSDERMAL_DRUG_DELIVERY_AND_MICROTECHNOLOGY">© Florina Silvia Iliescu, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Exp: GLUT1 (erythrocytes) and GLUT2 (liver &amp; pancreas)</p><ul><li>saturable</li><li>non-linear</li><li>selective, fast &amp; constant rate at 5-10 mM</li><li>uptake rate varies more (stimulates insulin release)</li></ul><h3 id="Active-transport">Active transport</h3><p>PS: Energy; Against Concentration</p><blockquote><ul><li>Move substances across membranes <strong>against their concentration gradient</strong> (from areas of low concentration to areas of high concentration)</li><li><strong>Energy</strong> is needed for this movement</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Primary-vs-Secondary-active-transport">Primary vs Secondary active transport</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Alberto-Canarini/publication/331257253/figure/fig1/AS:728743127568394@1550757309754/Summary-of-the-main-exudation-mechanisms-through-the-plasmamembrane-at-the-root-tip.ppm" alt="Primary vs Secondary active transport"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/331257253_Root_Exudation_of_Primary_Metabolites_Mechanisms_and_Their_Roles_in_Plant_Responses_to_Environmental_Stimuli">© Alberto Canarini, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Primary: simply against the concentration</li><li>Secondary: send the intermediate molecule against the concentration and then, Symport the target molecules against the concentration.</li></ul><blockquote><p>e.g.:</p><ul><li>Intestinal &amp; Kidney<br>Utilize the free-energy for Na (down its concentration gradient) to move glucose (against its concentration gradient)</li><li>SGLT-2 (Na-glucose co-transporter 2)</li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="Comparison-of-Different-Transport-Mechanisms">Comparison of Different Transport Mechanisms</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Property</th><th style="text-align:left">Passive<br>Diffusion</th><th style="text-align:left">Facilitate<br>diffusion</th><th style="text-align:left">Active<br>Transport</th><th style="text-align:left">cotransport</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left">Protein Required</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Against Graident</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">ATP Needed</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">contransported ion down its gradient</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">-</td><td style="text-align:left">+</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">EXP</td><td style="text-align:left">O<sub>2</sub>, CO<sub>2</sub>, steroid hormones, may drugs</td><td style="text-align:left">Glucose and AA (uniporters), ions, water (channels)</td><td style="text-align:left">Ions, small hydrophilic molecules, lipids (ATP-powered pumps)</td><td style="text-align:left">Glucose and AA (symporters); Various ions and sucrose (antiporters)</td></tr></tbody></table><ul><li>Saturable transport at high [solute]</li></ul><h2 id="4-Classes-of-ATP-powered-transport-proteins">4 Classes of ATP-powered transport proteins</h2><ul><li>P class pump</li><li>V class pump</li><li>F Class Proton Pumps</li><li>ABC (ATP Binding Cassette) Superfamily</li></ul><h3 id="P-Class-pump">P Class pump</h3><p>(Proton pump)</p><blockquote><ul><li>Plasma membrance of plants, fungi, bacteria (H<sup>+</sup> pump)</li><li>Plasma membrane of higher eukaryotes (Na<sup>+</sup>/K<sup>+</sup> pump)</li><li>Apical plasma membrane of mammalian stomach (H<sup>+</sup>/K<sup>+</sup> pump)</li><li>Plasam membrane of all eukaryotic cells (Ca<sup>+</sup> pump)</li><li>Sarcoplasmic reticulum membrane in muscle cells (Ca<sup>+</sup> pump)</li></ul></blockquote><p>Typical Intracellular and Extracellular Ion Concentrations</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left">Ion</th><th style="text-align:center">Cell(mM)</th><th style="text-align:center">Blood (mM)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>K<sup>+</sup></mark></td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>139</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">4</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Na<sup>+</sup></strong></em></td><td style="text-align:center">12</td><td style="text-align:center"><em><strong>145</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><em><strong>Cl<sup>-</sup></strong></em></td><td style="text-align:center">4</td><td style="text-align:center"><em><strong>116</strong></em></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup></td><td style="text-align:center">12</td><td style="text-align:center">29</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><mark>X<sup>-</sup></mark></td><td style="text-align:center"><mark>138</mark></td><td style="text-align:center">9</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Mg<sup>2+</sup></td><td style="text-align:center">0.8</td><td style="text-align:center">1.5</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left">Ca<sup>2+</sup></td><td style="text-align:center">&lt;0.0002</td><td style="text-align:center">1.8</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Na/K ATPase</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Thomas-Friedrich-4/publication/263053947/figure/fig1/AS:614297508012107@1523471347814/Reaction-mechanism-and-structural-detail-of-the-Na-K-ATPase-A-Schematic-reaction.png" alt="Na/K ATPase"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/263053947_Functional_analysis_of_human_NaK-ATPase_familial_or_sporadic_hemiplegic_migraine_mutations_expressed_in_Xenopus_oocytes">© Susan Spiller, et al.</a></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Inhibited by ouabain &amp;<br>digoxin</p><h3 id="F-Class-Proton-Pumps">F-Class Proton Pumps</h3><blockquote><p>Location:</p><ul><li>Bacterial plasma membrane</li><li>Inner mitochondrial membrane</li><li>Thylakoid membrane of chloroplast</li><li><mark>Use <strong>H<sup>+</sup> gradient to generate ATP</strong> (convert chemical energy to a different form)</mark></li></ul></blockquote><h3 id="V-Class-Proton-Pumps">V-Class Proton Pumps</h3><blockquote><p>Location:</p><ul><li>Vacuolar membranes in plants; yeats, other fungi</li><li><abbr title="胞内体">Endosomal</abbr> and lysosomal membranes in animal cells</li><li>Plasma membrane of osteoclasts and some kidney tubule cells.</li><li><mark>Utilize ATP to generate a H+ gradient</mark></li></ul></blockquote><p>PS: Functional against F-Class</p><h3 id="V-Class-H-ATPase">V-Class H<sup>+</sup> ATPase</h3><blockquote><p>Lysosomes:</p><ul><li>degrade extracellular materials (e.g. bacteria, LDL particles)</li></ul><p>Synapse:</p><ul><li>V-class H<sup>+</sup> pumps &amp; Synaptic Transmission</li><li>Vesicles, Pumps &amp; Synaptic Transmission</li></ul></blockquote><h2 id="ATP-Binding-Cassette-ABC-Superfamily">ATP Binding Cassette (ABC) Superfamily</h2><blockquote><ul><li>Bacterial plasma membrane (AA, sugar, and peptide transporters)</li><li>Mammalian plasma membranes (Transporters of phospholipids, small lipophilic drugs, cholesterol, other small molecules)</li><li><mark>Pre-systemic drug clearance, blood-brain barrier, renal secretion of drugs, cancer cells</mark></li></ul><p>Location:<br>BBB (blood-brain barrier ); GI tract; Kidney; Liver; Cancer</p></blockquote><h3 id="ABC-Transporters-Presystemic-Clearance">ABC Transporters &amp; Presystemic Clearance</h3><blockquote><p>Mechanism of presystemic clearance. After drug enters the enterocyte, it can undergo metabolism, excretion into the intestinal lumen, or transport into the portal vein. Similarly, the hepatocyte may accomplish metabolism and biliary excretion prior to the entry of drug and metabolites to the systemic circulation.</p></blockquote><h2 id="Ion-Channel">Ion Channel</h2><h3 id="Four-Subtypes-of-Ion-Channels">Four Subtypes of Ion Channels</h3><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:left"></th><th style="text-align:left">Types</th><th style="text-align:left">Example</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:left"><strong>1</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">Voltage-gate</td><td style="text-align:left">Na, Ca, K</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><strong>2</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">Ligand-gated<br>(extracellular ligand)</td><td style="text-align:left">GABA<sub>A</sub>, ACh, Nicotinic</td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><strong>3</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">Ligand-gated<br>(intracellular ligand)</td><td style="text-align:left">βγ, <abbr title="蕈鹼類受器">Muscarinic</abbr>, <abbr title="腺苷">Adenosine</abbr></td></tr><tr><td style="text-align:left"><strong>4</strong></td><td style="text-align:left">Stress-activated</td><td style="text-align:left">Stretch</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/313036222/figure/fig3/AS:455884053716994@1485702636814/Voltage-gated-sodium-channels-and-action-potential-generation.png" alt="Valtage Gate"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center"><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/313036222_Drug_targets_ligand_and_voltage_gated_ion_channels">© Nilan Jacob</a></td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Beta-Cells-of-the-Pancreas">Beta Cells of the Pancreas</h3><p>(How Transporters &amp; Ion Channels Regulate Insulin Release)</p><table><thead><tr><th style="text-align:center"><img src="https://z3.ax1x.com/2021/09/27/4gVyes.png" alt="Beta Cells of the Pancreas"></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="text-align:center">© Suttira “Joy” Intapad, Ph.D</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Ion-Channels-Membrane-Potential">Ion Channels &amp; Membrane Potential</h3><ul><li>Membrane electric potential</li><li>59 mV; intracellular medium</li></ul><h3 id="Membrane-electric-potential">Membrane electric potential</h3><h3 id="Patch-Clamp-Technique-Voltage-Clamp">Patch Clamp Technique (Voltage Clamp)</h3><h3 id="Transport-across-but-not-through-membranes">Transport across, but not through, membranes</h3><ul><li>Endocytosis</li><li>Exocytosis</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Classes notes of the Advanced Cell Biology</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Class" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Notes/Class/Tulane/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Classes/"/>
    
    <category term="Cell Biology" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Cell-Biology/"/>
    
    <category term="Tulane Classes" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Tulane-Classes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>librosa for sound track| Python</title>
    <link href="https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/18/Python/librosa/"/>
    <id>https://karobben.github.io/2021/09/18/Python/librosa/</id>
    <published>2021-09-18T21:56:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-21T23:13:16.537Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="python">python</h2><p>Cite: <a href="http://nladuo.github.io/2019/08/31/%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8Python%E5%AF%B9%E9%9F%B3%E9%A2%91%E8%BF%9B%E8%A1%8C%E7%89%B9%E5%BE%81%E6%8F%90%E5%8F%96/">叁公子KCN; 2019</a></p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="PYTHON"><figure class="iseeu highlight /python"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs python"><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> librosa<br><br><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> matplotlib.pyplot <span class="hljs-keyword">as</span> plt<br><span class="hljs-keyword">import</span> librosa.display<br><br>File = <span class="hljs-string">&quot;input.mkv&quot;</span><br><br>x , sr = librosa.load(File, sr=<span class="hljs-number">8000</span>)<br><br>plt.figure(figsize=(<span class="hljs-number">14</span>, <span class="hljs-number">5</span>))<br>librosa.display.waveplot(x[:<span class="hljs-number">10000</span>], sr=sr)<br>plt.show()<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div><h2 id="ffmpeg">ffmpeg</h2><p>Cite: <a href="https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/97914917">dennyyoung</a></p><div class="highlight-wrap"autocomplete="off" autocorrect="off" autocapitalize="off" spellcheck="false" contenteditable="true"data-rel="BASH"><figure class="iseeu highlight /bash"><table><tr><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-comment"># Video split</span><br>ffmpeg -y -ss 0 -t 3 -i Function.mkv -c:v libx264 -c:a copy  123.mkv<br><br><span class="hljs-comment"># Video merge</span><br>ffmpeg -y -i filename -i filename2 -vcode copy -acodec copy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></div>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">librosa library for sound track processing in python</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Python" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/categories/Python/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Python" scheme="https://karobben.github.io/tags/Python/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
